<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/jwu/github/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A reexamination of the organizational slack and innovation relationship</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2015-05-05">Available online 5 May 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Marlin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Kate Tiedemann College of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of South Florida St. Petersburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>140 7th Avenue South</addrLine>
									<postCode>33701</postCode>
									<settlement>St. Petersburg</settlement>
									<region>FL</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Scott</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Geiger</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Kate Tiedemann College of Business</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of South Florida St. Petersburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>140 7th Avenue South</addrLine>
									<postCode>33701</postCode>
									<settlement>St. Petersburg</settlement>
									<region>FL</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A reexamination of the organizational slack and innovation relationship</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2015-05-05">Available online 5 May 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jbusres.2015.03.047</idno>
					<note type="submission">Article history: Received 13 June 2013 Received in revised form 21 March 2015 Accepted 23 March 2015</note>
					<note>a r t i c l e i n f o</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>

		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.0-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID-SDO" when="2019-12-20T15:09+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid-sdo"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>Slack Innovation Configuration Equifinality</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>a b s t r a c t</head><p>In this study a configurational approach was used to examine the organizational slack and innovation relationship. Utilizing a sample of 437 manufacturing firms and multiple measures of firm innovation we identified distinct configurations of slack and found significant innovation differences between them. The results from our analyses demonstrate that configurations with moderately high combined levels of internal slack (available and recoverable slack) and moderately high levels of potential slack produced higher levels of innovation. Conversely, configurations with low to moderately low levels of each type of slack produced the lowest levels of innovation. Our findings also indicate that alternative configurations of slack can result in similar levels of innovation suggesting the existence of equifinality in this relationship. Overall, our findings suggest that the slack and innovation relationship is more complex than has been accounted for in previous research. The implications of these findings are discussed.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Organizational slack and its impact on firm innovation is an important area of research within the strategic management literature. Organizational slack has been studied because the accumulation and expenditure of resources impacts competitive ability and firm outcomes <ref type="bibr" coords="1,42.52,461.01,99.05,7.54" target="#b5">(Chen, Yang, &amp; Lin, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,145.36,461.01,87.99,7.54" target="#b6">Cheng &amp; Kesner, 1997;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,237.20,461.01,56.31,7.54;1,42.52,471.44,98.74,7.54" target="#b8">Daniel, Lohrke, Fornaciari, &amp; Turner, 2004)</ref>. Innovation has been studied because it plays a large role in a firm's ability to create competitive advantages via adaptation and new product development <ref type="bibr" coords="1,218.26,492.36,75.30,7.54;1,42.52,502.85,21.09,7.54" target="#b0">(Alessandri &amp; Pattit, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,67.97,502.85,172.87,7.54" target="#b16">Herold, Jayaraman, &amp; Narayanaswamy, 2006)</ref>. Overall, the research findings on the relationship between organizational slack and innovation remain largely equivocal.</p><p>Like many other areas of research, most studies examining the slack and innovation relationship have tested for linear relationships. For example, slack is argued to be a benefit for firms because it serves as a buffer from shortages of funds and can increase the potential for firm innovation <ref type="bibr" coords="1,82.99,576.04,63.00,7.54" target="#b2">(Bourgeois, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,148.02,576.04,74.47,7.54" target="#b7">Cyert &amp; March, 1963)</ref>. However, it is also argued that organizational slack is inefficient and accrues because of self-serving managers <ref type="bibr" coords="1,128.24,596.96,100.41,7.54" target="#b19">(Jensen &amp; Meckling, 1976;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,232.10,596.96,61.47,7.54;1,42.52,607.44,21.09,7.54" target="#b29">Nohria &amp; Gulati, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,66.16,607.44,47.40,7.54" target="#b36">Simon, 1957)</ref>. Other researchers have argued for contingency <ref type="bibr" coords="1,42.52,617.88,87.16,7.54" target="#b13">(Geiger &amp; Makri, 2006)</ref> or nonlinear <ref type="bibr" coords="1,181.53,617.88,75.78,7.54" target="#b16">(Herold et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,260.22,617.88,33.37,7.54;1,42.52,628.36,47.99,7.54" target="#b29">Nohria &amp; Gulati, 1996)</ref> relationships and thus expand beyond the good or bad arguments for slack. Most prior research has also examined slack uniformly from a theoretical perspective even though slack is recognized as being a multidimensional concept (e.g., <ref type="bibr" coords="1,475.65,398.25,59.79,7.54" target="#b4">Bromiley, 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,539.04,398.25,22.52,7.54;1,310.51,408.68,20.65,7.54" target="#b37">Singh, 1986;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,333.30,408.68,120.78,7.54" target="#b40">Voss, Sirdeshmukh, &amp; Voss, 2008)</ref> and the relationship between slack and innovation can vary depending on these different dimensions <ref type="bibr" coords="1,310.51,429.60,84.74,7.54" target="#b12">(Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002)</ref>.</p><p>The above highlights two important factors: (1) there is inconsistency in prior findings and (2) there is still much to be learned regarding the relationship between organizational slack and innovation. Given this, we believe the literature can be advanced in two ways. First, while prior research has examined the relationship between individual components of slack and innovation, no known studies have examined the joint impact of multiple types of slack on firm innovation. As such, we extend prior research by building on the theoretical arguments of both behavioral theorists <ref type="bibr" coords="1,403.31,523.76,81.33,7.54" target="#b7">(Cyert &amp; March, 1963)</ref> and agency theorists <ref type="bibr" coords="1,310.51,534.19,100.77,7.54" target="#b19">(Jensen &amp; Meckling, 1976)</ref> and then examining how firms bundle slack resources and how these bundles impact firm innovation. This is accomplished through the use of a configurational approach <ref type="bibr" coords="1,530.81,555.11,30.75,7.54;1,310.51,565.60,152.97,7.54" target="#b15">(Gruber, Heinemann, Brettel, &amp; Hungeling, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,467.26,565.60,94.29,7.54;1,310.51,576.03,21.45,7.54" target="#b35">Short, Payne, &amp; Ketchen, 2008)</ref> which to date has not been used when examining this relationship even though slack has been recognized as a multidimensional concept. Using such an approach provides insights that are either out of the scope of or unattainable by research focusing on the impacts of individual organizational elements <ref type="bibr" coords="1,435.57,617.87,47.66,7.54" target="#b28">(Miller, 1981)</ref>.</p><p>Second, no known studies have considered the combined effect of the different types of slack or whether the different types of slack resources, when uniquely bundled together, result in differing or similar firm level outcomes. Because slack is multidimensional, different unique combinations or configurations of slack resources may result in equifinality in the slack and innovation relationship. As described by <ref type="bibr" coords="1,310.51,691.12,91.81,7.54" target="#b14">Gresov and Drazin (1997)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" coords="1,419.36,691.12,77.86,7.54" target="#b21">Katz and Kahn (1978)</ref> equifinality exists when a system can reach the same final state from different initial conditions and by a variety of different paths. Since no prior studies have examined this relationship using a configurational approach, it is not known if there are multiple ways to bundle slack resources that result in similar levels of firm innovation. Thus, this study provides a first step in determining if certain slack bundles result in higher levels of innovation and if there are multiple ways of bundling slack resources that result in similar innovation outcomes.</p><p>In the following section we provide a review of the slack and innovation literature and develop testable hypotheses. Following this, we describe the data, research methodology and the results of our empirical analyses. Finally, we provide a discussion of the results that includes both managerial and theoretical implications as well as future research directions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Theory and hypotheses</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Types of slack and slack configurations</head><p>Based on prior definitions, slack can be thought of as a bundle of resources within or available to an organization above the minimum needed to create a given level of output <ref type="bibr" coords="2,174.16,277.49,83.84,7.54" target="#b12">(Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002)</ref>. Previous research has identified multiple components of slack <ref type="bibr" coords="2,243.44,287.92,41.31,7.54;2,33.73,298.41,20.97,7.54" target="#b2">(Bourgeois, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,56.86,298.41,91.10,7.54" target="#b3">Bourgeois &amp; Singh, 1983;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,150.18,298.41,84.52,7.54" target="#b12">Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,236.91,298.41,43.97,7.54" target="#b37">Singh, 1986)</ref>. These components have been most commonly categorized as available, recoverable, and potential slack <ref type="bibr" coords="2,150.57,319.33,64.19,7.54" target="#b2">(Bourgeois, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,217.02,319.33,67.75,7.54;2,33.73,329.76,21.85,7.54" target="#b3">Bourgeois &amp; Singh, 1983)</ref> absorbed and unabsorbed slack <ref type="bibr" coords="2,175.52,329.76,48.08,7.54" target="#b37">(Singh, 1986)</ref>, or internal and external slack <ref type="bibr" coords="2,85.15,340.25,85.45,7.54" target="#b12">(Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002)</ref>. These categories are similar in that internal slack is within the firm and either readily available and unabsorbed, or already absorbed and considered recoverable while external slack is not within the firm and is considered potential or unabsorbed. Since these frameworks are consistent we use available, recoverable, and potential slack as it is the most fine-grained approach in the literature.</p><p>Concerning slack's relationship with firm outcomes, varying arguments have been presented on its benefits <ref type="bibr" coords="2,202.90,423.93,63.17,7.54" target="#b2">(Bourgeois, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,268.21,423.93,16.62,7.54;2,33.73,434.36,53.66,7.54" target="#b25">Love &amp; Nohria, 2005)</ref>. Moreover, prior research suggests that the relationship between slack and firm outcomes can vary depending on the component or type of slack being examined <ref type="bibr" coords="2,171.55,455.28,88.61,7.54" target="#b12">(Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,262.49,455.28,22.23,7.54;2,33.73,465.77,19.85,7.54" target="#b37">Singh, 1986)</ref>. Overall, the literature has conceptualized slack as a multidimensional concept (i.e., <ref type="bibr" coords="2,129.66,476.25,61.11,7.54" target="#b2">Bourgeois, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,193.09,476.25,91.61,7.54" target="#b3">Bourgeois &amp; Singh, 1983;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,33.73,486.69,58.52,7.54" target="#b4">Bromiley, 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,94.62,486.69,45.99,7.54" target="#b37">Singh, 1986;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,142.92,486.69,60.94,7.54" target="#b40">Voss et al., 2008)</ref>. However, individual studies have typically failed to make varying theoretical arguments regarding the relationship between slack and firm outcomes based on the different slack dimensions. Also, prior research has yet to examine the combined or simultaneous effects of the different slack dimensions on firm outcomes such as innovation. As such, the use of a multidimensional approach such as a configurational approach should improve our understanding of this relationship.</p><p>Within the overall body of management research configurational relationships are often examined. Configurational approaches are used because they allow researchers to examine sets of firms that share common profiles across a variety of key variables <ref type="bibr" coords="2,192.92,601.78,71.01,7.54" target="#b15">(Gruber et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,265.66,601.78,19.11,7.54;2,33.73,612.21,40.01,7.54" target="#b35">Short et al., 2008)</ref>, and they demonstrate differences in outcomes among the groups of firms studied <ref type="bibr" coords="2,124.55,622.70,127.11,7.54" target="#b22">(Ketchen, Thomas, &amp; Snow, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,254.78,622.70,29.93,7.54;2,33.73,633.13,38.84,7.54" target="#b23">Ketchen et al., 1997)</ref>. Thus, when studying slack and innovation, a configurational approach allows for the testing of how multiple components of slack are bundled and how these bundles, or configurations, are associated with different levels of firm innovation. Surprisingly, despite the equivocal findings related to slack and innovation outcomes using other methods, configurational studies that specifically examine the slack and innovation relationship do not exist. This is unfortunate as prior slack research (e.g., <ref type="bibr" coords="2,132.83,706.37,62.85,7.54" target="#b2">Bourgeois, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,199.11,706.37,59.77,7.54" target="#b4">Bromiley, 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,262.26,706.37,22.52,7.54;2,33.73,716.81,21.07,7.54" target="#b37">Singh, 1986;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,57.15,716.81,62.79,7.54" target="#b40">Voss et al., 2008)</ref> has recognized the multidimensional nature of slack and the need for additional research <ref type="bibr" coords="2,208.85,727.29,71.68,7.54" target="#b8">(Daniel et al., 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,280.54,727.29,4.24,7.54;2,33.73,737.72,77.58,7.54" target="#b12">: Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Slack and innovation</head><p>It important to note that firm innovation involves both important inputs into the innovation process such as R&amp;D expenditures and important outputs of a firm's innovative activities such as patents. In this study we examine both types of innovative activities and thus our theoretical arguments are based on how firm behavior will impact both innovation inputs and outputs. Within the literature slack has been argued to have positive, negative, and curvilinear influences on firm innovation <ref type="bibr" coords="2,359.77,151.97,63.34,7.54" target="#b2">(Bourgeois, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,425.20,151.97,68.16,7.54" target="#b16">Herold et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,495.49,151.97,57.32,7.54;2,301.72,162.40,19.49,7.54" target="#b29">Nohria &amp; Gulati, 1996)</ref>. The positive outcomes of slack are often tied to the arguments of behavioral theorists that slack buffers an organization from environmental uncertainty and provides extra resources that allow for scientific research and experimentation <ref type="bibr" coords="2,410.28,193.81,66.26,7.54" target="#b38">(Tan &amp; Peng, 2003)</ref>. This results in innovative cultures and experimental projects being more likely to develop <ref type="bibr" coords="2,301.72,214.73,62.43,7.54" target="#b2">(Bourgeois, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,365.84,214.73,76.97,7.54" target="#b29">Nohria &amp; Gulati, 1996)</ref>. Under this scenario managers are less likely to worry about the risk of failure because excess resources exist to buffer against any losses. In this sense slack can also serve to facilitate strategic behavior which allows firms to create new strategies and new products <ref type="bibr" coords="2,367.65,256.57,62.66,7.54" target="#b2">(Bourgeois, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,432.23,256.57,60.64,7.54" target="#b39">Thompson, 1967)</ref>. Overall, slack is acknowledged to have costs, but its benefits are thought to outweigh these costs <ref type="bibr" coords="2,343.10,277.49,67.25,7.54" target="#b38">(Tan &amp; Peng, 2003)</ref>. Conversely, according to agency theorists slack has negative effects on firm outcomes because managers are self-serving and wasteful <ref type="bibr" coords="2,412.61,298.41,97.12,7.54" target="#b19">(Jensen &amp; Meckling, 1976)</ref>. Following this line of reasoning, managers may not have the incentive to act in the best interest of the firm and the firm's owners may lack the information needed to monitor managerial behavior. Thus, managers may pursue personal projects, engage in empire building, or simply inefficiently utilize resources, all of which could reduce firm outcomes such as innovation <ref type="bibr" coords="2,327.34,361.17,88.45,7.54" target="#b12">(Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002)</ref>. However, the relationship between slack and innovation may vary based on the type of slack and thus these relationships are discussed separately below.</p><p>Available slack identifies the amount of resources that are unutilized and readily available to the firm. Typically used measures of available slack include liquidity measures such as the current ratio or quick ratio <ref type="bibr" coords="2,322.19,423.93,63.17,7.54" target="#b4">(Bromiley, 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,388.57,423.93,86.46,7.54" target="#b6">Cheng &amp; Kesner, 1997;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,478.37,423.93,74.39,7.54;2,301.72,434.36,19.85,7.54" target="#b30">Palmer &amp; Wiseman, 1999)</ref>. Available slack is internal, flexible, highly deployable and provides firms with a buffer to the ebb and flow in firm innovative outcomes <ref type="bibr" coords="2,339.36,455.28,63.40,7.54" target="#b2">(Bourgeois, 1981)</ref>. A benefit of available slack is that firms can experiment knowing that resources will still remain even if the experimentation fails. When viewed in this way available slack within the firm allows managers the ability to take on many initiatives, including innovative efforts, knowing that a safety net exists if a given initiative is unsuccessful. Thus, the existence of available slack should positively impact firm innovative efforts <ref type="bibr" coords="2,423.38,518.10,68.72,7.54" target="#b39">(Thompson, 1967)</ref>. Conversely, it can also be argued that at a certain point controls used in selecting or terminating projects may become relaxed due to excessive available slack <ref type="bibr" coords="2,321.50,549.45,50.19,7.54" target="#b20">(Jensen, 1993)</ref>. In other words, because available slack is flexible and readily available to managers they may pursue or continue with projects that otherwise would be avoided or terminated if little or no available slack existed. This can result in a suboptimal level of innovation becoming acceptable to managers because of available slack in the firm and thus as available slack increases innovation may actually suffer. Therefore, on balance and consistent with the arguments of <ref type="bibr" coords="2,301.72,622.69,94.81,7.54" target="#b29">Nohria and Gulati (1996)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" coords="2,415.84,622.69,78.94,7.54" target="#b38">Tan and Peng (2003)</ref> both too much and too little available slack can be detrimental to innovation.</p><p>Recoverable slack has typically been operationalized using selling and general administrative expenses divided by sales <ref type="bibr" coords="2,492.77,654.04,60.00,7.54" target="#b4">(Bromiley, 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,301.72,664.53,89.67,7.54" target="#b30">Palmer &amp; Wiseman, 1999)</ref>. This measure identifies the amount of excess costs embedded within a firm that could be reduced and thus recovered during financially difficult times <ref type="bibr" coords="2,426.04,685.45,97.38,7.54" target="#b3">(Bourgeois &amp; Singh, 1983)</ref>. While recoverable slack is different from available slack discussed above, it is also a form of internal slack and thus much of the same logic applies to its relationship with innovation. For example, some firms retain more employees than needed to endure the ebb and flow of demand and general business activity. This increases expenses but also provides a buffer to ensure effectiveness if demand increases <ref type="bibr" coords="3,235.16,57.81,58.41,7.54;3,42.52,68.24,21.28,7.54" target="#b7">(Cyert &amp; March, 1963)</ref> and provides the embedded resources that allow for experimentation and innovative projects to be born <ref type="bibr" coords="3,194.56,78.73,84.05,7.54" target="#b29">(Nohria &amp; Gulati, 1996)</ref>. As such, following this line of reasoning recoverable slack is argued to have a positive impact on firm innovation. However, it can also be argued that excessive recoverable slack resources will cease to improve innovation. Agency theorists suggest that managers can become selfserving and wasteful <ref type="bibr" coords="3,116.39,131.06,92.10,7.54" target="#b19">(Jensen &amp; Meckling, 1976)</ref> and that in the presence of recoverable slack resources loose organizational controls and poor resource decisions are more likely to be made. This can take place because information asymmetry exists between principals and agents and thus specific to recoverable slack, managers can pad budgets and accumulate resources in a way that is difficult for agents to detect. Moreover, it is argued that recoverable slack in the form of excessive personnel or capital embedded in overhead can be difficult to recoup <ref type="bibr" coords="3,215.37,204.24,78.21,7.54" target="#b25">(Love &amp; Nohria, 2005)</ref> and forces such as power and politics can negatively impact the recovery of this type of slack <ref type="bibr" coords="3,132.94,225.16,73.91,7.54" target="#b16">(Herold et al., 2006)</ref>. This is quite different than is the case with available slack, however, this logic also suggests a similar relationship in that innovation should increase in the presence of recoverable slack but at some point the benefits of recoverable slack will be diminished or eliminated altogether. Given the conflicting arguments in the literature, on balance both too much and too little recoverable slack should also be detrimental to innovation <ref type="bibr" coords="3,258.51,287.92,35.08,7.54;3,42.52,298.41,48.44,7.54" target="#b12">(Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002)</ref>.</p><p>Lastly, potential slack has been operationalized using financial leverage variables such as a firm's debt to equity ratio <ref type="bibr" coords="3,245.65,319.33,47.94,7.54;3,42.52,329.76,46.52,7.54" target="#b3">(Bourgeois &amp; Singh, 1983;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,91.95,329.76,59.20,7.54" target="#b4">Bromiley, 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,154.03,329.76,96.36,7.54" target="#b30">Palmer &amp; Wiseman, 1999)</ref>. This slack component is external in nature because it represents the ability of a firm to secure resources with debt financing. It is argued that innovation is encouraged because the risks of experimentation are buffered when the potential for accessing outside resources exists suggesting a positive relationship between potential slack and innovation <ref type="bibr" coords="3,229.94,382.09,63.73,7.54;3,42.52,392.52,19.64,7.54" target="#b12">(Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002)</ref>. However, unlike available and recoverable slack the existence of potential slack should not by its very nature lead to issues of misuse because this component of slack consists of resources that are only potentially available to the firm and currently not utilized <ref type="bibr" coords="3,264.86,423.93,28.71,7.54;3,42.51,434.36,40.23,7.54" target="#b16">(Herold et al., 2006)</ref>. Moreover, the incurrence of debt financing implies future outflows in the form of interest expense and likely involves a high amount of scrutiny from principals and agents no matter the level that exists <ref type="bibr" coords="3,65.70,465.77,88.98,7.54" target="#b12">(Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,157.03,465.77,68.83,7.54" target="#b16">Herold et al., 2006)</ref>. For example, the issuance of long term debt may impact bond ratings and involve board approval. Thus, at high levels of potential slack the principalagent problem of monitoring and control <ref type="bibr" coords="3,187.82,497.17,77.53,7.54" target="#b25">(Love &amp; Nohria, 2005)</ref> is likely not a factor as is this case with available and recoverable slack. Based on these arguments, a positive relationship is expected between potential slack and innovation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Slack configurations and innovation</head><p>The above review and extension of prior research provides a framework within which to predict levels of slack that will be associated with higher and lower levels of firm innovation. These arguments, however, do not take into account the combined effects of the different types of slack. With an understanding that different firms will bundle resources in different ways, it is expected that different configurations of slack will exist among firms. Further, given the different types of slack and prior research findings it seems likely that different configurations of slack will result in different innovation outcomes. Firms with overall low slack will have few excess resources to take risks, will be restricted in the ability to absorb any internal or external shocks to the organization, and will have limited embedded resources that might induce innovation within the firm <ref type="bibr" coords="3,120.87,695.94,84.00,7.54" target="#b7">(Cyert &amp; March, 1963;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,207.89,695.94,63.56,7.54" target="#b39">Thompson, 1967)</ref>. This suggests that firms with low levels of each type of slack will have less opportunity to encourage innovation, absorb failures in experimentation, or secure external funding for innovative projects. While prior research findings support these arguments <ref type="bibr" coords="3,203.58,737.78,89.99,7.54" target="#b12">(Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,310.51,57.80,78.83,7.54" target="#b29">Nohria &amp; Gulati, 1996)</ref> no previous studies have examined this relationship while considering the different types of slack simultaneously as a bundle of resources. Thus, we propose the following hypothesis.</p><p>Hypothesis 1. Configurations exhibiting low levels of each type of slack (available, recoverable, and potential) will experience low levels of innovation.</p><p>High levels of available and recoverable slack are also expected to negatively impact innovation <ref type="bibr" coords="3,422.93,146.24,89.26,7.54" target="#b29">(Nohria &amp; Gulati, 1996)</ref> although for slightly different reasons. For example, it is argued that the existence of available slack will cause managers to relax controls when selecting or terminating projects which in turn could lead to fruitless projects and result in the potential opportunity cost of reduced innovation <ref type="bibr" coords="3,310.51,198.57,70.81,7.54" target="#b16">(Herold et al., 2006)</ref>. Recoverable slack on the other hand could come in the form of excess personnel and/or padded budgets. The presence of recoverable slack can lead to loose organizational controls because managers can use these resources in a way that is difficult for principals to detect and thus could involve suboptimal utilization of resources. Moreover, in the case of personnel, embedded slack resources are difficult to eliminate, recover, and in turn redeploy in innovation efforts <ref type="bibr" coords="3,310.51,271.82,75.35,7.54" target="#b16">(Herold et al., 2006)</ref>. With regard to potential slack, the literature suggests that the above arguments do not hold because potential slack is not currently available, the use of it involves future interest expense, and it requires a great deal of scrutiny from principals and agents <ref type="bibr" coords="3,335.90,313.66,86.64,7.54" target="#b12">(Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,424.69,313.66,66.81,7.54" target="#b16">Herold et al., 2006)</ref>. Prior research has found that high levels of potential slack do not negatively impact innovation <ref type="bibr" coords="3,353.48,334.58,90.66,7.54" target="#b12">(Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002)</ref>. Thus, it can be expected that firms displaying high levels of available and recoverable slack combined with a low level of potential slack will have low levels of innovation. Formally stated:</p><p>Hypothesis 2. Configurations exhibiting high levels of available and recoverable slack and a low level of potential slack will experience low levels of innovation.</p><p>Concerning higher innovation configurations, the relationship between internal slack (available and recoverable) and innovation has been argued to follow a curvilinear relationship such that at both lower and higher levels of slack innovation is reduced <ref type="bibr" coords="3,524.74,455.10,36.77,7.54;3,310.50,465.53,48.12,7.54" target="#b12">(Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002)</ref>. In other words moderate levels of available and recoverable slack should lead to higher levels of innovation. Again these arguments do not take into account the combined effects of the different types of slack. Given the expected relationships between both types of internal slack (available and recoverable) and innovation it seems reasonable to assume that the combined level of available and recoverable slack should be moderate since as discussed previously both low and high levels of available and recoverable slack can hurt innovation. Overall moderate levels of internal slack can be achieved in multiple ways such as high available slack combined with low recoverable slack, low available slack combined with high recoverable slack, and moderate available slack combined with moderate recoverable slack to name a few. Thus, to maximize innovation firms should avoid having high or low levels of both available and recoverable slack.</p><p>With regard to potential slack, prior research suggests that the slack and innovation relationship is positive and remains positive even at higher levels of slack <ref type="bibr" coords="3,387.44,632.96,85.62,7.54" target="#b12">(Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002)</ref>. Unlike internal slack, it is not expected that potential slack will suffer from the same agency issues such as information asymmetry among principals and agents because a great deal of scrutiny is expected when the use of potential slack is considered <ref type="bibr" coords="3,380.29,674.80,86.40,7.54" target="#b12">(Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002)</ref>. Given this, it is expected that high levels of potential slack will be beneficial to firm innovation independent of available and recoverable slack. These arguments provide a framework to hypothesize which slack configurations will lead to higher levels of innovation such that to maximize innovation the combined level of internal slack (available and recoverable) should at least be moderate but not too high so as to negatively impact innovation, while potential slack should be moderate to high to provide a buffer for the firm and foster innovation. This leads to our final hypothesis.</p><p>Hypothesis 3. Configurations exhibiting moderate combined levels of available and recoverable slack and a moderate to high level of potential slack with experience higher levels of innovation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Sample</head><p>Our study sample was drawn from the S&amp;P 500, Mid-cap 400, and Small-cap 600 indices for the year 2010. Since levels of slack and innovation can be expected to vary widely across broader industry groupings we chose to only examine manufacturing firms (identified as those competing in the 2000 through 3999 SIC code industries) in this study. The year 2010 was chosen since it was at the time of data collection the most recent year which would allow for complete data to be collected. These choices resulted in an initial sample of 579 firms.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Slack measures</head><p>We utilized a total of seven variables to capture available, recoverable, and potential slack <ref type="bibr" coords="4,128.69,305.89,97.28,7.54" target="#b3">(Bourgeois &amp; Singh, 1983)</ref>. The measures chosen are consistent with prior research <ref type="bibr" coords="4,193.43,316.33,91.35,7.54" target="#b1">(Bergh &amp; Lawless, 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="4,33.73,326.81,96.33,7.54" target="#b3">Bourgeois &amp; Singh, 1983;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="4,133.68,326.81,59.88,7.54" target="#b4">Bromiley, 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="4,197.18,326.81,87.60,7.54" target="#b6">Cheng &amp; Kesner, 1997;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="4,33.73,337.25,83.12,7.54" target="#b12">Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="4,118.94,337.25,91.92,7.54" target="#b30">Palmer &amp; Wiseman, 1999)</ref>. In addition, to help in the determination of causality we used a one year time lag with slack measured in 2009 and innovation measured in 2010. Available slack was operationalized using three measures: current ratio (current assets divided by current liabilities), quick ratio (current assets minus inventories divided by current liabilities), and working capital (current assets minus current liabilities divided by sales). Potential slack was operationalized using three measures: debt to equity, debt to sales, and debt to assets. Finally, recoverable slack was operationalized using a single measure: selling, general, and administrative expenses divided by sales.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Innovation</head><p>We chose three measures of innovation for this study: R&amp;D expenditures, patent applications and patents granted. This allowed us to capture both important inputs into the innovation process and important outputs of a firm's innovative activities. Since a firm's patent activities can vary significantly from year to year and often takes several years to develop and come to fruition we used a three year average (2010-2012) in these calculations. Finally, since the use of ratio measures can be problematic <ref type="bibr" coords="4,47.72,558.46,60.59,7.54" target="#b41">(Wiseman, 2009)</ref> we chose not to adjust these measures for firm size which is a commonly used approach in the literature <ref type="bibr" coords="4,221.88,568.89,62.90,7.54;4,33.73,579.38,20.76,7.54" target="#b12">(Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="4,56.86,579.38,148.82,7.54" target="#b17">Hitt, Hoskisson, Johnson, &amp; Moesel, 1996)</ref>. Instead we used the actual levels of R&amp;D expenditures, patent applications and patents granted and as described below we included firm sales as a control measure. It is worth noting that we replicated our analyses using innovation measures adjusted for firm sales and found very similar results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.">Control measures</head><p>Innovation may be impacted by other organizational variables and thus firm size, product diversification, geographic diversification, financial performance, and industry innovation levels were used as controls. <ref type="bibr" coords="4,65.82,695.94,57.28,7.54" target="#b32">Rumelt's (1974)</ref> relatedness ratio was used to capture product diversification. Geographic diversification was operationalized using the percentage of foreign sales relative to total sales. Return on assets was used to measure financial performance. Firm sales was used to control for firm size. Finally, since industry setting is likely to affect firm innovation it was important to control for industry effects. Consistent with <ref type="bibr" coords="4,336.47,68.24,59.04,7.54" target="#b17">Hitt et al. (1996)</ref> this was accomplished by grouping all firms in the sample into primary 2-digit SIC code industry groups, calculating average innovations levels, and using these averages as controls.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5.">Analyses</head><p>To identify configurations we cluster analyzed the slack measures. Since cluster analysis can be sensitive to outliers we trimmed all slack measures at three standard deviations from the mean. In addition, since the outcome of interest was firm innovation we removed from the sample firms not actively spending money on R&amp;D. These choices reduced the size of our sample from 579 to 437 manufacturing firms. Because of the likelihood of multicollinearity among the slack measures and the severe problems it can pose with cluster analysis <ref type="bibr" coords="4,511.87,204.24,40.91,7.54;4,301.72,214.73,45.04,7.54" target="#b24">(Ketchen &amp; Shook, 1996)</ref>, we first factor analyzed the slack measures using principal components analysis with varimax rotation and used the uncorrelated factor scores as the basis for clustering.</p><p>We then preprocessed the data using SAS's ACECLUS procedure and used the Ward's minimum variance clustering method. The identification of optimal cluster solutions was based on visual inspection of the tree-plots along with the following decision criteria: (1) the clusters explain at least 65% of the overall variance, (2) with an additional cluster increasing the overall fit by less than 5%, (3) with a local peak in the Cubic Clustering Criterion, (4) with a local peak in the pseudo F statistic combined, and (5) with a small value of the pseudo t 2 statistic and a larger pseudo t 2 statistic for the next cluster fusion. When discrepancies existed across these decision criteria, we relied on visual inspection of the tree-plots and prioritized our use of each decision criteria in the order in which they are listed above. These decision criteria are consistent with those used in prior configurational research (i.e., <ref type="bibr" coords="4,509.39,371.66,43.40,7.54;4,301.72,382.09,60.50,7.54" target="#b10">Fiegenbaum &amp; Thomas, 1990;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="4,364.37,382.09,112.15,7.54" target="#b27">Marlin, Ritchie, &amp; Geiger, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="4,478.66,382.09,74.07,7.54" target="#b22">Ketchen et al., 1993)</ref> and with clustering stopping rules recommended by the SAS Manual (SAS <ref type="bibr" coords="4,322.13,403.01,58.02,7.54" target="#b34">Institute, 2003)</ref> and by the SAS Technical Report A-108 (SAS <ref type="bibr" coords="4,301.72,413.50,52.76,7.54" target="#b33">Institute, 1983)</ref>.</p><p>Once our cluster analysis was complete, we ran ANOVAs to determine whether the clusters differed on the underlying slack measures and whether the results of our cluster analysis produced different slack configurations. We then ran pair-wise means comparisons on each slack measure to determine where the configurations differed. Next, we used ANCOVA to test for between configuration differences in innovation. Finally, least-squares means (i.e., means adjusted for our controls) comparisons were utilized to test for and identify specific innovation differences between the identified slack configurations. <ref type="table" coords="4,313.68,549.45,25.25,7.54" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> reports descriptive statistics and correlations for all variables used in the study. The descriptive statistics show that the firms varied in innovation as well as the slack and control variables examined. The cluster analysis of 437 firms produced clusters representing six slack configurations. <ref type="table" coords="4,359.32,591.34,27.12,7.54" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> reports the results of ANOVAs and pairwise tests for configuration differences along the slack measures. Significant differences were found across configurations with all slack measures suggesting the existence of distinct slack configurations. <ref type="table" coords="4,524.30,622.69,28.48,7.54" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> provides a summary of each configuration based on level and type of slack (and innovation which will be discussed later). Below we highlight and provide a brief interpretation of the configurations to facilitate the discussion of our results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Configuration 1: constrained borrowers</head><p>Configuration 1 was labeled constrained borrowers. The main characteristics of this configuration included moderately low available, potential, and recoverable slack. Specifically, relative to other configurations this group had the second lowest available and recoverable slack and was slightly below average for potential slack. Thus, this configuration was constrained with overall low internal slack but utilized a moderately high level of debt financing and thus was limited in the area of potential slack.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Configuration 2: spenders/borrowers</head><p>Configuration 4 was characterized by having high recoverable slack, moderate available slack, and low potential slack. Labeled as spenders/borrowers, this group embedded slack into the firm by spending firm resources on things such as employees, marketing, and administration that could later be reduced if necessary. However, this configuration was similar to configuration 1 in that it utilized a high level of debt financing and thus was also limited in the area of potential slack. Spenders/borrowers ranked the highest in recoverable slack, the third highest in available slack and the second lowest in potential slack.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Configuration 3: hoarders</head><p>Configuration 3 was labeled hoarders. This group ranked the highest in available and potential slack and ranked third in recoverable slack. Thus, the main characteristic of this group was the significant amount of readily available resources stashed away for use at a later time as well as the low level of borrowing utilized. Relative to other configurations this group had a moderate level of recoverable slack spending less than configurations 2 and 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.">Configuration 4: moderate accumulators</head><p>Configuration 4 which was labeled moderate accumulators exhibited the second highest level of each type of slack and was closest to configuration 3 in the area of potential slack but higher with regard to recoverable slack. This group uses little debt and strikes a balance between accumulating available resources and spending resources which creates recoverable slack. Thus, they have moderately high levels of available, potential and recoverable slack.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5.">Configuration 5: refrainers</head><p>Configuration 5 ranked fourth in available and recoverable slack and third in potential slack. Labeled refrainers, this group was similar to configuration 1 in that it had moderately low levels of available resources. However, this group had moderate levels of spending and refrained from utilizing significant levels of debt. Thus, this group had moderately low levels of available slack, moderate recoverable slack, and retained moderately high levels of potential slack.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.6.">Configuration 6: depleters</head><p>This the smallest configuration was labeled depleters. This group had the lowest levels of all three types of slack. Thus, these firms had little available slack, few embedded resources and thus little recoverable slack, and finally a depleted availability of potential slack from external sources due to high levels of debt financing. Overall, this group had a depleted level of all resources and as such had low overall slack.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.7.">Innovation results</head><p>In <ref type="table" coords="6,54.94,235.37,25.76,7.54" target="#tab_3">Table 4</ref> we report ANCOVA tests of innovation differences across the identified slack configurations. In these analyses we controlled for the effects of firm size, product diversification, geographic diversification, financial performance, and industry levels of innovation. All multivariate and univariate tests were significant (p b .01 to p b .001) for innovation differences between the identified configurations. These results suggest an overall effect of cluster membership and thus slack configurations on firm innovation. Finally, with regards to our control variables, firm size and industry were significantly related (p b .01 to p b .001) to all three innovation measures and foreign sales was significantly related (p b .10 to p b .05) to patents granted and patent applications. <ref type="table" coords="6,45.69,350.46,25.76,7.54" target="#tab_4">Table 5</ref> presents least squares means comparisons which tested for innovation differences between slack configurations while again controlling for firm size, product diversification, geographic diversification, financial performance, and industry levels of innovation. The pairwise comparisons revealed significant innovation differences (p b .05) between the identified configurations using all three innovation measures. It is worth noting that spenders/borrowers (configuration 2), hoarders (configuration 3), and moderate accumulators (configuration 4) are higher slack configurations while constrained borrowers (configuration 1), refrainers (configuration 5), and depleters (configuration 6) are lower slack configurations.</p><p>Concerning our hypotheses, moderate support was found for Hypothesis 1 which predicted that configurations exhibiting low levels of each type of slack would experience low levels of innovation. Constrained borrowers (configuration 1) and depleters (configuration 6) had low or moderately low levels of each type of slack and produced the lowest levels of innovation. Hypothesis 2 which predicted that configurations exhibiting overall high levels of available and recoverable slack and a low level of potential slack would experience low levels of innovation was not supported. Our analyses did not produce any configurations with high levels of both available and recoverable slack combined with a low level of potential slack. The configuration which came closest to this slack profile was that of spenders/borrowers (configuration 2) which had moderate available, high recoverable and low potential slack and produced higher levels of innovation. Finally, Hypothesis 3 which predicted that configurations exhibiting moderate combined levels of available and recoverable slack and a moderate to high level of potential slack would experience higher levels of innovation received some support. More specifically, hoarders (configurations 3) and moderate accumulators (configuration 4) both had moderately high combined levels of internal slack (available and recoverable slack) and moderately high levels of potential slack and produced high levels of innovation. Finally, and as mentioned above spenders/ borrowers (configuration 2) also had moderately high combined levels of internal slack (available and recoverable slack) but had a low level of potential slack and generally produced high levels of innovation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.8.">Reliability and validity</head><p>Following procedures recommended by <ref type="bibr" coords="6,456.32,188.54,92.66,7.54" target="#b24">Ketchen and Shook (1996)</ref>, we conducted an assessment of the reliability and validity of our cluster analyses and of our results. This consisted of two main assessment areas: (1) multicollinearity among our slack measures, and (2) the stability and consistency of our cluster results. Concerning multicollinearity our rotated factor pattern supported the existence of three components of slack (i.e., available, potential, and recoverable) with all factor loadings above .75 and the highest cross-loading being .321. Further, Cronbach's alphas on the three available and three potential slack measures were both above .83. These analyses support our use of factor analysis and the resulting uncorrelated factor scores as the basis for clustering. To further examine the reliability and validity of our results we performed multiple cluster analyses changing the approach we used to measure slack and thus control for multicollinearity. The agreement in cluster assignments across all approaches used ranged from 68% to 73%. More importantly, the results of each of these additional analyses were nearly identical to those reported above. Additional analyses were then performed concerning and more specific to the stability and validity of our cluster results. This involved using two additional clustering approaches. The agreement in cluster assignments across all approaches ranged from 68% to 79% and produced cluster and innovation results nearly identical to those reported above. Further details about these analyses are available from the authors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Discussion</head><p>The findings of this study show that different configurations of slack resources are associated with differences in firm innovation. The configurations associated with a combined level of moderate/high internal slack (available and recoverable slack) had the highest levels of innovation. Specifically, moderate accumulators (configuration 4) were among the highest level of innovators for all three innovation measures and demonstrated moderate/high levels of all three types of slack. Hoarders (configuration 3) were among the highest level of innovators for two of the three innovation measures and demonstrated high available slack, moderate recoverable slack, and moderate/high potential slack. Spenders/borrowers (configuration 2) were among the highest level of innovators for one of the three innovation measures and demonstrated a high level of recoverable slack, moderate available slack, and low potential slack. Conversely, constrained borrowers (configuration 1), refrainers (configuration 5), and depleters (configuration 6) had lower levels of innovation for all three innovation measures used and demonstrated  lower levels of internal slack (available and recoverable) and varying levels of potential slack. Overall, these findings suggest that at moderately high levels, internal slack (available and recoverable) has a positive impact on a firm innovation. Moreover, these results suggest that while a positive relationship tends to exist between potential slack and innovation this may be tempered by the level of available or recoverable slack within the firm. For example, spenders/borrowers and constrained borrowers had slightly different potential and available slack, but spenders/borrowers had much higher recoverable slack and benefited from a much higher level of innovation than constrained borrowers for all three measures of innovation. Overall, these findings provide support for the behavioral argument that slack provides a positive impact on organizational outcomes such as innovation. However, none of the configurations in this study had high levels of all types of slack and thus it is difficult to determine if high overall slack would negatively impact innovation. As such, the negative impacts of slack that are argued from an agency theory perspective cannot be completely dismissed.</p><p>This study contributes to prior slack research by utilizing a configurational approach and considering the combined effects of different types of slack on innovative outcomes. Our results suggest that different types or bundles of slack resources result in different or varying levels of firm innovative activities. This study provides a richer description of how multiple types and levels of slack are related to a firm's innovative activities by identifying bundles or configurations of slack resources. Overall, the results of this study suggest that slack is positively related to innovation. However, this differs somewhat from prior research which suggests an inverted U shaped relationship between slack and innovation <ref type="bibr" coords="7,84.24,444.85,86.26,7.54" target="#b29">(Nohria &amp; Gulati, 1996)</ref> and between some types of slack and innovation <ref type="bibr" coords="7,99.72,455.28,86.72,7.54" target="#b12">(Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002)</ref>. These prior studies failed to account for either multiple slack measures <ref type="bibr" coords="7,198.36,465.77,85.30,7.54" target="#b29">(Nohria &amp; Gulati, 1996)</ref> or how firms configure or bundle multiple types of slack resources <ref type="bibr" coords="7,42.52,486.69,84.90,7.54" target="#b12">(Geiger &amp; Cashen, 2002)</ref>. Thus, an important contribution of this study is that while level of slack may be important, how the various types of slack are bundled also serves as an important factor in firm outcomes and should be examined by future researchers. The current study neither supports nor runs counter to prior slack research in that no other studies have examined the simultaneous impact of slack bundles on innovation. In general, this study does support the view that the presence of slack is positively related to firm innovation. Future research will be needed to determine if, and the degree to which, high overall slack profiles exhibit the negative influences on innovation as argued by agency theorists.</p><p>The results indicate multiple ways of bundling slack resources that can lead to similar innovation outcomes suggesting that equifinality <ref type="bibr" coords="7,42.52,622.69,71.02,7.54" target="#b21">(Katz &amp; Kahn, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="7,115.31,622.69,82.12,7.54" target="#b14">Gresov &amp; Drazin, 1997)</ref> exists among some configurations. The three configurations that had the highest levels of innovation had significantly different slack profiles yet statistically similar levels of innovation. For example, hoarders (configuration 3) and moderate accumulators (configuration 4) enjoyed a statistically equal high level of innovation for two of the three innovation measures but had different slack profiles for two of the three slack dimensions. This result suggests equally effective ways to manage slack resources to achieve innovative outcomes and adds to prior research that has found that equifinality exists with regards to firm outcomes in service industries <ref type="bibr" coords="7,83.11,727.29,159.49,7.54" target="#b18">(Jennings, Rajaratnam, &amp; Lawrence, 2003)</ref>, in different compensation systems <ref type="bibr" coords="7,130.11,737.73,67.97,7.54" target="#b9">(Eisenhardt, 1988)</ref>, among strategic groups <ref type="bibr" coords="7,310.51,162.40,122.03,7.54" target="#b26">(Marlin, Ketchen, &amp; Lamont, 2007)</ref>, between organizational configurations <ref type="bibr" coords="7,329.78,172.89,47.08,7.54" target="#b31">(Payne, 2006)</ref>, among configurations of contextual factors <ref type="bibr" coords="7,534.27,172.89,27.27,7.54;7,310.51,183.32,57.48,7.54" target="#b11">(Ganter &amp; Hecker, 2014)</ref>, and between configurations or different bundles of sales and distribution resources <ref type="bibr" coords="7,430.98,193.81,74.90,7.54" target="#b15">(Gruber et al., 2010)</ref>. The evidence of equifinality found in this study provides a significant extension to the literature on slack and innovation.</p><p>The results of this study also have important practical implications. Our findings suggest that slack impacts innovation and it may do so in ways not yet considered. More specifically, our results suggest that managers can achieve similar levels of innovation inputs and outputs using different patterns of slack resources. This is good news for managers as it provides for alternative pathways to the same end in that they can use the approach that best fits their organization and its resources. Thus, attention should be paid to identifying appropriate levels for each type of slack as part of an appropriate slack profile and how this slack profile could impact a critical firm outcome such as innovation.</p><p>Our study also has limitations that provide opportunities for future research. First, it must be recognized that we examined the slack and innovation relationship using cross-sectional data and only with U.S. manufacturing firms. As such, different slack configurations and innovation results could be found using other industries or time frames. Also, the measures used in this study are not necessarily appropriate indicators of slack resources or of innovation in other settings. For example, our measures of innovation would clearly not be appropriate for the examination of firms in the retail industry. Future research should consider examining the slack and innovation relationship using a configurational approach in other industry settings and using longitudinal data. Overall, this study provides a unique contribution to the slack and innovation literature and should provide a framework for future research utilizing alternative methods for investigating this and other relationships. We also hope that our findings will provide managers with useful insight when making slack resource decisions. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="5,42.51,58.07,513.06,200.89"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Descriptive statistics.</figDesc><table coords="5,42.51,81.20,513.06,177.76">Variable 
Mean 
sd 
1 
2 
3 
4 
5 
6 
7 
8 
9 
10 
11 
12 
13 

1 Current ratio 
3.042 
1.895 
2 Quick ratio 
2.333 
1.683 
.962 
3 Working capital 
.403 
.337 
.837 
.845 
4 Debt/equity a 
.534 
.957 
.272 
.273 
.268 
5 Debt/sales a 
.211 
.197 
.285 
.277 
.211 
.427 
6 Debt/assets a 
.166 
.137 
.415 
.423 
.401 
.618 
.853 
7 SGA expenses 
.288 
.160 
.364 
.435 
.526 
.164 
.007 
.202 
8 Relatedness ratio 
.902 
.170 
.202 
.207 
.203 
.066 
.116 
.131 
.210 
9 Foreign sales 
.441 
.269 
.048 
.067 
.172 
.049 
.022 
.086 
.093 
.053 
10 Return on assets 
.076 
.068 
.055 
.071 
.028 
.016 
.131 
.102 
.063 
.113 
.087 
11 Firm sales 
7.499 
1.565 
.549 
.511 
.495 
.274 
.292 
.360 
.374 
.228 
.110 
.083 
12 R&amp;D expenditures 
301.265 
907.443 
.113 
.069 
.020 
.050 
.128 
.008 
.103 
.054 
.124 
.070 
.463 
13 Patents granted 
196.030 
533.778 
.099 
.049 
.026 
.023 
.036 
.033 
.002 
.110 
.218 
.110 
.446 
.533 
14 Patent applications 
103.430 
315.260 
.060 
.018 
.013 
.003 
.044 
.031 
.020 
.104 
.187 
.076 
.343 
.330 
.747 

N = 437. 
If correlation N |.083| p b .05. 
If correlation N |.110| p b .01. 
If correlation N |.142| p b .001. 
a Higher values indicate lower slack. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,42.52,599.55,513.09,145.69"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Configuration means and results of tests for significant differences.</figDesc><table coords="5,124.78,622.68,39.82,6.03">Configuration 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="6,33.73,58.07,244.98,136.82"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Configuration summary based on level and type of slack. Type of slack c,d a Moderate equals the mean and each category is within +/ half of a standard deviation. b Based on an average of the three measures used for this type of slack. c Numbers in bold indicate higher innovation configurations. d Numbers in italics indicate lower innovation configurations.</figDesc><table coords="6,39.68,92.97,239.03,54.89">Level of slack a 
Available b 
Potential b 
Recoverable 

High 
3 
-
2 
Moderate/high 
4 
3 4 5 
4 
Moderate 
2 
-
3 5 
Low/moderate 
1 5 6 
1 
1 6 
Low 
-
2 6 
-

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="6,33.50,646.89,513.32,98.35"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Multivariate and univariate innovation results.+ p b .10.  p b .05.  p b .01.  p b .001.</figDesc><table coords="6,39.68,670.02,507.14,36.19">Variable 
Firm sales 
Relatedness ratio 
Foreign sales 
Return on assets 
Industry innovation 
Configuration 
Overall F 

R&amp;D Expenditures 
157.86  
0.06 
1.19 
0.81 
21.81  
14.33  
24.58  
Patents granted 
130.26  
1.17 
3.98  
0.06 
17.86  
6.09  
19.83  
Patent applications 
62.54  
1.89 
3.49 + 
0.01 
7.96  
3.70  
10.57  

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="7,42.52,58.07,513.09,85.71"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Least squares innovation means across configurations and results of means comparisons.  p b .05.</figDesc><table coords="7,48.47,81.20,507.14,49.48">Configuration 

Variable 
1 
2 
3 
4 
5 
6 
Means comparisons  

R&amp;D expenditures 
65.05 
946.77 
619.73 
624.76 
303.86 
144.65 
2,4,3 N 5,6,1; 2 N 4; 5 N 1 
Patents granted 
62.41 
252.26 
349.76 
430.45 
180.58 
42.48 
4,3 N 5,1,6; 2,5 N 1 
Patent applications 
48.54 
170.30 
155.31 
222.46 
83.41 
3.29 
4 N 5,1,6; 2 N 1,6; 3 N 1 

</table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,310.51,545.63,250.95,6.03;7,322.47,553.63,239.06,6.03;7,322.47,561.56,26.35,6.03" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Drivers of R&amp;D investment: the interaction of behavioral theory and managerial incentives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Alessandri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pattit</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Business Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="158" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,310.51,569.56,250.99,6.03;7,322.47,577.55,239.13,6.03;7,322.47,585.49,89.47,6.03" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Portfolio restructuring and limits to hierarchical governance: the effects of environmental uncertainty and diversification strategy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bergh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lawless</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organization Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="102" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,310.51,593.48,251.02,6.03;7,322.47,601.42,86.27,6.03" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the measurement of organizational slack</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bourgeois</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Academy of Management Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="39" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,310.51,609.41,251.02,6.03;7,322.47,617.40,187.19,6.03" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Organizational slack and political behavior within top management groups</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bourgeois</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
			<publisher>Academy of Management Proceedings</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="43" to="47" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,310.51,625.34,251.05,6.03;7,322.47,633.34,123.41,6.03" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Testing a causal model of corporate risk taking and performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bromiley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<publisher>Academy of Management Journal</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="59" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,310.51,641.18,250.96,6.38;7,322.47,649.27,239.06,6.03;7,322.47,657.20,70.85,6.03" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does technological diversification matter to firm performance? The moderating role of organizational slack</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Business Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1970" to="1975" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,310.51,665.20,251.02,6.03;7,322.47,673.19,215.33,6.03" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Organizational slack and response to environmental shifts: the impact of resource allocation patterns</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Kesner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="18" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,310.51,681.03,251.01,6.38;7,322.47,689.12,38.31,6.03" xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A behavioral theory of the firm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Cyert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>March</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1963" />
			<publisher>Prentice-Hall</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Englewood Cliffs, NJ</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,310.51,696.96,251.11,6.38;7,322.47,705.05,195.07,6.03" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Slack resources and firm performance: a meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Daniel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Lohrke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Fornaciari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Business Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="565" to="574" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,310.51,713.04,251.02,6.03;7,322.47,720.98,189.19,6.03" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Agency-and institutional-theory explanations: the case of retail sales compensation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Eisenhardt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Academy of Management Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="488" to="511" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,310.51,728.97,251.02,6.03;7,322.47,736.91,178.64,6.03" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strategic groups and performance: the U.S. insurance industry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fiegenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Strategic Management Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="197" to="215" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,33.73,56.49,251.02,6.03;8,45.69,64.48,239.06,6.03;8,45.69,72.42,95.65,6.03" xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Configurational paths to organizational innovation: qualitative comparative analyses of antecedents and contingencies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ganter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hecker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Business Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1285" to="1292" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,33.73,80.41,251.05,6.03;8,45.69,88.35,173.81,6.03" xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A multidimensional examination of slack and its impact on innovation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Geiger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Cashen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Managerial Issues</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="68" to="84" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,33.73,96.34,251.12,6.03;8,45.69,104.18,239.00,6.38;8,45.69,112.27,97.91,6.03" xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploration and exploitation innovation processes: the role of organizational slack in R&amp;D intensive firms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Geiger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Makri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of High Technology Management Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="108" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,33.73,120.26,251.03,6.03;8,45.69,128.20,130.51,6.03" xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Equifinality: functional equivalence in organization design</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gresov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Drazin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Academy of Management Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="403" to="428" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,33.73,136.20,251.05,6.03;8,45.69,144.13,239.03,6.03;8,45.69,152.13,190.59,6.03" xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Configurations of resources and capabilities and their performance implications: an exploratory study on technology ventures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gruber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Heinemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brettel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hungeling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Strategic Management Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1337" to="1356" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,33.73,160.12,251.00,6.03;8,45.69,168.06,239.06,6.03;8,45.69,176.05,26.35,6.03" xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What is the relationship between organizational slack and innovation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Herold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Jayaraman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Narayanaswamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Managerial Issues</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="372" to="392" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,33.73,183.99,251.12,6.03;8,45.69,191.98,206.03,6.03" xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The market for corporate control and innovation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hoskisson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Moesel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Academy of Management Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1084" to="1119" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,33.73,199.97,251.01,6.03;8,45.69,207.81,239.06,6.38;8,45.69,215.90,26.35,6.03" xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strategy-performance relationships in service firms: a test for equifinality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Jennings</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rajaratnam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Lawrence</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Managerial Issues</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="208" to="220" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,33.73,223.75,251.12,6.38;8,45.69,231.83,207.67,6.03" xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Theory of the firm: managerial behavior, agency cost, and ownership structure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Jensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Meckling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Financial Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="305" to="360" />
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,33.73,239.77,251.02,6.03;8,45.69,247.77,126.37,6.03" xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The modern industrial revolution, exit, and failure of internal control systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Jensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Finance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="831" to="880" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,33.73,255.76,251.02,6.03" xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The social psychology of organizations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Kahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York, NY</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,33.73,263.70,251.01,6.03;8,45.69,271.69,239.01,6.03;8,45.69,279.63,66.37,6.03" xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Organizational configurations and performance: a comparison of theoretical approaches</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ketchen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Snow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Academy of Management Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1278" to="1313" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,33.73,287.62,250.98,6.03;8,45.69,295.62,239.06,6.03;8,45.69,303.55,97.01,6.03" xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Organizational configurations and performance: a meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ketchen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Combs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Shook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Runge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Academy of Management Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="223" to="240" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,33.73,311.55,251.02,6.03;8,45.69,319.48,239.06,6.03;8,45.69,327.48,26.35,6.03" xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The application of cluster analysis in strategic management research: an analysis and critique</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ketchen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Shook</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Strategic Management Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="441" to="458" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,301.72,56.48,251.05,6.03;8,313.68,64.38,239.06,6.38;8,313.68,72.41,33.51,6.03" xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reducing slack: the performance consequences of downsizing by large industrial firms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Love</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Nohria</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Strategic Management Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1087" to="1108" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,301.72,80.31,251.06,6.38;8,313.68,88.34,191.67,6.03" xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Equifinality and the strategic groupsperformance relationship</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Marlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ketchen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Lamont</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Managerial Issues</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="208" to="232" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,301.72,96.34,251.03,6.03;8,313.68,104.27,210.62,6.03" xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strategic group membership and nonprofit organization performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Marlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ritchie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Geiger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nonprofit Management &amp; Leadership</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="39" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,301.72,112.27,251.02,6.03;8,313.68,120.26,138.94,6.03" xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward a new contingency perspective: the search for organizational gestalts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Management Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,301.72,128.20,251.02,6.03;8,313.68,136.19,104.02,6.03" xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Is slack good or bad for innovation?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Nohria</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gulati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<publisher>Academy of Management Journal</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1245" to="1264" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,301.72,144.13,251.04,6.04;8,313.68,152.13,234.20,6.03" xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decoupling risk taking from income stream uncertainty: a holistic model of risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wiseman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Strategic Management Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1037" to="1062" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,301.72,160.02,251.02,6.38;8,313.68,168.06,155.00,6.03" xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Examining configurations and firm performance in a suboptimal equifinality context</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Payne</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organization Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="756" to="770" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,301.72,176.05,251.06,6.03;8,313.68,183.99,46.98,6.03" xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Strategy, structure and economic performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Rumelt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
			<publisher>Harvard University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Boston, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,301.72,191.98,251.11,6.03;8,313.68,199.98,37.60,6.03" xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The cubic clustering criterion. SAS technical report A-108</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A S</forename><surname>Institute</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
			<publisher>SAS Institute</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cary, NC</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,301.72,207.91,219.39,6.03" xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">SAS/STAT user&apos;s guide, version 8. Cary, N.C.: SAS Institute</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sas Institute</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,301.72,215.91,251.01,6.03;8,313.68,223.84,239.06,6.03" xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Research on organizational configurations: past accomplishments and future challenges</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Short</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Payne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ketchen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1053" to="1079" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,301.72,231.84,199.89,6.03" xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Administrative behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1957" />
			<publisher>Free Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York, NY</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,301.72,239.77,251.03,6.03;8,313.68,247.77,130.55,6.03" xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Performance, slack and risk-taking in organizational decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Academy of Management Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="562" to="585" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,301.72,255.66,251.12,6.38;8,313.68,263.70,239.06,6.03;8,313.68,271.69,43.58,6.03" xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Organizational slack and firm performance during economic transitions: two studies from an emerging economy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Peng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Strategic Management Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1249" to="1263" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,301.72,279.63,215.52,6.03" xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Organizations in action</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
			<publisher>McGraw-Hill</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York, NY</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,301.72,287.62,251.02,6.03;8,313.68,295.61,239.13,6.03;8,313.68,303.55,59.31,6.03" xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of slack resources and environmental threat on product exploration and exploitation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Voss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sirdeshmukh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Voss</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Academy of Management Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="147" to="164" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,301.72,311.54,251.03,6.03;8,313.68,319.48,239.05,6.03;8,313.68,327.48,38.88,6.03" xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the use and misuse of ratios in strategic management research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wiseman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Research methodology in strategy and management</title>
		<editor>D.D. Bergh, &amp; D.J. Ketchen</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="110" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
