<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/jwu/github/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Performance Gender Gap: Does Competition Matter?</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Evren</forename><surname>Ors</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">EDHEC Business School</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hec</forename><surname>Paris</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">EDHEC Business School</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frédéric</forename><surname>Cepr</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">EDHEC Business School</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Palomino</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">EDHEC Business School</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Performance Gender Gap: Does Competition Matter?</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>

		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.0-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID-SDO" when="2019-12-20T15:12+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid-sdo"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Eloïc Peyrache, HEC Paris</head><p>Using data for students undertaking a series of real-world academic examinations with high future payoffs, we examine whether the differences in these evaluations' competitive nature generate a performance gender gap. In the univariate setting we find that women's performance is first-order stochastically dominated by that of men when the competition is higher, whereas the reverse holds true in the less competitive or noncompetitive tests. These results are confirmed in the multivariate setting. Our findings, from a real-world setting with important payoffs at stake, are in line with the evidence from experimental research that finds that females tend to perform worse in more competitive contexts.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I. Introduction</head><p>A new line of research, mainly experimental, suggests that there are performance differences among males and females in competitive environments. For example, Gneezy, Niederle, and Rustichini ð2003Þ find that men's We would like to thank Jeffrey Smith ðthe associate editorÞ, David Thesmar, and participants at the 2008 Centre for Economic Policy Research/Research Training Network Conference on Economics of Education and Education Policy in Europe in Amsterdam ðOctober 24-25, 2008Þ for their helpful comments. We also would like to thank Bernard Ramanantsoa ðdean of HEC ParisÞ and Thierry Debay ðdirector of La Direction des Admissions et ConcoursÞ for allowing us to access the confidential entrance exam data, Virginie Charton and Xavier Lecoustillier for their performance increases as the competitiveness of the experimental test increases, while that of females does not. Similarly, Niederle and Vesterlund ð2007Þ observe that, after experiencing both noncompetitive and competitive tournament-type tasks in experiments, males show a much larger preference for competitive tournament-type tasks than females ð73% for the former as opposed to 35% for the latterÞ. However, evidence from more recent empirical studies that use field data does not necessarily point to a performance difference across genders in competitive setups. While Kleinjans ð2009Þ finds that women have a greater distaste for competition, Lavy ð2008bÞ finds no gender-based difference in a rank-order tournament among high school teachers in which prizes are based on their students' performance, whereas Paserman ð2010Þ, examining the performance of highly competitive professional tennis players during grand-slam tournaments, finds no difference in forced errors across genders during critical points of the game. In a recent addition to this literature, Jurajda and Munich ð2011Þ examine multiple university entrance exams taken by the same individuals and find that women do not shy away from applying to more competitive institutions, but men perform better than women in entrance exams for these more prestigious institutions, even though no such difference exists for the exams of the less competitive schools.</p><p>The main contribution of our article is to add to this growing literature on gender gap in performance by comparing real-world academic achievement examinations between men and women in contexts characterized by different levels of competition for the same group of subjects. Our field data come from a series of academic tests for the same individuals in a setting in which future, career-related, payoffs are economically high. While these academic achievement tests are not directly comparable with the more controlled environment of laboratory experiments used in the literature, our findings suggest in a parallel vein that performance differences arise across genders when the competitiveness of the tests increases.</p><p>Specifically, we examine three cohorts of candidates over the period 2005-7 taking the competitive entrance exam for admission to the Master of Science in Management ðhereafter MScÞ at Ecole des Hautes Etudes Commerciales in Paris ðhereafter HEC; recently changed officially to HEC ParisÞ, a business school that is ranked first in France and in Europe. Only 380 out of approximately 3,400 candidates are admitted each year following a series of written and oral exams. The entrance exam takes place over 3 weeks and covers a wide variety of subjects, including mathematics, history and geography, French, two foreign languages, and "general culture" ða mixture of sociology, philosophy, and current eventsÞ as well as the ability to debate a help creating the proprietary database, and Deborah Philippe for her research assistance. An earlier version of this article circulated as the Centre for Economic Policy Research discussion paper no. 6891. All errors remain our own. Contact the corresponding author, Evren Ors, at ors@hec.fr. topic. In our analysis, we first compare the performance differences between males and females coming from similar educational backgrounds during the written and oral exam stages of the selection process in which the candidates compete for a limited number of places that are available. 1 Then we compare the performances of the same population before and after the entrance exam during the high school finishing exam ðthe French baccalaure´atÞ and during their first-year core courses at HEC ðfor candidates admitted to the schoolÞ.</p><p>Unlike the HEC entrance exam, the baccalaure´at does not have a predetermined number of seats for the successful candidates and has drastically lower failure rates ðapproximately 15% as opposed to an 89% failure rate for the entrance examÞ. Once admitted to the school, the students face a series of academic assessments in a much less competitive environment. While HEC asks professors to follow a grading scheme based on a "curve" and suggests that the bottom 10% of the grade distribution can be given an F, less than 1% of the first-year core courses' letter grades are fails. In fact, the proportion of students failing and having to repeat their first year is approximately 1% of the 380 who are admitted to the school. These differences suggest that the HEC entrance exam, which selects the highestranked 380 candidates, is a much more competitive setting than the latter two academic evaluations. Given the structure of the HEC selection process, we specifically consider the upper tail of the performance distributions.</p><p>Our main result is that men perform better than women at the very competitive HEC admission contest, despite the fact that ðiÞ in the same cohort of candidates, the females performed significantly better than men in the "noncompetitive" national baccalaure´at exam ðsince the number of diplomas awarded is not predetermined and one candidate obtaining the diploma has no bearing on the other candidatesÞ 2 years prior to the sitting of the HEC admission exam; and ðiiÞ among the subsample of candidates admitted to the school, females appear to outperform the same males during the first year of the HEC's MSc program ðwhere grades are based on relative performances in a very loose senseÞ but only in the nonmathematicsoriented classes. <ref type="bibr" coords="3,147.74,462.45,3.00,5.44">2</ref> More precisely, using quantile regressions, we show that men perform better than women during the written exam stage at the 25th, 50th, 75th, and 90th percentiles ðbut not at the 10th percentileÞ, the observed perfor-1 As discussed further below, in order to eliminate differences in educational backgrounds as a possible driver of a gender performance gap that we observe, we focus on a sample of 5,750 science track candidates ðover three cohortsÞ, which form the largest group among the candidate pool. While there are no quotas for any type of background, approximately 250 of the 380 admitted to HEC come from a scientific background in high school. <ref type="bibr" coords="3,89.52,580.72,3.00,5.44">2</ref> The fact that we deem the baccalaure´at as noncompetitive and the first-year of HEC as less competitive does not mean that these are nonstressful events. What we claim is that the resulting pressures during the latter two exams are lower, in a relative sense, than those engendered by the HEC entrance exam. mance differences being statistically significant at the 1% level. As only roughly a quarter of the initial candidate pool is allowed to proceed to the oral exams' stage of the admission process, the men's proportion increases during the second round of the admission process. Estimates of quantile regressions for the oral exams at the 25th, 50th, and 75th percentiles suggest that females' overall performance remains lower than that of males only at the 75th percentile, a result that is statistically significant at the 10% level. Consequently, more men are admitted to HEC than women.</p><p>To examine the impact of the selection process on the performance of the same cohorts, we first estimate linear probability models for the bac-calaure´at honors using ordinary least squares ðOLSÞ. <ref type="bibr" coords="4,304.04,210.45,3.00,5.44">3</ref> We observe that the probability of obtaining honors is higher for women compared to men, the result being statistically different from zero at the 1% level, irrespective of the honors level considered. When we run OLS regressions using firstyear grade point average ðGPAÞ or letter grades and control for all the observable characteristics at our disposal, we find some evidence that women perform better than men: overall, women's GPA or course grades are higher than those of men, but only in the nonmathematics-oriented courses ðwe observe no statistically significant difference in performance when we consider all the grades or the mathematics gradesÞ. This is surprising: a priori, we would not expect to find any performance difference among a group of students who have excelled in a highly competitive elimination process and succeeded in entering HEC. Taken together, these results suggest that the higher competitive pressure in the exam that puts more emphasis on relative performance has a different impact on men than on women.</p><p>Next, we consider alternative explanations for the changes in performance that we observe for the same subjects in settings in which competitiveness differs in a relative sense. One possibility is that gender discrimination or bias by exam evaluators may be driving our results ðas in Goldin and Rouse 2000Þ. For example, while the written exam copies are graded after being rendered anonymous, we cannot rule out the possibility that some graders may be able to discern the genders thanks to the candidates' handwriting style. However, we do not believe that this or a similar discrimination during the oral exams would result in a bias that is material enough to affect our results for three reasons. First, even if some graders may be able to discern the gender of the candidate through handwriting style differences, they would need to be biased toward one gender or the other, which is not obvious given that the examiners come from both sexes ðe.g., Lavy 2008aÞ. Second, our main performance metric is a weighted average of all ðwritten or oralÞ exam grades in different subjects. For any potential gender discrimination to affect our results systematically, one or more fields would have to be graded by one or more groups of examiners with a similar bias. This is difficult to achieve given that the number of copies to be graded in the science track alone is 1,900 per year on average per subject matter. The fact that we are using weighted-average exam scores across different fields suggests that any possible bias that a few individual examiners may exhibit would be largely diluted. Finally, it is highly unlikely that HEC administration would have given us access to the data if there were any suspicions of gender bias in the admission exam: given the predominant status of the institution among French business schools, our research question is a delicate one for the general public and HEC. <ref type="bibr" coords="5,375.53,210.45,3.00,5.44">4</ref> Our results are also unlikely to be explained by a "women shying away from competition" argument: in our data set the proportion of female candidates in the initial candidate pool with a science background ð49.2%Þ is 2%-3% higher than the proportion of females graduating from high school with a science major over the same period ð46. <ref type="bibr" coords="5,307.77,270.49,85.17,10.21;5,80.96,282.46,116.45,10.21">6% in 2005, 46.2% in 2006, and 47.3% in 2007Þ.</ref> The fact that there are more females in the candidate pool than among the relevant population of high school graduates rules out stories based on a selection mechanism that men and women share in common, even though we cannot rule out, on the basis of this information, more general stories involving different selection mechanisms for men and women. <ref type="bibr" coords="5,169.29,342.44,3.00,5.44">5</ref> Given that the candidates who take the HEC entrance exam follow the same number of years of schooling, human capital differences are most likely to be driven by innate abilities as opposed to differences in backgrounds. It is possible that women's attitudes toward family and childbearing may engender differences in their investment in education ðsee, e.g., Ge 2011Þ, which may explain the lower initial proportion of female candidates ð49.16% vs. 50.84% for malesÞ in the applicant pool. However, these potential differences in attitudes are unlikely to explain differences in performance during the entrance exam or the systematic change that we observe in the bacca-laure´at or the first year of HEC.</p><p>We also explore whether gender differences in mathematics affinity may matter for our results. While we observe some statistically significant per-4 In fact, an earlier version of this article was covered in the French press ðe.g., Le Monde 2009Þ, generating a nonnegligible amount of debate about the findings. <ref type="bibr" coords="5,89.97,534.85,3.00,5.44">5</ref> Evidence suggests that genders' attitude toward competition has a cultural component: Gneezy, Leonard, and List ð2009Þ find that while men among the Maasai in Tanzania, a patriarchal society, tend to participate in competitive tasks at twice the rate of women, the reverse is observed in the matrilineal society of the Khasi in India. We do not know of any study that examines the variation in the differences that genders exhibit regarding their participation in competitive tasks for different subsamples that share the same culture. formance differences across genders involving subjects that are mathematics and nonmathematics oriented, these are not systematic enough to explain all our main findings. In certain cases we obtain similar results with the mathematics and the nonmathematics exams. For example, in quantile regressions of the written exam performance, males perform better than females at the 25th, 50th, 75th, and 90th percentiles of the data, irrespective of whether the content is mathematics or nonmathematics oriented. In other cases, we observe differences that indicate that females do worse in nonmathematics fields. For example, in quantile regressions of oral exam performance, females do worse ða result that is statistically significantÞ than males at the 75th percentile in the nonmathematics exams, while we observe no such difference at the 75th percentile of the mathematics exam. Yet again, in other instances women do better in nonmathematics-oriented subjects, for example, during the first-year courses, while they do no worse in the mathematics-oriented courses. We also note that the implicit weights given to mathematics-related fields in the three different academic evaluations that we examine do not vary systematically to disadvantage the females during the entrance exam, while giving them an edge in the other two tests. <ref type="bibr" coords="6,390.05,294.42,3.00,5.44">6</ref> We then conclude that the gender-related academic performance differences that we observe are closely linked with the differences in the competitive pressures inherent in these evaluations.</p><p>Our data set is relevant and interesting for the study of the gender differences in performances for several reasons. First, payoffs at stake are very high since the Financial Times ðFTÞ has ranked HEC's MSc in <ref type="bibr" coords="6,369.70,366.47,17.48,10.21;6,81.07,378.49,172.66,10.21">Management program first in Europe in 2005</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="6,253.73,378.49,25.40,10.21" target="#b17">, 2006</ref>, the three years in our sample. 7 For these three years the average annual salary of HEC MSc alumni 3 years after graduation is approximately US$13,000 ðinternational purchasing power parity adjusted as reported by the FTÞ higher than that of the closest follower in France. This amount corresponds to 24.5% of the average salary ð$53,000 over 2005-7Þ of the alumni of the business school that is typically ranked the second in France ðESSECÞ. The salary spread increases to almost $24,000 between HEC and the last-ranked French business school in the FT survey during 2005-7 ðwhich corresponds to 57% of the average salary for alumni of the least-well-ranked French school in the FT classificationÞ. 8 Even in 2011, when HEC was ranked fourth in the FT rankings for MSc in Management, the average starting salary of its graduates was more than $8,600 higher than that of the graduates of the first-ranked business school in France ðEcole Supérieur de Commerce de Paris ½ESCPÞ in that year, a difference that equals 13% of the average salary of the latter school's alumni. Not only do HEC alumni perform very well early in their career ðwhich they typically start at the age of 24Þ, they also do well in the long run: among the 32 French firms ranked in the FT Global 500 in 2007, which includes the world's 500 largest companies by market value, 22% have a chief executive officer who graduated from HEC. The school's alumni also include seven French government ministers. In a different vein, Pascal Lamy and Dominique Strauss-Kahn, two HEC alumni, are, respectively, the director of the World Trade Organization and the ex-managing director of the International Monetary Fund. These examples illustrate short-and longterm rewards, and hence the incentives, of being admitted to the school.</p><p>Second, a priori, we should not observe any difference in performance across genders in this pool of candidates given that we examine highly competitive individuals compared to their age group in the general French population since ðiÞ they are among the very best-performing French high school seniors as measured by the honors that they obtain in the bacca-laure´at, 9 ðiiÞ they have chosen to apply to and have been admitted to selective preparatory schools that train students during 2 years for business school entrance exams, and ðiiiÞ they self-select to sit for the toughest of such exams despite the fact that they are guaranteed admission to a French university in any year following their high school graduation. As a result, the research question that we examine is not trivial. If anything, the competitive nature of the group of students that we examine should make it more difficult for us to find any differences in performance across genders.</p><p>Third, we are able to observe the performance of this motivated group of individuals in academic evaluations that exhibit large differences in their conditions for success. One particularity of the setups that we examine is that the success at the HEC entrance exam is based on relative performance in a strict sense for a given year ðonly the top 380 performers are admittedÞ. In contrast, in the baccalaure´at exam, there is no predetermined number of high school diplomas to be granted. Students who obtain an average grade of 10 or higher out of 20 get their diploma. For these reasons we consider the baccalaure´at to be a noncompetitive setting. Competition is also very mild in the HEC first-year core course phase. The school follows the European Credit Transfer System ðECTSÞ standard for grading distributions, which suggests that 10% of the class be given an F. 10 In our sample the proportion of failing grades is less than 7.5% of the distribution if one were to consider all grades below a D and less than 1% if one considers only letter grade F ðafter taking a makeup examÞ. In fact, HEC requires that students validate 50 ECTS credit hours out of the 60 needed for the year. By this criterion, the number of students failing their first year and repeating it the next year is approximately 1% of the entering class: of the 2005, 2006, and 2007 entering classes, three, three, and four students, respectively, repeated part or all of their first year. As a result, the intensity of the competition for 380 spots out of 3,400 during the entrance exam is drastically higher than that for the first-year HEC courses but also much higher than that for the baccalaure´at exam.</p><p>Since the baccalaure´at and the HEC first-year exams' difficulty and their evaluations are most likely to change over time, we do not consider them as being based on fixed standards that remain constant over time ðeven when the nominal threshold for a pass may remain constant, as in the case of the baccalaure´atÞ. What matters for our purpose is the fact that these two sets of exams be relatively less competitive than the HEC entrance exam.</p><p>Finally, our sample allows us to rule out differences of earlier orientation in education during high school as possible drivers of the gender performance gap. For that purpose, we focus on science majors, the largest cohort in the HEC entrance exam, and control for the potential differences among the submajors ði.e., mathematics, physics and chemistry, and life sciencesÞ that they chose in the last year of high school. Not only do we test for differences in the gender composition of different science submajors, but we also explicitly control for them in a multivariate analysis to account for potential differences in mathematics affinity across genders.</p><p>The article is organized as follows. Section II reviews the related literature. Section III provides an overview of the French higher education system and explains in detail the two-stage HEC admission tournament. Sections IV and V present the data set and the results, respectively. Section VI provides a discussion, and Section VII presents conclusions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>II. Related Literature</head><p>Even though the setup we examine is a not direct real-life counterpart to the experimental studies of <ref type="bibr" coords="8,197.40,500.50,86.17,10.21">Gneezy et al. ð2003Þ</ref> and Niederle and Vestersystem is very similar to the one used in US universities: course letter grades range from an A for the best-performing students in a class to an F for those who fail the class, with the addition of an E, which is a passing grade that is worse than a D. The ECTS system was introduced in 1999 as part of the so-called Bologna Process that seeks to harmonize educational standards within the European Higher Education Area with a view to facilitate educational transfers across countries ðhttp://ec .europa.eu/education/lifelong-learning-policy/doc48 _ en.htmÞ. lund ð2007Þ, our results expand the literature on performance differences across genders and complement their results. <ref type="bibr" coords="9,271.96,102.46,55.88,10.21">Gneezy et al.</ref> observe that as the competitiveness of the environment increases, men's performance increases while that of women does not. Furthermore, they find that the performance of women is significantly higher in single-sex tournaments than in noncompetitive treatments, suggesting that the competitive environment in which women operate can affect their performance. In the experiments run by Niederle and Vesterlund, participants are asked to solve tasks in a noncompetitive environment and then in a competitive tournament environment. In a second step, participants are asked to select in which of the two environments they want to operate: while 73% of the men choose to enter the competitive tournament, only 35% of the women decide to do so.</p><p>Our work is also closely related to a growing body of papers on performance gender gap using real-life data with conflicting results. Paserman ð2010Þ finds no difference in forced errors across genders during critical points of grand-slam tennis tournament matches. His results suggest that, in the context of same-sex tournaments, women do no worse than men when competitive pressure increases. Lavy ð2008bÞ examines the effects of a rankorder tournament among mathematics and language teachers with important cash prizes that are based on the performances of their students. He finds no gender-based difference among teachers in terms of performance rank, rate of winning, or prize won. Moreover, the gender composition of the pool of competitor-teachers in the same school does not appear to matter, even though women appear to be more pessimistic about teaching outcomes and more realistic about their chances of winning a prize. In a similar vein, Delfgaauw et al. ð2009Þ introduce a performance competition among the stores of a Dutch retail chain, but in contrast to Lavy ð2008bÞ, they find a positive and statistically significant effect on sales-based performance when the manager and most of the employees have the same gender, irrespective of whether a cash prize was proposed or not.</p><p>Our work contributes to this line of literature and is closely related to the recent article by Jurajda and Munich ð2011Þ, who study performance differences across genders during the entrance exams for Czech universities. They find that while women perform as well as men in entrance exams of lower-ranked universities, their probability of being admitted to top universities is lower than that of men with similar abilities ðas measured by their score in a national high school graduation examÞ.</p><p>Our work is different from that of Jurajda and Munich ð2011Þ in several ways. First, whereas Jurajda and Munich can observe each candidate's multiple university applications, we observe the same candidates in three different exam settings: in the noncompetitive baccalaure´at exam, during the highly competitive HEC entrance exam, and during the somewhat competitive first year of their studies once admitted. Thus, we can observe whether the gender performance gap observed during the entrance exam exists prior to and after this contest, in less competitive environments. Second, the entrance exam that we focus on proceeds in two steps, one written and one oral, as opposed to a single set of written evaluations in Jurajda and Munich's study. As a result, we can test for a gender performance gap in written versus oral settings. Third, while our data are limited to a single school's entrance exam, as opposed to many universities' admission exams, the admission procedure that we examine is richer in that it examines students over a larger set of subject matters ðe.g., mathematics, history and geography, languages, and "general culture" during the entrance exam but also accounting, economics, finance, etc. during the first yearÞ rather than just mathematics and language skills as in Jurajda and Munich's study. Hence, we are able to examine whether mathematics affinity is the driver of the gender difference in performance. As such, our findings extend and complement those of Jurajda and Munich.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>III. The French Higher Education System and the HEC Admission Exam</head><p>This section presents an overview of the French higher education system so as to provide a better understanding of the competitive pressure and the economic incentives that the subjects we study face during the different academic evaluation tests that we examine.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. A Two-Tiered Higher Education System</head><p>At present, higher education in France is dispensed through 81 public universities and 202 grandes e´coles. The history of the current system can be traced back to the earlier years of the thirteenth century, when the three oldest French universities ðParis, Toulouse, and MontpellierÞ were created. The first institution of higher learning that was not affiliated with a university, le Collège Royal de Paris ðnow called le Collège de FranceÞ, was created in 1530, followed by the first military oceanography and artillery schools in the seventeenth century. During the eighteenth century, technological advances increased the demand for engineers among army corps officers and led to the creation of other military engineering schools by the royal power. 11 Following the French Revolution, similar institutions continued to be created ðincluding Ecole Polytechnique, the most prestigious of French engineering schoolsÞ, with the appearance of nonmilitary independent schools such as the Ecole Normale ðto train secondary school teachers after the expulsion of Jesuits who fulfilled that roleÞ and the transformation of law and medicine faculties of universities into independent law and medi-cal schools ðthese would be subsequently reattached to universitiesÞ. These independent institutions of higher learning outside the university system, which were typically attached to a military corps or to a government ministry, will eventually become what is known as the grandes e´coles system. In the nineteenth century, a second wave of occupational schools dedicated to the teaching of business and management began to be created, including the HEC, by the Chamber of Commerce and Industry of Paris ðCCIPÞ in 1881. <ref type="bibr" coords="11,103.24,174.45,6.00,5.44">12</ref> The university-grande e´cole duality is still very much present in French higher education and boils down to three major differences among these institutions. First, the former are not typically allowed to select students who are legally guaranteed a spot in one of the three universities of their choice in the acade´mie of their high school upon graduation, irrespective of their academic level. <ref type="bibr" coords="11,182.44,246.45,6.00,5.44">13</ref> In contrast, starting as early as the eighteenth century, admission to grande e´cole programs involves an entrance exam whose difficulty and selectiveness are very tightly associated with the quality and ranking of the school. Differences in the admission procedures and selection criteria are reflected in the number of students enrolled in the universities and the grandes e´coles: during the period 2005-7 ðyears in our sam-pleÞ, approximately 1.4 million students were enrolled in universities ðall fields and years combinedÞ compared to approximately 160,000 in all types of grandes e´coles put together ðRERS 2007Þ. This general difference in selectivity is further exacerbated by the competition among the highest-ranked grandes e´coles that select the very best candidates through separate entrance exams. The difficulty of getting into one of the top-ranked schools is closely related with job market outcomes. It is not too far-fetched to state that typically a French employer, the country's establishment, and even the French public at large would consider the last-ranked candidate entering the firstranked grande e´cole in a given field to be a better student than the first-ranked student entering the second-ranked school. In fact, when offered admission from a number of schools, few of those admitted to the first-ranked school would go to a second-or lower-ranked school. In the case of HEC, out of 381 12 HEC is the eighth French business school to be created, the first one being another school created by the CCIP, the ESCP. Almost all French business schools are affiliated with, and partially financed by, a chamber of commerce. The latter receives a tax, called taxe d'apprentissage, which businesses headquartered in its geographical area are required to pay. Nevertheless, French business schools require a tuition that many prestigious engineering grandes e´coles do not thanks to their historic affiliation with a ministry of the French state. <ref type="bibr" coords="11,89.97,554.86,6.00,5.44">13</ref> The French national education system is split into 26 regional units called acad-e´mies that cover administrative aspects of primary, secondary, and higher education. These academies typically cover a re´gion, which is a geographic administrative unit of the French state, though some large metropolitan areas, such as the greater Paris region ðnamely, Ile de FranceÞ, are split into more than one academy. admitted in <ref type="bibr" coords="12,130.30,90.49,262.74,10.21">2005 and 380 in 2006 and 2007, only 18, 15, and 11, respectively,</ref> chose to go to another school. 14 Second, whereas entry at a university takes place right after high school, candidates to grande e´coles follow subject-specific preparatory programs for 2 years, which prepare them for the competitive entrance exams. These 2-year prep schools ðclasses pre´paratoires, or simply pre´pa in FrenchÞ follow curricula defined at the national level and may be thought of as being the equivalent of freshman and sophomore years in a US college. Even though these schools do not confer diplomas, students who drop out of them after the first year or fail to enter a grande e´cole of their choice can be awarded ECTS credit hours that they can use toward a university degree's credit hour requirements. <ref type="bibr" coords="12,214.13,222.42,6.00,5.44">15</ref> The prep schools are typically associated with public or private high schools but are not organically linked with the grandes e´coles. <ref type="bibr" coords="12,141.79,246.45,6.00,5.44">16</ref> Admission to one of the 406 existing prep schools also follows a very selective process. During their last year of high school, students wishing to enter a prep school of their choice fill out application forms ðmainly providing grades obtained in their last 2 years of high schoolÞ. In contrast to the university system, students can be rejected from all the prep schools that they apply to. In fact, prep schools offer different programs given the type of grande e´cole targeted ði.e., engineering or businessÞ and are ranked by field ði.e., mathematics, science, economics, or literatureÞ, with the selectivity being especially stringent at the very best institutions. Importantly for us, admission decisions to business prep schools, though conditional on successfully obtaining the high school diploma, are typically made public before the baccalaure´at exam takes place. In other words, business prep school programs do not select students on the basis of their baccalaure´at exam performances. For example, a top-ranked business prep school pro- <ref type="bibr" coords="12,89.97,445.11,6.00,5.44">14</ref> The students who chose not to attend HEC typically enrolled in Ecole Normale Supérieur, a research-oriented grande e´cole that prepares for a PhD in economics, humanities, and sciences. Few students chose a lower-ranked business school over HEC. The school does not offer additional admissions to replace the students who chose not to enroll. <ref type="bibr" coords="12,89.97,495.28,6.00,5.44">15</ref> A student can transfer up to 60 ð120Þ ECTS credit hours toward her or his university degree upon successful completion of the first year ðsecond yearÞ of prep school. <ref type="bibr" coords="12,89.97,515.29,6.00,5.44">16</ref> As of 2007 there were approximately 1,550 public and 1,070 private high schools in France. The latter group is further subdivided into two. The first group, called sous-contrat avec l'e´tat ði.e., under contract with the stateÞ, includes institutions that follow the French national curriculum, lead to a French baccalaure´at, receive aid from the state that appoints some of its teachers, and charge anywhere between €500 and €4,500 per year for tuition. The overwhelming majority of these institutions are denominational ðtypically CatholicÞ schools. The second group comprises private high schools that follow other curricula ðAmerican, English, or German, e.g.Þ, lead to international diplomas ðsuch as American or Swiss international baccalaureate or UK A-levelsÞ, do not receive any state aid, and charge much higher amounts for tuition ðanywhere between €10,000 and over €25,000 per yearÞ. gram that rejects a candidate on the basis of high school grades will not typically revisit its decision even if the student in question eventually graduates at the baccalaure´at with honors ðmore information on the equivalence of French high school honors is provided belowÞ. 17 This suggests another reason why the baccalaure´at can be seen as a noncompetitive exam for students admitted to the prep schools: superior performance during the high school finishing exam has no bearing on the prep school's admission decision, which the student already knows by the time of the baccalaure´at exam. Moreover, prep schools are highly competitive environments, typically posting the rankings of their students within a class after exams and eventually asking poorly performing ones to leave ðe.g., Le Monde 2012Þ.</p><p>Third, while students graduating from high school are guaranteed a spot in one of the three universities in the acade´mie of their high school, irrespective of their academic performance as long as they obtain their high school diploma, they have to take different competitive entrance exams for different grandes e´coles. The fact that few schools pool their entrance exams limits the number of grandes e´coles a student can apply to. 18 Candidates have to optimize their time and efforts over a large number of entrance exams, a fact that contributes to the selectiveness of the grande e´cole system.</p><p>Fourth, upon graduation, job market prospects are drastically different for grande e´cole and university graduates. The nonselectivity of the university admission process combined with ðiÞ the increasing proportion of 18-year-olds in the general population obtaining a baccalaure´at over the decades and ðiiÞ a mismatch between the labor market demand and the number of students graduating in various fields implies that French universities often confer diplomas with little value in the job market ðwith few notable exceptions, such as medicineÞ. For example, in 2006, French universities had approximately 65,000 psychology students ðone-fourth of the European students in the fieldÞ and roughly 45,000 "sports science" students ðEconomist 2006Þ. <ref type="bibr" coords="13,155.57,450.44,5.83,5.44">19</ref> In contrast, grandes e´coles provide engineering or business education with much better employment opportunities. In fact, the salary gap between HEC and other business school graduates that we noted in the introduction is even larger with respect to university graduates. During the last year of their studies, HEC students typically get multiple job offers 17 High school students can typically apply to up to three universities and up to 12 prep schools before taking their baccalaure´at exam. Many prep schools shortlist candidates and may accept students after the baccalaure´at exam if the students offered admission choose to attend another prep school and free up space.</p><p>18 HEC pools its written exams with ESCP, traditionally the third-best-ranked business grande e´cole in France, even though each school conducts its own set of oral exams. Both schools are affiliated with the CCIP. <ref type="bibr" coords="13,90.43,606.23,6.00,5.44">19</ref> Such large numbers can be explained, in part, by the fact that France's 81 universities are public, requiring fees of only less than a few hundred euros per year. In before they obtain their diplomas, with a nonnegligible number of offers being for positions in other countries, such as the United Kingdom. A diploma from a top-ranked grande e´cole also gives access to a large and established alumni network within and outside of France. As such, getting admission into a grande e´cole drastically changes career prospects for the candidates, all the more so if the candidate is admitted to the best school in its field. This context explains the high level of pressure and competition that is built into the entrance exam of a top-ranked grande e´cole such as HEC.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. HEC Admission Process</head><p>The HEC MSc in Management is the direct descendant of the program created 110 years ago. Since 1920, admission takes place through a competitive exam. Historically an all-male establishment, in 1973 the school started to admit women, whose proportion rose from approximately 30% in 1985 to just below 50% in 2007. The competitive entrance exam is organized by la Direction des Admissions et Concours ðthe Admissions and Entrance Exam Administration Center ½AEEACÞ, which is not directly affiliated with HEC, and proceeds in two steps. First, all applicants ðon average 3,400 per year during the period 2005-7Þ, whom we will refer to as candidates, have to take seven written exams. In a second stage, the highest-ranked 700 or so, whom we will refer to as admissibles, will be allowed to take a series of oral exams. On the basis of the weighted sum of all grades obtained at the written and the oral exam stages, HEC will admit the highest-ranked 380, whom we will refer to as the admitted. The school does not set any quotas per gender, educational background, nationality, or socioeconomic class. Admission is solely based on the final ranking of the candidate among all other candidates using the weighted sum of written and oral exam scores. The weights used in this evaluation differ depending on the educational background of the candidate. There are four different educational backgrounds or tracks: science ðapproximately 56% of the candidate poolÞ, economics ð30%Þ, literature ð13%Þ, and technology ð1%Þ. 20 It should be noted that the rankings are done across the board for these four tracks ði.e., a literature candidate who has a better total weighted sum would be placed higher than a science candidate with a lower scoreÞ. During the selection process, the written exams are based on essay-type questions or involve solving mathematical problems but do not include multiple-choice questions. The oral exams typically contrast, even though many of the best engineering grandes e´coles are public and tuition free, business grandes e´coles are attached to regional chambers of commerce and typically require tuition, which may be up to €12,000 per year ðas in the case of HECÞ. That said, it is easy for students admitted to HEC to obtain bank loans to finance their studies, and the school provides need-based scholarships. <ref type="bibr" coords="14,89.97,594.21,6.00,5.44">20</ref> The last group has a baccalaure´at from a technological high school. France has three types of high schools and baccalaure´ats, a degree obtained by roughly two-thirds of 18-year-olds inthecountry:ðiÞ generalist ðintroduced in 1808Þ, ðiiÞ tech- <ref type="bibr" coords="14,81.07,68.23,13.50,9.19">456</ref> Ors et al.</p><p>involve 15-30 minutes of testing on a question or problem that is drawn randomly from a question bank. Our study focuses on the largest group of candidates: those with a science major in high school, who have to specialize in a submajor during the last year of high school in mathematics, physics and chemistry, or life and earth sciences ði.e., biology and geologyÞ. We rely on the sample of students with the same science background in order to reduce the possibility that the gender gap we observe is due to differences in backgrounds or selfselection of females into nonscience fields. 21 This group typically attends science-oriented prep schools that prepare students for entrance exams of grandes e´coles in management. <ref type="bibr" coords="15,212.32,210.45,6.00,5.44">22</ref> Even though attending a prep school is not a prerequisite for taking the grande e´cole entrance exam, 93.96% of the candidates in our sample attend these institutions.</p><p>In the first stage of the entrance exam, all candidates, irrespective of their track, are evaluated on their expression skills in French as well as two foreign languages ðone of which is typically EnglishÞ. Candidates also sit for track-specific exams depending on their educational background. The candidates with a science background take two written exams in mathematics, one in history and geography, and one in general culture. <ref type="table" coords="15,322.98,306.49,31.19,10.21" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> provides the complete list of different written and oral exams for the science track. For each exam, students receive a mark, ranging between zero and 20, in line with the French primary and secondary education grading scheme. <ref type="bibr" coords="15,367.43,342.44,6.00,5.44">23</ref> The weights indicated in table 1 are used in the calculation of the weighted sum 22 Science-oriented prep schools follow different curricula dependent on whether they prepare students for management or engineering grandes e´coles.</p><p>23 While there is no official correspondence between the French grading system out of 20 and the American system based on letter grades, the Fulbright Commission in France suggests the following equivalence scheme ðfor eleventh and twelfth gradesÞ: 18-20 A1, 16-17 A, 13-15 A2, 12 B1, 11 B, 10 B2, 9 C1, 8 C, 7 C2, 6 D1, 5D, 4 D2, and 3 and below F ðhttp://www.fulbright-france.org/docs/2010170242 _ Balzactoolkitfrench.pdf, 12Þ. A French student needs an average of 10/20 to validate an academic year or the baccalaure´at. <ref type="bibr" coords="15,89.97,484.68,6.00,5.44">21</ref> We would have had a much more heterogeneous sample if we had analyzed the full sample of all candidates: to make the point, among high school students who graduated in 2005 with a generalist baccalaure´at, 46.6% of science majors were females, whereas the same proportion was 63.5% for economics and social science majors and 81.6% for literature majors in high school.</p><p>nological ðintroduced in 1964Þ, and ðiiiÞ vocational ðintroduced in 1985Þ. The generalist baccalaure´at, which 99% of HEC candidates possess, is the most soughtafter degree, obtained by 54% of French high school seniors. Middle school students who are unable to perform adequately in the generalist institutions are directed toward technological or vocational high schools. Technological high schools educate students in the fields of engineering and management with a view toward training technicians and clerical staff ðsuch as accountantsÞ who will eventually pursue a shorter higher education program without necessarily attending a university or a grande e´cole. Vocational high school students train to become artisans or skilled workers in various industries. of grades, which the AEEAC uses to rank the candidates. We calculate an equivalent weighted-average score ðout of 20Þ that we use as the performance metric. Even though we limit ourselves to science track students, the diversity of subjects on which these candidates are evaluated still allows us to test whether any performance difference that we observe may be driven by differences in mathematics affinity across genders. This is important because for the science track candidates, mathematics accounts for 36.67% of written exam weights and 25% of oral exam weights. In fact, the structure of the entrance examination resembles an iterated elimination tournament in which ð1Þ less than 25% of the approximately 3,400 candidates per year become admissibles and ð2Þ approximately 55% of the admissibles ðwhich corresponds to 11% of candidatesÞ are eventually admitted to the school.</p><p>Once admitted to HEC, students spend 3 years on campus and take an interim year to do a series of internships. Their first year ends the bachelor cycle initiated in prep school, whereas their last 2 years correspond to the MSc in Management degree. <ref type="bibr" coords="16,202.62,474.42,6.00,5.44">24</ref> Except for a few elective courses, the bulk of the first year consists of the same core courses for all the admitted, which allows us to examine whether the differences observed during the entrance exam persist in the first year of HEC studies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C. The Baccalauréat Exam</head><p>The baccalaure´at exam, first introduced in 1808 by Napoléon, is the product of a highly centralized system run by the French Ministry of Na- <ref type="bibr" coords="16,89.97,588.48,6.00,5.44">24</ref> The last year is dedicated to a 1-year specialization in one area of management ðaccounting, finance, strategy, marketing, international business, etc.Þ. It should be noted that no diploma or certificate is conferred at the end of the first year of HEC when the bachelor cycle is completed. tional Education. It differs in many aspects from the US high school diploma, which is the product of a decentralized system. The baccalaure´at degree is obtained following a series of national written tests ðand oral tests for foreign languagesÞ typically spread over 5 days. The composition of the exams in terms of subject matters ðFrench literature, mathematics, physics, chemistry, life sciences ½biology and geology, philosophy, and foreign lan-guagesÞ and the different weights given to these fields vary according to the major chosen at the end of seconde ðthe equivalent of tenth grade in the United StatesÞ and the submajor chosen at the end of premie`re ðthe eleventh gradeÞ. The interaction of gender and acquaintance cannot affect the results we observe for the baccalaure´at. Grading of this exam is anonymous: teachers coming from other and typically nonneighborhood high schools grade blinded-exam papers. <ref type="bibr" coords="17,172.35,246.45,6.00,5.44">25</ref> The evaluation of the exam copies is based on the answer key and grading scheme provided by the Ministry of National Education. There is no "curve" involved either for individual topics or for the baccalaure´at as a whole: only students who obtain a weighted average of 10 out 20 obtain their diploma.</p><p>The baccalaure´at exam is inherently different from the HEC entrance exam for two reasons. First, in contrast to the HEC admission process, which is clearly a contest for a fixed number of spots, the baccalaure´at is in essence a pass-or-fail type of exam with three levels of graduation honors beyond a simple "pass." The 300,000-325,000 high school students who are about to take the general baccalaure´at exam each year know that any student who manages to obtain a weighted-average baccalaure´at score ðwith weights that are predetermined for each of the submajorsÞ of 10 out of 20 will necessarily obtain his or her diploma. In other words, students taking the baccalaure´at do not directly compete against each other: the success of a candidate does not imply the failure of another one. Moreover, instead of a curve, a standardized grading scheme is applied to the same set of questions for all the high school seniors in a given track. In that sense the bac-calaure´at provides a fixed standard for a given year. Finally, as already mentioned, for high school students who have been admitted to a prep school ð93.96% of candidates in our sampleÞ, since admission is known before the baccalaure´at they need only a pass in this exam. Conversely, when they sit for the HEC entrance exam, candidates know that there will be only 380 admitted students, irrespective of the number of candidates.</p><p>Second, the success rates at the two exams are clearly of very different magnitudes. The success rates in the 2003, 2004, and 2005 general bacca-laure´at ðwhich correspond to the 2005, 2006, and 2007 candidate cohorts in our sample, respectivelyÞ were 83.7%, 82.7%, and 84.3%, respectively, for all majors combined and 84.8%, 83.0%, and 84.8%, respectively, for the science majors. As noted earlier, the proportion of students successfully validating their first year at HEC is approximately 99%. These rates are very different from the 11% success rate at the HEC entrance exam. In our opinion, these differences render the entrance exam a very competitive and stressful setting, whereas the baccalaure´at is in fact a noncompetitive exam that is relatively less stressful.</p><p>One could argue that the possibility for prep school students to be able to transfer to a university degree program without losing a year ðprovided that the prep school year is successfully completedÞ reduces the pressures involved in the HEC entrance exam. However, it should also be noted that the large salary gaps noted earlier between HEC and other business schools, let alone universities, create important economic incentives that increase the stakes for the HEC entrance exam.</p><p>While we cannot observe baccalaure´at exam grades, our data set includes honors obtained during the high school finishing exam. Beyond providing a useful control for the ability of the candidate in the multivariate analysis of the HEC entrance exam and during the first-year courses at HEC, we use the baccalaure´at performance to test whether, for the same cohort of students, the gender gap existed in a noncompetitive, ðrel-ativelyÞ less stressful exam 2 years prior to the competitive entrance exam ðat least for our set of candidates, who are among the best high school students in their yearÞ.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D. First-Year Core Courses at HEC</head><p>We also look at the performance of students admitted in 2005 and 2006 in their core courses in the first year of HEC when they take 11 compulsory classes that account for 44 ð73.33%Þ of the 60 ECTS credits needed for the academic year: 26 accounting, economics, finance, marketing, law, theory of organizations, supply chain, statistics, quantitative methods, modeling with Excel, and English as a first foreign language. The first seven of these courses are worth 5 ECTS credits, statistics and quantitative methods 2.5 ECTS credits, and the last two courses 2 ECTS credits. There are also a number of elective courses worth 16 ECTS points. Since students differ in their elective course choices, we do not include the nonmandatory courses in our analysis in order to be able to have a common performance metric.</p><p>In contrast to the entrance exam or the baccalaure´at, exam copies are not anonymously graded during the first-year courses at HEC. One could argue that an interaction between gender and personal acquaintance could theoretically play a role in our empirical analysis of the first-year performance. However, we do not believe that this is a serious concern for two reasons. First, when performance is measured by the first-year ðcore courseÞ GPA, we note that ðiÞ there are 78 professors teaching the 11 core courses, ðiiÞ no professor teaches all the sections of a given class in a given year, and ðiiiÞ the GPA is a weighted average of 11 courses that would largely dilute any potential bias. Second, when using the individual letter grades as the performance metric, we include year, course, and professor indicator variables in our specifications to account for differences in average grades across years, courses, and professors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IV. Data and Descriptive Statistics</head><p>The data set used in the analysis covers 5,743 students who applied to the HEC MSc in <ref type="bibr" coords="19,141.79,260.46,128.27,10.21">Management program in 2005</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="19,277.91,260.46,18.00,10.21">Management program in , 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="19,322.76,260.46,20.00,10.21">Management program in , and 2007</ref> to take the science track of the admission exam. As part of the application process the candidates have to provide to the AEEAC official documents that attest to their identity, gender, age, nationality, and the name of the prep school they attended. Since better-ranked prep schools are more selective and since the training received by students for 2 years may influence their performance in the entrance exam, we use prep school indicator variables ði.e., fixed effectsÞ to control for the quality of the scientific prep schools or, alternatively, the rankings of prep schools that are published in the French press. The candidates also have to provide a copy of their baccalaure´at diploma that explicitly states the high school major, submajor, as well as any honors ðbut not the average gradeÞ the student may have received during the high school graduation exam. The proprietary data set made available to us by AEEAC contains all the entrance exam marks ðgiven out of 20Þ at all the written exams for all the candidates, all the marks at the oral exams for all the admissibles, and an indicator variable for the admitted. During the written ðoralÞ exam stage, the examiners do not have access to the candidates' baccalaure´at ðand writtenÞ exam grades or honors. <ref type="table" coords="19,90.93,476.46,32.16,10.21">Table 2</ref> provides descriptive statistics at the different stages of the admission process for the science track candidates, admissibles, and admitted. In a first series of tests, we examine the evolution of the fraction of females through the stages of the admission exam using two-tailed binomial tests for the equality of the observed ði.e., estimatedÞ proportions ðfor which, see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" coords="19,149.95,536.50,24.56,10.21">Siegel</ref>  In the remainder of the table the equality of the means for the variables baccalaure´at honors, science prep school rank, and non-French nationals is tested using a two-tailed t-test that allows for unequal variances ðt-statistics are provided in bracesÞ. Test-statistic p-values are provided in brackets and sample sizes in parentheses.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="20,408.25,572.02,22.17,34.65">* p &lt; .10. ** p &lt; .05. *** p &lt; .01.</formula><p>We cannot reject H 1 0 for the candidates, of which 49.16% are female. 27 In contrast, we reject H 1 0 for the admissibles ð46.32%Þ and the admitted ð45.92%Þ at the 1% and 5% levels, respectively. Second, we test the null hypothesis ðH 2 0 Þ that the fractions of males and females are equal at a given stage of the admission exam. There are slightly fewer female candidates ð49.16Þ than male ones ð50.84Þ, the difference being statistically significant at the 10 level. This gender gap increases among the admissibles, where the females constitute 46.32 of the candidates retained for the oral exam compared to 53.68 for males, a difference that is statistically significant at the 1% level. This discrepancy in the gender composition persists among the admitted, of which 45.92% are female, whereas males constitute 54.08%, with H 2 0 being rejected at the 1% level. Third, we test the null hypothesis ðH 3 0 Þ that the observed fraction of females among the candidates ð49.16%Þ is equal to that among the admissibles ð46.32%Þ: H 3 0 is rejected at the 10% level. Fourth, we cannot reject the null ðH 4 0 Þ that there is no difference in the estimated proportions of females among the admissibles ð46.32%Þ versus the admitted ð45.92%Þ. Finally, we observe that the null hypothesis ðH 5 0 Þ of the equality of the observed fraction of females between the admitted ð45.92%Þ and the candidates ð49.16%Þ is rejected at the 10% level, in line with the rejection of H 3 0 and the nonrejection of H 4 0 . These binomial tests of the equality of estimated proportions suggest that the proportion of females decreases following the written stage and stays roughly constant during the oral stage.</p><p>In table 2, in a second series of tests, we examine the gender differences in honors obtained at the baccalaure´at exam for the candidates, the admissibles, and the admitted. <ref type="bibr" coords="21,182.38,390.45,6.00,5.44">28</ref> There are three types of honors in the baccalau-re´at, with grades between 10 and 12 ðout of 20Þ corresponding to passable ði.e., a simple pass with no distinctionsÞ, grades between 12 and 14 to assez bien ðthe equivalent of cum laudeÞ, grades between 14 and 16 to bien ðthe equivalent of magna cum laudeÞ, and grades above 16 to tre`s bien ðthe equivalent of summa cum laudeÞ. We code the baccalaure´at honors variable as 1, 2, 3, or 4 when the baccalaure´at has been successfully obtained with a simple pass or with honors that are the equivalent of cum laude, magna cum laude, or summa cum laude, respectively. On average, women perform much better than men at the baccalaure´at exam. Female candidates' bacca- laure´at honors average is 2.98 out of 4, whereas the men's average is 2.69, and the 0.29 difference between the two groups is statistically significant at the 1% level in a two-tailed t-test. Moreover, the same observation is made when examining the baccalaure´at performance differences for the admissibles and the admitted. Among the admissibles, females' average baccalaure´at honors of 3.43 is 0.30 points higher than that of males, whereas among the admitted, the females' average baccalaure´at honors of 3.58 is 0.30 points higher than that of males. In both cases, the difference is statistically significant at the 1% level in two-tailed t-tests.</p><p>In the next section in table 2 we check whether the results for the bac-calaure´at honors still hold if we consider separately the different submajors ðmathematics, physics and chemistry, or life sciencesÞ that science majors can specialize in as seniors in high school. We observe that for different science submajors, females' baccalaure´at honors is always statistically higher than that of males for candidates, admissibles, and admitted categories ðsee under baccalaure´at honors in table 2Þ. The only exception is the group of admitted physics and chemistry submajors, where the females' higher honors average ð3.51/4.00Þ is not statistically different from that of males ð3.39/ 4.00Þ. <ref type="bibr" coords="22,104.43,306.44,6.00,5.44">29</ref> Overall, these results indicate that female candidates, admissibles, and admitted do significantly better in the French high school finishing exam than their respective male counterparts. We reexamine this discrepancy in a multivariate setting below in Section V.B.</p><p>We also compare the average baccalaure´at honors for candidates for the HEC entrance exam with the one that we calculated for the population of science majors taking the high school finishing exam 2 years prior to our sample cohort-years. Unsurprisingly, HEC candidates are much more successful than the general population of students taking the regular baccalau-re´at exam ði.e., excluding students taking technology or vocational bacca-laure´at examsÞ. <ref type="bibr" coords="22,229.86,426.46,17.54,10.21">For , and 2005</ref>, the years in which the 2005, 2006, and 2007 cohorts in our sample took the scientific versions of the high school finishing exam, the females' average baccalaure´at honor was 1.75 out of 4 ðcompared to 2.98 in our sampleÞ, whereas that of males was 1.64 ðcompared to 2.69 in our sampleÞ. It should be noted that even the candidates who are eliminated after the first-round ðwrittenÞ exams have much higher bacca-laure´at performance: for this group the baccalaure´at honors average is 2.84 for females and 2.55 for males. These statistics suggest that the benchmark group in the HEC entrance exam has much higher academic abilities than the general population of students obtaining the baccalaure´at. 30</p><p>In the second to last row in table 2, we look at prep school rankings and any differences that may exist in this dimension across genders at various stages of the entrance contest. There are 236 institutions in our initial sample that offered a business grande e´cole prep school program, all types of tracks ðscience, economics, and literatureÞ combined. Of these, 91 that provided a science track prep school were ranked ðLa Lettre de L'Etudiant 2006Þ. <ref type="bibr" coords="23,107.32,162.44,6.00,5.44">31</ref> We coded the ranked prep schools in decreasing order; that is, the top-ranked institution is coded 1 and the last-ranked is coded 91. Out of 5,743 candidates in our data set, 5,396 ð93.96%Þ had attended one of these 91 ranked institutions. The ranking variable was coded 92 for the 219 candidates attending one of the 27 nonranked science track prep schools and as 93 for the 128 candidates for whom no prep school name is provided. The average prep school ranking for the male candidates is 27.62 compared to 24.75 for females, the difference being statistically significant at the 1% level in a two-tailed t-statistic. In other words, female candidates attend better-ranked prep schools than males, on average. If anything, this almost three-position higher rank potentially gives an advantage to females given the fact that candidates coming from a top 20 prep school are more successful in entering HEC: 49.26% of the candidates attended a top 20 prep school, compared to 78.59% of the admissibles and 86.28% of the admitted. In table 2, the higher average prep school ranking of females persists among admissibles ð12.93 for females vs. 14.21 for malesÞ and the admitted ð10.36 for females vs. 11.53 for malesÞ, but the observed difference is only marginally statistically significant for the admissibles ðat the 10% levelÞ but not statistically significant for the admitted.</p><p>In the last row of table 2, we also examine the proportion of non-French among the candidate pool since the entrance exams, with the exception of foreign languages, are conducted in French. Non-French make up 7.45% of the candidates, compared to 7.34% of the admitted ðnot reported in table 2Þ. The observed 0.11% difference is not statistically different from zero. The non-French male-to-female ratio remains similar at different stages of the entrance exam. The percentage of female non-French candidates is 9.03% versus 5.92% for males ðthe difference is statistically significant at the 1% level in a two-tailed t-testÞ, whereas among the admitted the percentage of non-French females is 9.47% versus 5.53% for the males ðthe difference is statistically significant at the 5% levelÞ. Even though being non-French does not appear to affect the proportion of females or the chances of becoming admitted, we nevertheless account for it in our multivariate analysis in order to control for the possibility that differences in written and oral expression skills between native ðmother tongueÞ and nonnative French speakers may have an effect on exam performance.</p><p>Restricting ourselves to science majors in high school does not necessarily guarantee homogeneity in gender composition. Science submajors may have different gender compositions if, for example, males are more likely to choose mathematics or physics and chemistry submajors while females are more likely to choose life sciences ðbiology and geologyÞ. In table 3, we document the gender composition of the three science subspecialties in the baccalaure´at that form 98.10% of our sample: mathematics, physics and chemistry, and life sciences ðbiology and geologyÞ submajors, which represent 70.30%, 15.25%, and 12.55% of our sample, respectively.</p><p>First, we use a two-tailed binomial test for the equality of the observed ði.e., estimatedÞ proportions to check whether there are statistically significant differences in the gender composition of submajors and present the results in brackets in column 3 of table 3. The proportion of male candidates in the mathematics submajor ð51.39%Þ is higher than that of females ð48.61%Þ, a difference that is statistically significant at the 5% level. While the proportion of female candidates is higher for physics and chemistry and life sciences submajors, the observed differences for the latter two groups are not statistically significant. Second, always using a two-tailed binomial test, we check for the equality of the observed proportions of males and females in different submajors as a percentage of the total number of males and females in the overall sample, respectively. The results are reported within parentheses in table 3. We find that the ratio of males with a submajor in mathematics to the total number of males ð71.11%Þ is slightly higher than that of females ð69.46%Þ, a difference that is not statistically significant. We also find that the proportion of males with a submajor in physics and chemistry ðlife sciencesÞ with respect to the total number of males, which is 14.67% ð12.06%Þ, is lower than that of females, which is 15.86% ð13.05%Þ. These differences are not statistically significant either. We also conduct these two sets of proportionality tests for the engineering and other nonspecified submajors and find statistically significant differences. However, these two subsamples form less than 2% of our sample and hence are unlikely to have a major influence on our results. Finally, we conduct a Kolmogorov-Smirnov ðKSÞ equality-of-distributions test after coding a mathematics submajor as 1, physics and chemistry as 2, life and earth sciences as 3, and so forth ðfor the KS test, see, e.g., Siegel and Castellan ½1988, 144-51Þ. We obtain a KS test statistic of 0.0165 with a p-value of .829: when the whole distribution is taken into account, the KS test does not reject the null hypothesis that the science submajors' frequency distributions for males and females are equal, a result that is not surprising given the previous set of proportion test results. Despite the test results in table 3, we nevertheless control for potential differences in the gender composition of the different submajors ðiÞ by including submajor indicator variables in our multivariate regressions and ðiiÞ by reestimating our multivariate specifications for the different submajors ðthese last regressions are reported in the online appendixÞ. Next, we focus on the differences in entrance exam performance between males and females using univariate tests and multivariate regressions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>V. Gender Differences in Performance</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Univariate Analysis</head><p>To test whether there are any differences in performance between genders, we start by conducting a series of parametric and nonparametric univariate tests. First, we examine the overall ðweighted-averageÞ written and oral exam grades. Second, for the same sample, we test for differences in performance during the baccalaure´at and first year of HEC. Third, we explore if the differences that we observe may be driven by potential differences in affinity toward mathematics across genders by examining mathematics and nonmathematics grades.</p><p>In table 4, we present two-tailed test results for the equality of the medians, means, variances, and distributions as well as the frequency distributions for the HEC weighted-average entrance exam grades. Tests of central tendencies for the written and oral exams ðpanels A and B of table 4Þ provide weak evidence that males may be outperforming females. The median of the written ðoralÞ exam grades for males is 10.69 ð10.69Þ compared to 10.52 ð10.54Þ for females. The null hypothesis of the equality of the medians across genders is rejected in a nonparametric test for the equality of the medians for the written exam but cannot be rejected for the oral exam. 32 The mean written ðoralÞ exam score for males is 10.66 ð10.70Þ compared to 10.58 ð10.56Þ for females; the null hypotheses of the equality of the means across genders cannot be rejected in two-sided t-tests for either type of exam. <ref type="bibr" coords="26,386.36,222.42,6.00,5.44">33</ref> Since the entrance exam selects admissibles and admitted using rankingbased cutoffs in the upper tails of the written and oral exams, respectively, we focus our attention on the frequency distributions of the exam grades. When we use a nonparametric KS test, the equality of the frequency distributions is rejected for the written exams score at the 10% level but not rejected for the oral exams. Eyeballing different percentiles of the data reported in panels A and B of table 4, we observe that, compared to the frequency distributions of grades for the women, the men's frequency distributions have fatter right tails in the written and oral exams starting with the medians of these distributions ðsee further below in this section for a formal statistical test of stochastic dominanceÞ. These findings suggest that any acceptance rule that sets a threshold above the median would lead to a higher percentage of men among the admissibles and the admitted.</p><p>These observed differences in performance across genders in the univariate setting may be due to potential differences in mathematics affinity across genders ðfor a discussion, see Niederle and Vesterlund ½2010Þ. To check for this possibility, we repeat the tests described above for the mathematics and nonmathematics parts of the written and oral exams separately ðusing the weights of table 1 to calculate weighted averagesÞ.</p><p>Results are presented in panels C and D of table 4. For the written mathematics exams, we observe a higher median and mean for males and fatter tails that lead to statistically significant differences in frequency distribution and variance tests ðall test results are statistically significant at the 1% levelÞ; for the written nonmathematics exams, we reject the equality of the distributions at the 10% level and the equality of the variances at the 1% level, but we cannot reject the equality of the means or medians. For the oral exams, the two-sided t-test for the null hypothesis of the 32 See Siegel and Castellan ð1988, 124-28Þ for a description of this test. <ref type="bibr" coords="26,90.03,587.01,6.00,5.44">33</ref> The Wilcoxon-Mann-Whitney test ðe.g., <ref type="bibr" coords="26,257.50,587.42,96.08,9.19" target="#b24">Siegel and Castellan 1988</ref>, 128-37Þ, the nonparametric equivalent of a t-test, rejects the equality of the means for the written test at the 10% level. <ref type="bibr" coords="26,81.07,68.23,13.50,9.19">468</ref> Ors et al. equality of the means is rejected only for the oral mathematics exam. These results indicate that we need to repeat our multivariate analyses for the mathematics and nonmathematics performance metrics to rule out the possibility that any difference that we may observe is driven by differences in mathematics affinities across genders. While the tests described above help us understand differences in various characteristics of performance metrics, they cannot help answer whether the distribution of males' performance dominates that of females in the sense of first-order stochastic dominance ðFOSDÞ. To answer this question, we use the KS-type FOSD test proposed by <ref type="bibr" coords="28,252.68,198.49,113.56,10.21;28,366.18,198.44,6.00,5.44">Barrett and Donald ð2003Þ. 34</ref> This test allows us to check for FOSD even when the test variable takes on a limited number of values ðas in the case of the baccalaure´at honors or the letter grades during the first year of HECÞ and when the sample sizes differ across males and females.</p><p>Weak FOSD is formally defined as follows: given MðxÞ and FðxÞ, the CDF for a variable x for males and females, respectively, M weakly dominates F in the FOSD sense if MðxÞ ≤ FðxÞ for any x. A rejection of the null hypothesis H 0 : FðxÞ ≤ MðxÞ ðin col. 1 of table 5Þ combined with a failure to reject H 0 0 : MðxÞ ≤ FðxÞ ðin col. 2 of table 5Þ would suggest that males' performance weakly dominates that of females in an FOSD sense, while the converse finding would suggest that females' performance weakly dominates that of males. A failure to reject both null hypotheses would suggest that FðxÞ and MðxÞ cannot be ranked in the FOSD sense.</p><p>We observe that in the written exam, the performance of males dominates that of females in the FOSD sense: in row 1 of table 5 we reject H 0 ðFðxÞ ≤ MðxÞÞ but we cannot reject H 0 0 ðMðxÞ ≤ FðxÞÞ. Similarly, the test results presented in row 2 of table 5 indicate that during the first stage of the entrance exam, males' mathematics performance dominates that of females in the FOSD sense. In contrast, the tests of row 3 indicate that females' nonmathematics performance dominates that of males in the FOSD sense. These results indicate once more that we need to repeat our multivariate regressions for the mathematics and nonmathematics parts of the entrance exam separately.</p><p>Interestingly, these results do not extend to the oral stage of the entrance exam, where the CDFs for the performance of males and females cannot be ranked in the FOSD sense: in rows 4, 5, and 6 of table 5, neither of the two null hypotheses H 0 and H 0 0 can be rejected. In other words, during the oral exams, neither group dominates the other one in an FOSD 34 Their approach has the advantage of avoiding the problem of test inconsistency by comparing cumulative distribution functions ðCDFsÞ of the test variable across the two groups on a continuous basis ðinstead of a fixed number of arbitrary points, say 5 or 10 as in Anderson ½1996 or Davidson and Duclos ½2000Þ. To conduct the Barrett and Donald ð2003Þ test, we use the GAUSS codes available on Garry Barrett's website: http://www.economics.unsw.edu.au/GarryBarrett. sense when using global or mathematics versus nonmathematics performance metrics. Of course, this conclusion is obtained in a univariate setting and need not hold in a multivariate setting, something we focus on in Section V.B below.</p><p>Next, using the same cohorts of students, we conduct FOSD tests using academic performance metrics before and after the entrance exam. Row 7 of table 5 presents FOSD test results for baccalaure´at honors. We observe a nonrejection of the null hypothesis in column 1 together with a rejection in column 2 at the 1% level. This suggests that science major female candidates' performance at the end of high school as measured by baccalaure´at honors dominates that of men in the FOSD sense.</p><p>We revisit the potential concern that differences in baccalaure´at performance may, at least in part, be driven by potential differences in mathematics ability across genders, which is likely to be reflected in the submajor choices. In rows 8, 9, and 10 of table 5, we repeat the same FOSD tests for the three largest categories of science submajors ðmathematics, physics and chemistry, and life sciencesÞ. We find that the females' bac-calaure´at performance continues to dominate that of males for all the science submajors at the 1% significance level, which suggests that females' superior performance during the baccalaure´at does not appear to be driven by implicit differences in gender distributions across submajors.</p><p>We also provide FOSD tests of performance during core courses in the first year of HEC when the admitted take 11 compulsory classes. To increase the power of our tests, we use letter grades obtained in all compulsory first-year courses ð5,046 observationsÞ rather than students' GPAs ð459 observationsÞ. <ref type="bibr" coords="29,163.67,390.45,6.00,5.44">35</ref> Results provided at the bottom of table 5 indicate that women's performance dominates that of men in the FOSD sense: in row 11 we cannot reject H 0 , but we reject H 0 0 , albeit at the 10% level. Then, we repeat weak FOSD tests after splitting the 11 first-year courses into two groups: five mathematics-oriented courses ðeconomics, finance, quantitative methods, statistics, and supply chain managementÞ and six nonmathematics-oriented courses ðaccounting, business law, English as a first foreign language, marketing, modeling with Excel, and theory of organi-zationsÞ. For the mathematics-oriented classes ðrow 12 of table 5Þ, we cannot reject either H 0 or H 0 0 . In contrast, for the nonmathematics-oriented classes ðrow 13Þ, we cannot reject H 0 while we reject H 0 0 at the 1% level: females weakly dominate males in the FOSD sense in the nonmathematics courses during the first year. In row 14 of table 5 we obtain a similar, albeit weaker, result with the subsample of students who were a mathematics submajor in <ref type="bibr" coords="29,89.97,567.00,6.00,5.44">35</ref> All of the 459 first-year students ðwith a science backgroundÞ in our sample ð226 in 2005 and 233 in 2006Þ took the 11 core courses. However, we have 5,046 letter grade observations, rather than 5,049 ð5 459 Â 11Þ, because three letter grades are missing in our data. In our empirical analysis, we do not take into account the differences in ECTS credits across these 11 courses when using letter grades. high school: we cannot reject H 0 , but we reject H 0 0 at the 10% level. When we repeat the FOSD tests with the physics and chemistry ðrow 15Þ or life sciences ðrow 16Þ submajors, we fail to reject both hypotheses. We conclude that the women's FOSD results during HEC's first year are driven by the mathematics submajors in high school, but through their nonmathematicsoriented classes.</p><p>Given the HEC entrance selection process, these results provide a first insight. The distribution of male candidates' written-exam scores has a right tail that is fatter than that of female candidates. Since roughly only the top quartile of candidates are admitted to the oral exam stage, a larger percentage of men become admissible than women. This result contrasts with those obtained for the ðnoncompetitiveÞ baccalaure´at exam: ðthe sameÞ women in our sample did significantly better than the same men in the baccalaure´at exam ðin terms of high school graduation honorsÞ, irrespective of whether they were candidates or admissibles or were eventually admitted. In other words, the women who did relatively worse than men in the top quartile for the HEC entrance contest, which roughly corresponds to the admissibles, actually did better than the same men at the baccalaure´at exam. When examining the written exam scores, we observe that the male candidates have performed better in mathematics than females, with the roles  the top quartile of candidates becomes the admissibles, this observed performance difference disappears in the oral exam setting. These univariate tests do not allow us to control for the observable characteristics of the candidates, which may explain part or all of the observed variation in performance across males and females. As a result, in the next subsection we conduct a series of tests using multivariate regressions that also have the advantage of absorbing the residual variance, which allows for more precise estimates of the differences across genders.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Multivariate Regression Analysis</head><p>Because we would like to examine how the observed difference varies at the tails of the distribution for our academic performance metrics, we use quantile regressions with bootstrapped standard errors ðobtained with 5,000 replicationsÞ that are simultaneously estimated for different percentiles. We limit ourselves to the 10th, 25th, 50th, 75th, and 90th percentiles because ðiÞ they are commonly used in the literature and ðiiÞ the 75th percentile of candidates ðtop 1,420 observationsÞ approximately corresponds to the admissibles ð1,371 observationsÞ whereas the 90th percentile of candidates ðtop 570 observationsÞ very roughly approximates the admitted ð736 observationsÞ.</p><p>We include a number of indicator ð"dummy"Þ variables ðpreceded by D _ Þ in our specifications to control for the various characteristics of candidates. First, we control for potential differences in the grading distributions across the 3 years in our data using indicator variables for years <ref type="bibr" coords="32,331.21,367.38,61.93,10.21;32,81.07,378.15,98.88,11.46;32,179.89,379.34,6.00,5.44">2006 and 2007 ðD _ 2006 and D _ 2007Þ. 36</ref> Second, we account for the fact that non-French candidates' performance may be affected in a series of exams conducted in French through the indicator variable D _ non-French. Third, we control for the science submajor chosen during the last year of high school using the indicator variables D _ mathematics _ submajor, D _ physics _ and _ chemistry _ submajor, and D _ life _ sciences _ submajor. Fourth, we account for the academic ability of the candidates using indicator variables for any honors they have received during the baccalaure´at: D _ cum _ laude, D _ magna _ cum _ laude, and D _ summa _ cum _ laude. Finally, we account for the quality of the 2-year preparation that the candidate followed prior to taking the entrance exam through indicator variables for the individual prep schools. These prep school "fixed effects" ðwhose coefficients are not reported to conserve spaceÞ allow us to control for the unobservable quality of all the prep schools, including the quality of the nonranked ones. 37 They also allow us to implic- <ref type="bibr" coords="32,89.97,562.01,6.00,5.44">36</ref> The year dummies would account for the changes in the quantiles of the grading distributions across the years for both genders. We have no reason to suspect that the potential changes in grading standards would evolve differently for each of the genders. <ref type="bibr" coords="32,89.97,602.03,6.00,5.44">37</ref> In alternative specifications we used the logarithm of the prep school ranking, which cannot take into account the quality of the nonranked institutions as these latter are given the same rank. The resulting estimates ðwhich are reported in the itly control for the unobservable academic abilities of the candidates, albeit at the prep school level, that would have played a part in these institutions' admission decisions. Following the inclusion of all the indicator variables mentioned above, the constant term picks up the average grade for the omitted group, which includes French males who were not in one of the three most prestigious science submajors in high school, who did not receive any honors during the 2005 baccalaure´at, and who did not attend a prep school to prepare for the entrance exam. Given the focus of our study, D _ female is our test variable. For the oral exam performance regressions, we also use all the grades obtained in the individual written exams, as well as their squared values, in order to be able to extract the maximum amount of information from the data that are at our disposal.</p><p>Regression results in which the overall written exam score is the dependent variable are presented in table 6. First, we focus on the 50th percentile ðthe median regressionÞ column to get a sense of the coefficient estimates for the various indicator variables included in our specification. The coefficient estimates for D _ 2006 and D _ 2007 are 0.7954 and 0.9799, respectively, and are statistically significant at the 1% level, suggesting that there are differences in the performance and/or grading of the candidates across the years. As we expected, the non-French tend to do less well ðthe coefficient estimate, which is statistically significant at the 1% level, is equal to 20.4711Þ. There are no discernible differences in the performance of the candidates coming from different science submajors in high school ðnamely, mathematics, physics and chemistry, and life sciencesÞ compared to the excluded group. We observe that the baccalaure´at honors are very good predictors of performance at the HEC entrance exam: compared to students with no honors, students with a cum laude obtain an average grade 0.8994 points higher ðout of 20Þ, those with magna cum laude 1.5976 points higher, and those with summa cum laude 2.5888 points higher, all of which are statistically significant at the 1% level. To put these coefficient estimates into perspective, we note that the written exam threshold for a candidate to become admissible was 11.64 ðout of 20Þ in <ref type="bibr" coords="33,256.17,462.46,136.80,10.21;33,80.96,474.48,17.52,10.21">2005, 12.58 in 2006, and 12.76 in 2007</ref>, with the highest overall written exam grade obtained being <ref type="bibr" coords="33,359.51,474.48,33.46,10.21;33,80.96,486.50,160.92,10.21">16.99 in 2005, 17.47 in 2006, and 18.30 in 2007</ref>. These findings for the median regression generally extend to the quantile regressions for the 10th, 25th, 75th, and 90th percentiles, with the exception of ðiÞ mathematics submajors whose performance is higher only in the regression for the 10th percentile ðalbeit statistically significant at the 10% levelÞ and ðiiÞ non-French candidates whose performance is worse than that of the French candidates ðcoefficient estimates are negative and statistically significantÞ in the regressions for the 10th and 25th percentiles, but not in the regressions for the 75th and 90th percentiles. online appendix to conserve spaceÞ are not materially different from the ones we report.  <ref type="table" coords="35,244.46,90.49,5.00,10.21" target="#tab_8">6</ref> show that the coefficient estimate for the D _ female variable is 20.1357 in the regression for the 10th percentile, 20.2562 for the 25th percentile, 20.3488 for the 50th percentile, 20.5153 for the 75th percentile, and 20.6646 for the 90th percentile, all of which are statistically significant at the 1% level except the first one, which is not statistically significant. 38 Hence, after controlling for the potential differences in grading and/or cohorts' ability across the years, candidates' affinity for mathematics ðindirectly, through the high school submajor indicator vari-ablesÞ, candidates' academic ability ðdirectly using the baccalaure´at honors they received 2 years ago as well as indirectly using the prep school fixed effectsÞ, and whether they hold French nationality or not, we find that women, on average, do worse than men in the written exam in the regressions for the 25th, 50th, 75th, and 90th percentiles.</p><p>To get a sense of the economic significance of the observed difference for the females, we look at the effect of hypothetically adjusting the threshold for admission for the females. In this exercise we recalculate the proportion of females among the admissibles after decreasing the year-specific written exam threshold to become admissible by 0.3488 ðthe coefficient estimate for D _ female in the quantile regression for the medianÞ and after applying this hypothetical threshold to females alone. As a result of this exercise, which is admittedly unfair to males, the proportion of females among the admissibles increases from 46.32% to 50.64%, suggesting that the effects we observe are economically nonnegligible. Another way to argue for the economic significance for the underperformance is to note that females with no honors would need to have cum laude honors compared to males with no honors in order to be able to compensate for their lower performance during the written exam. <ref type="bibr" coords="35,235.67,402.42,5.83,5.44">39</ref> We conclude that the results of table 6 corroborate those obtained in univariate tests: in the written exam, women underperform men in the regressions at the 25th, 50th, 75th, and 90th percentiles of the performance distribution, while there is no statistically significant performance difference between the two genders at the 10th percentile regression. We should note that while women outperform men in the lower tail of the written exam average in a univariate setting ðe.g., at the 10th percentile of the distribution in table 4Þ, we find no such difference in a multivariate setting ðthe coef- <ref type="bibr" coords="35,89.97,526.97,6.00,5.44">38</ref> In an alternative specification, which uses the logarithm of prep school rank instead of prep school fixed effects, we obtain quantitatively similar results. These estimates are reported in app. table A1. <ref type="bibr" coords="35,89.97,556.96,6.00,5.44">39</ref> That said, obtaining cum laude honors would overcompensate for the females' underperformance given that the positive coefficient estimate in table 6 for D _ cum _ laude is larger than the negative coefficient estimate for D _ female. For example, in the regression for the 50th percentile regression, the coefficient estimate for D _ female is equal to 20.3488 whereas the coefficient estimate for D _ cum _ laude is equal to 0.8994 ðboth of them statistically significant at the 1% levelÞ. ficient estimate for D _ female, which is equal to 20.1357, is not statistically significantÞ. These findings suggest that it is important to control for the observable characteristics of the candidates before reaching any conclusions.</p><p>Next, we explore whether our findings of lower performance for females in the written exam might be driven by differences in performance in the mathematics versus nonmathematics tests, for two reasons. First, the univariate test results reported in tables 4 and 5 suggest that there are performance differences between genders across the written mathematics versus nonmathematics exams. Given that mathematics grades account for one-third of the written entrance exam's total score for the science track candidates ðsee table 1Þ, we would like to rule out the possibility that our results are actually driven by the mathematics scores. Second, there appear to be differences across genders in perceptions of own abilities in scientific and nonscientific fields ðsee, e.g., Niederle and Vesterlund ½2010 for a dis-cussionÞ. <ref type="bibr" coords="36,118.21,270.44,6.00,5.44">40</ref> To examine whether potential mathematics affinity differences across genders play a role, we run the same quantile regressions separately for the mathematics and nonmathematics parts of the written exam, using their respective weighted-average exam scores. Results are reported in tables 7 and 8, respectively. For the written mathematics and nonmathematics exams, results are qualitatively similar to those obtained in table 6 using the overall written exam performance. Focusing on our test variable, D _ female, for the weighted-average score of the two mathematics exams taken during the first stage, we find that the coefficient estimate in table 7 is equal to 20.1267 for the regression at the10th percentile, 20.3877 at the 25th percentile, 20.7830 at the 50th percentile, 21.1051 at the 75th percentile, and 21.2504 at the 90th percentile. All these coefficient estimates are statistically significant at the 1% level except that for the 10th percentile, which is not statistically significant. Importantly, we observe a similar pattern in table 8 for the nonmathematics exams' weighted-average score with all the written exams except the two mathematics exams. The coefficient estimate for D _ female is equal to 20.0632 for the regression for the 10th percentile, 20.1453 for the 25th percentile, 20.2242 for the 50th percentile, 20.2747 for the 75th percentile, and 20.2968 for the 90th percentile. These estimates are all statistically significant ðat the 5% or 1% levelÞ except for the 10th percentile regression. Together, these results indicate that the performance difference that we observe for females in table 6 for the global written exam 40 For example, Beyer ð2002Þ finds differences in self-valuation between men and women in a mathematics test but no difference in an English test or in a history and geography test. Similarly, <ref type="bibr" coords="36,196.44,567.41,69.80,9.19">Beyer et al. ð2004Þ</ref> provide evidence that female undergraduate students majoring in management information systems underestimate their ability to a greater extent than do male students, while Beyer, Rynes, and Haller ð2004Þ find that women have lower confidence levels than men in their ability in computer sciences. <ref type="bibr" coords="36,81.07,68.23,13.50,9.19">478</ref> Ors et al.  grade for the various percentiles is not driven by differences in mathematics alone: in the regressions at the 25th, 50th, 75th, and 90th percentiles, men's performance is higher than women's, with the differences being statistically significant irrespective of whether the evaluations are based on mathematics or not. 41 While we observe a similar pattern of increasing differences in the gender performance gap for mathematics and nonmathematics exams, the coefficient estimates reported in tables 7 and 8 are not directly comparable since the standard deviation of written mathematics exams' score ð4.25Þ is more than twice as large as that for nonmathematics exams ð2.07Þ. To make the coefficient estimates of D _ female comparable across tables 7 and 8, we standardize the coefficient estimates by multiplying each with the standard deviation of the explanatory variable and dividing by the standard deviation of the dependent variable. The standardized coefficient estimates ðnot reportedÞ suggest that the wedge between the performance of males and females is larger for mathematics: the standardized coefficient estimates for D _ female for mathematics exams are 1.3, 1.7, 1.9, and 2.0 times larger than the standardized estimates for nonmathematics exams in the regressions at the 25th, 50th, 75th, and 90th percentiles, respectively. It should also be noted that the weight of the nonmathematics fields in the overall written exam score is 63.33%, which is almost double that of the mathematics weight. Together, these two observations suggest that, for example, at the 90th percentile of the ðoverallÞ written exam performance distribution, the mathematics and nonmathematics fields contribute approximately equally to the observed difference in performance. In other words, men's higher performance in mathematics is not the sole driver of the gender performance gap that we observe in the written exam: even though the mathematics exams have a higher impact than those in the nonmathematics-related fields, the latter, compared to the former, have almost twice the weight in the overall performance metric for the written exam.</p><p>Finally, given the differences observed in table 3 in the proportion of genders across mathematics submajors on the one hand ð48.61% femalesÞ and the physics and chemistry or life sciences submajors ð51.14% and 51.12% females, respectivelyÞ on the other, we also reestimate the simultaneous quantile regressions of table 6 for these subsamples separately: the results for the mathematics submajor in high school on the one hand ðin online app. table A4Þ and the physics and chemistry and life sciences submajors on the other ðin app. table A5Þ mirror very closely those of table 6. We conclude that our results are not solely driven by the mathematics submajor as the univariate tests of table 3 may have suggested.</p><p>Next, we turn our attention to the second stage of the entrance exam. <ref type="table" coords="40,81.07,102.46,32.21,10.21" target="#tab_11">Table 9</ref> presents the results of the oral exam performance regressions using simultaneous quantile regressions, with bootstrapped standard errors ðwith 5,000 replicationsÞ, for the 25th, 50th, and 75th percentiles. The choice of these percentiles is guided by the fact that the admitted roughly correspond to the 75th percentile of the admissibles sample taking the oral exams. 42 On the right-hand-side of the oral exam performance specification, we add the grades for all the written exams in various subjects as well as their squared values in order to better control for the academic aptitudes of the admissibles as reflected in the grades of the first stage. Results for the weighted-average oral exams ðwith the weights as detailed in table 1Þ, reported in columns 1-3 of table 9, indicate that the performance difference at the higher end of the distribution that we observe for females during the first stage of the entrance exam remains during the second stage: D _ female coefficient estimates are 20.2052, 20.2036, and 20.2780 for the quantile regressions at the 25th, 50th, and 75th percentiles, respectively. However, these results are weaker, with only the coefficient estimate at the 75th percentile being marginally significant at the 10% level. We would like to note that, given the smaller sample size for the admissibles versus the candidates ð1,366 vs. 5,635 observations, respectivelyÞ, the coefficient estimates of the oral exam performance regressions are less precise than those of the written exam.</p><p>The oral mathematics exam results ðcols. 4-6 of table 9Þ also indicate a lower performance for females, but only at the 25th percentile: coefficient estimates for the dummy variable D _ female are 20. <ref type="bibr" coords="40,327.23,366.51,65.82,10.00;40,81.07,378.50,55.36,10.21">7340, 20.2992, and 20.2679</ref> for the regressions at the 25th, 50th, and 75th percentiles, respectively, with only the coefficient estimate for the 25th quartile being statistically significant ðat the 5% levelÞ. The results for the weighted average of oral nonmathematics exams ðcols. 7-9 of table 9Þ mirror those of columns 1-3: the coefficient estimates for D _ female are 20.0383, 20.1632, and 20.3574 for the quantile regressions at the 25th, 50th, and 75th percentiles, respectively, with only the coefficient estimate at the 75th percentile being statistically significant at the 5% level. These results are weaker than those obtained for the written exams. They nevertheless suggest that the females still underperform males in the highest quartile, with the observed effect being driven by nonmathematics-related fields, which is surprising given the results of univariate tests reported in table 4. In fact, this finding is comforting since it suggests that the selection process is not solely driven by the potentially higher mathematics affinity of males. However, it should also be noted that the coefficient estimates for the oral exams are also less precise: the sample size of admissibles in table 9 is roughly one-fourth of the sample size of candidates in table 6. Finally, we reestimate the regressions of table 9 for the subsample of admissibles who majored in mathematics ðapp. table A6Þ and those who majored in physics and chemistry or the life sciences ðapp. table A7Þ. In appendix table A6, women's underperformance results for the 1,069 admissibles who are mathematics submajors are stronger than those of table 9 ðin terms of estimates with statistical significanceÞ. In contrast, we find no evidence of underperformance for the physics and chemistry or the life sciences majors, noting that we have only 275 observations for this subsample in the oral exam stage.</p><p>Next, we turn our attention to the less competitive academic evaluations that the same students went through: the noncompetitive baccalau-re´at exam 2 years prior to the entrance exam and the less competitive firstyear core courses at HEC. To examine performance differences across genders in the baccalaure´at exam, we estimate a series of linear probability models. In the main set of regressions, the dependent variable is equal to one if the candidate obtained the high school diploma with at least a certain level of honors ðcum laude, magna cum laude, or summa cum laudeÞ and zero for the group that got a simple pass ðwith no honorsÞ. For example, for the group that has obtained the baccalaure´at with at least magna cum laude, the dependent variable is equal to one if the candidate has obtained the high school diploma with magna cum laude or summa cum laude and zero if the candidate got no honors; the candidates with cum laude honors are excluded. In these regressions, where the base case is always the group with no honors, we control for the two characteristics of the candidates that were observable as of the date of the exam: the category of science submajor in high school and whether the candidate is a non-French national. We also include the year indicator variables to control for changes in the difficulty of the baccalaure´at and/or the distribution of its evaluation standards across the years. In these regressions we use heteroskedasticityconsistent ði.e., "robust"Þ standard errors because the linear probability models are heteroskedastic by construction.</p><p>The results, presented in columns 1-3 of table 10, indicate that the female candidates, who eventually do worse than males during the HEC entrance exam, actually do better than the same male candidates during the baccalaure´at exam. Irrespective of the honors type, the coefficient estimate for D _ female is positive and statistically significant at the 1% level: the probability of a candidate obtaining the baccalaure´at degree with honors is higher for females. The coefficient estimate for D _ female is 0.0503 ðcol. 1Þ for the group with at least cum laude ðwhich is inclusive of all honors groupsÞ, 0.0782 ðcol. 2Þ for the group with at least magna cum laude, and 0.2129 ðcol. 3Þ for the group with at least summa cum laude. The relative probability of a female obtaining an honor appears to increase with the level of the honors. 43  In alternative linear regression models, presented in columns 4-6 of table 10, we reestimate the same set of linear probability models after including fixed effects for prep schools, which allow us control for the candidates' unobservable academic characteristics, albeit in an indirect way. The admission decisions of prep schools are based on candidates' academic qualities ðthrough grades and high school professors' appreciations as reflected in grade bulletins and reference lettersÞ that are unobservable to us: prep schools vary in the degree of selectiveness in their admission process, with the best ones admitting the best high school seniors. Moreover, these institutions make their admission decisions before the candidates pass their baccalaure´at exams. As a result, introducing prep school fixed effects allows us to better control for candidates' unobservable characteristics ðas revealed by these institutions' admission decisionsÞ as of the date of the bac-calaure´at exam, albeit at the prep school level.</p><p>The results presented in columns 4-6 of table 10 are very similar to those of columns 1-3. We observe that after we control for the unobservable academic qualities that lead to prep school admission decisions, female candidates have a higher relative probability of obtaining their baccalaure´at with honors. In columns 4-6 of table 10, D _ female coefficient estimates corresponding to at least cum laude, at least magna cum laude, or at least summa cum laude honors are equal to 0.0328, 0.0496, and 0.1034, respectively ðall are statistically significant at the 1% levelÞ.</p><p>Finally, given the differences in the proportion of female candidates in different subsamples in table 3, we reestimate table 10 regressions separately for the subsample that majored in mathematics ðapp. table A8Þ and the subsample that majored in physics and chemistry or life sciences ðapp. table A9Þ. The results of these subsample regressions are very similar to those presented in table 10. We conclude that female candidates, whose performances were below those of males in the very competitive HEC entrance exam, did significantly better than the same males 2 years prior in a series of noncompetitive exams.</p><p>In the final part of our multivariate analysis, we examine the performance of the admitted during the first year of the HEC grande e´cole program. Univariate tests presented in table 5 using core course letter grades suggest that females' performance dominates that of males in an FOSD sense when we combine all letter grades. To revisit these results, first, we regress students' GPA, which is based on 11 core courses they have to take, on all the observable characteristics of the admitted. Similarly to our analysis of the written and oral stages of the HEC entrance exam, we also reestimate the first-year regressions using a GPA based on the five mathematicsoriented courses and another GPA based on the six nonmathematicsoriented subjects. These GPAs are calculated using course letter grades and respective ECTS credit hours. 44 Before commenting on the GPA regression results, we note that, in a multivariate setting, we do not expect to find any differences in performance between males and females during the first-year core courses for two reasons. First, this is a group of highly talented students who excelled in the baccalaure´at, who were typically admitted to the best prep schools, and who survived the competitive HEC entrance exam. We have no a priori reason to believe that any differences in performance across genders would remain for such a group of highly competitive and ex post successful individuals. Second, despite the above-mentioned FOSD test results presented in table 5, in the first-year performance regressions we are including "everything but the kitchen sink," which allows us to control for all the observable student characteristics.</p><p>When we examine the first-year GPA ðcol. 1 of table 11Þ, the coefficient estimate for D _ female is positive and equal to 0.0342 but is not statistically significant. We also find no effect when examining GPA of the mathematicsoriented classes ðcol. 2Þ: the coefficient estimate for D _ female is equal to 20.1118 but is not statistically significant. Nevertheless, when we run the GPA regression for the nonmathematics-oriented classes, we find a coefficient estimate of 0.1521, which is statistically significant at the 5% level ðcol. 3Þ. So we have some evidence that women do better than men when we examine the first-year GPAs, albeit for nonmathematics-oriented courses alone.</p><p>However, the first-year GPA regressions may not be precise enough. First, the GPA is an ECTS credit weighted-average performance metric in which professor or course-specific grade distribution differences cannot be accounted for. Second, the number of observations with which GPA regressions can be run is somewhat limited: we have 457 students, but these have obtained a total of 5,046 letter grades.</p><p>Given this, we run similar regressions using the individual first-year core course letter grade as the dependent variable, after including separate time-varying professor and course fixed effects to the existing prep school fixed effects. Given that we use all the core course letter grades obtained by an individual, we cluster the standard errors at the student level. Results are reported in table 11, columns 4-6. In column 4, where we consider all individual course grades, the coefficient estimate for D _ female is equal to 0.0420, which is statistically insignificant. In column 5, the corresponding coefficient estimate based on the mathematics-oriented course grades is equal to 20.0942, which is not statistically significant either. The D _ female coefficient estimate in column 6 in the regression for the nonmathematicsmethods 2.5 ECTS credits each; and modeling with Excel and English as a first foreign language 2 ECTS credits each, for a total of 44 ECTS credits for the 11 mandatory courses. We exclude the first-year elective courses ðworth 16 ECTS creditsÞ since students differ in their elective course choices, and we would like to have a common performance metric. oriented course grades is equal to 0.1506 and is statistically significant at the 5% level. We note that the GPA and course grade regressions yield D _ female coefficient estimates that are similar in size and statistical significance, even though GPAs are weighted by ECTS credit hours whereas the individual letter grades are not. We interpret these results, which are limited to nonmathematics-oriented courses, as weak evidence of higher performance by women in the first year at HEC. We would like to stress that our prior was to find no systematic performance difference among this highly competitive group of students admitted to the school. Finally, wealsorevisit the regression models of table 11 with the subsamples' mathematics submajors as well as physics and chemistry and life sciences submajors in high school. The results are presented in appendix table A10: the coefficient estimate for D _ female is not statistically significant except for the letter grade regression for the physics and chemistry or life sciences submajors, for which it is negative but statistically significant only at the 10% level.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>VI. Discussion</head><p>In this section, we revisit our findings within the context of the related literature on performance differences across genders. We have shown that in the setting of a tournament-like real-world academic selection process ðthe HEC entrance examÞ, where payoffs at stake are large and economically important, women tend to do worse than men, while they perform as well as or better than the same men in academic evaluations where competition is either absent or less intensive. The findings of the univariate tests are corroborated in multivariate regressions in which we control for all the observable characteristics that are available to us as of the date of the said evaluation. We find that, typically, the right tail of the performance distributions is significantly fatter for men than for women. Given that only 380 candidates are admitted to the school, this results in more men being admitted to the top French business school than women.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Potential Differences in Innate Ability</head><p>The easiest ðbut, in our opinion, erroneousÞ conclusion one could draw by focusing on the data obtained from the HEC entrance examination is that men are more skilled than women. For such an explanation to hold, we should observe systematically lower performance for females in the three academic evaluations taken by the same individuals. Evidence provided in Section V shows that this is not the case. For the same cohort of students, women's performance is higher during the baccalaure´at, which is a noncompetitive exam ðin the sense that the success of one student does not hinder another student's attainment of the degree during the baccalau-re´atÞ. For the admitted, during the first year of HEC, which is less competitive than the entrance exam ðin the sense that the ex ante failure probabilities given the HEC-suggested grade distributions as well as the ex post 1-3Þ and ðiiÞ individual letter grades in core courses ðcols. 4-6Þ. All regressions are with prep school fixed effects ðfor which the coefficient estimates are not reportedÞ. "Everything but the kitchen sink" regressions ðcols.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4-6Þ</head><p>with letter grades as the dependent variable also include time-varying professor and time-varying course fixed effects ðfor which the coefficient estimates are not reportedÞ. Standard errors are reported within parentheses below coefficient estimates. In cols. 4-6, heteroskedasticity-consistent standard errors are clustered at the student level. * p &lt; class failures are very lowÞ, we also find, albeit weaker, evidence that female students do better than male students. We also would like to note that there are similarities in content that are important, allowing us to focus on the differences in the level of competition. For example, during the science track baccalaure´at exam, similarly to the HEC admission process, students have to take written exams that include French literature ðboth written and oralÞ, mathematics, history, geography, philosophy, and foreign languages ðoralÞ. 45 Hence, the comparison of the distributions of performances both at the baccalaure´at exam and at the HEC admission contest provides a way of testing whether difference in ability is a possible explanation for the differences in performances observed at the HEC admission contest. We observe striking differences when we compare the results of tables 6-9, where females underperform in the HEC entrance exam, with those of table 10, where they outperform in the baccalaure´at exam. Importantly, this reversal of performances persists even when we reestimate the multivariate regression models for the different science submajors. Moreover, when considering the much less competitive HEC first-year core courses ðwhere only 1% of students obtain an FÞ, we observe that in multivariate "everything but the kitchen sink" regressions of individual letter grades, women who underperform during the entrance exam do better than the same men in nonmathematics-oriented classes once admitted to the school. These findings therefore suggest that differences in innate abilities are unlikely to explain the lower performance of females during the HEC entrance exam.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Potential Differences in Mathematics Affinity</head><p>The accumulating evidence indicates that males perform better in mathematics in more competitive settings ðsee Niederle and Vesterlund ½2010 for a thorough review of this literatureÞ. Our evidence indicates that some of the gender gap in performance that we observe may be driven by the higher mathematics affinity of males in our sample. In both univariate tests and multivariate regressions, we observe that the males' ðfemales'Þ tendency to do better in mathematics or mathematics-related ðnonmathematics-relatedÞ subjects relative to females ðmalesÞ can be detected in our data. This result is consistent with the results of <ref type="bibr" coords="51,211.12,487.40,75.34,10.21">Guiso et al. ð2008Þ</ref>, who find that ðiÞ gender differences in mathematics performance are positively correlated with the World Economic Forum Gender Gap Index and that ðiiÞ France scores low in that index. This said, the differences of genders in mathematics affinity could not be said to be the main driver of our results. First, women's performance dominates that of men during the baccalaure´at exam irrespective of the submajor, even in fields such as life sciences or physics and chemistry, where females make up a relatively higher fraction of the students. Second, in the written stage of the entrance exam, women underperform men in both mathematics and nonmathematics-related fields ðsee tables 7 and 8Þ. Third, we would like to emphasize the fact that in the overall performance metrics ðthe dependent variable in table 6 and cols. 1-3 of table 9Þ, the weight of mathematics is 36.67% in the written stage and 25% in the oral stage ðmore on this in Sec. VI.C belowÞ. If anything, given men's apparently higher affinity for mathematics and women's apparently higher affinity for nonmathematics-related subjects, the way mathematics are weighted in the entrance exam is likely to put men at a disadvantage, potentially biasing the exam in favor of women. That said, our results also indicate that, while we observe no difference in performance across genders when all courses together or when mathematics-oriented first-year courses are considered, women appear to be doing better in nonmathematics-oriented classes once admitted to HEC.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C. Weights Associated with Mathematics-Oriented Fields in Performance Metrics</head><p>Another possibility for the observed gender difference in performances is that the implicit weights involved in the calculation of the weightedaverage grades in the three academic evaluations that we examine favor males during the entrance exam and females during the baccalaure´at and first-year core courses at HEC. This could be a plausible explanation given that we observe differences in the mathematics affinity of males and females in our sample ðas reflected in the results reported in <ref type="table" coords="52,320.77,354.57,72.24,10.21;52,81.07,366.59,105.96,10.21" target="#tab_5">table 5, table 7 vs.  table 8, as well as table 9Þ</ref>. To explore this possibility, in tables 12, 13, and 14, we provide detailed information about the weights given to each of the subject matters included in the three academic evaluations that we analyze. In table 12, we provide weights in the baccalaure´at per science submajor. For the mathematics and physics and chemistry submajors ðwhich form 87.45% of our sampleÞ, the weights given to the fields that lend their names to them account for 37.5% of the baccalaure´at grade, with the remaining 62.5% accounted for by the fields that we label as nonmathematics-oriented ðlife sciences, French, history and geography, first and second foreign ½or a regional language, philosophy, and physical educationÞ. <ref type="bibr" coords="52,319.58,474.53,6.00,5.44">46</ref> In contrast, the weight of mathematics during the written part of the entrance exam is a slightly lower 36.67% ðtable 13Þ. If anything, the slightly higher weight given to mathematics-oriented fields during the baccalaure´at should favor men's performance. However, we observe the opposite. The slightly lower weights for mathematics and physics and chemistry for the life sciences submajors, which form 12.55% of our sample, are unlikely to explain the differences we observe between tables 6 ðwritten exam regressionsÞ and 10 <ref type="bibr" coords="52,89.97,587.01,6.00,5.44">46</ref> We choose not to classify the life sciences ðbiology and geologyÞ submajor and exams as mathematics oriented, something that is potentially open to debate, so as not to "inflate" mathematics-oriented fields' weights in the baccalaure´at.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>494</head><p>Ors et al.  or 11 ðbaccalaure´at regressionsÞ. In fact, as mentioned before, females' higher performance during the baccalaure´at persists when we examine the mathematics submajors ðsee app. tables A8 and A9Þ.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D. Alternative Explanations</head><p>One potential explanation for the observed difference in performance across genders is risk aversion. As detailed in the literature surveys of Eckel and Grossman ð2008Þ and Croson and Gneezy ð2009Þ, the findings of the experimental studies indicate that women tend to be more risk  averse than men in various settings. Unfortunately, the data that are at our disposal do not allow us to construct a statistical test that would clearly indicate whether or not the observed differences in performance could be linked to differences in risk aversion across genders. 47 E. Are Women Potentially Less Competitive than Men?</p><p>As already mentioned, a striking result of our study is the reversal of the performance gender gap at the HEC admission exam ðan elimination-type tournamentÞ compared to the French baccalaure´at ða pass-or-fail examÞ, even though the academic content of both exams is similar. For the driver of these results to be women's underperformance in relatively more competitive environments, we should observe, during the first year of HEC, a pattern that is similar to that of the baccalaure´at. As a matter of fact, this is what we observe, albeit only for the nonmathematics-oriented courses, when we look at the GPA or individual course letter grades in our "everything but the kitchen sink" regressions presented in table 11. Note that many ðbut not allÞ courses at HEC are based on a curve system, whose resulting letter grade distribution could be a priori known by the students. So, we do not claim that there is no competitive pressure during HEC's first year. Instead we only suggest that once students are admitted to the school, this pressure is much lower than that prevailing during the school's entrance exam.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>VII. Conclusion</head><p>Using a unique database, we analyze gender differences in performance in a two-round elimination-type tournament: the admission exams to HEC Paris's MSc in Management. Given that this program is ranked first in Europe in its category and given the important differences in salary upon graduation, payoffs at stake are very high for the candidates we examine. We find that men perform better than women in this competitive exam despite the fact that, for the same cohorts of candidates, the women performed significantly better at an earlier pass/fail type of exam ðthe national baccalaure´at examÞ and, once admitted, during the less competitive first year of their studies at HEC, though our evidence, which is limited to nonmathematics-oriented courses, is somewhat weaker in the latter case. While during the entrance exam men perform better than women among the top 10% of the applicant pool ði.e., those who are eventually admitted to the schoolÞ, there is no statistically significant gender difference in performance as far as the bottom 10% is concerned. The general picture is then that of a larger dispersion of performances among men.</p><p>Consistent with earlier experimental studies, our results, which are based on real-world data, indicate that the competitive aspect of the contest may lead to differences in performance across genders. This in turn has implications for the successful pool of candidates, which ends up containing more males than females.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="16,80.96,68.23,312.11,199.24"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Structure of the HEC Admission Exam</figDesc><table coords="16,80.96,68.23,312.11,199.24">Written Exam 
ðFirst StageÞ 

Oral Exam 
ðSecond StageÞ 

Duration Coefficient 
Duration 
Coefficient 

Common exams: 
French 
3 hours 
3 
1st foreign language 
4 hours 
4 
15 minutes 
4 
2nd foreign language 
3 hours 
2 
15 minutes 
3 
General culture 
20 minutes 
6 
Debate 
40 minutes 
6 
Exams specific to the science track: 
General culture 
4 hours 
4 
Mathematics 1 
4 hours 
6 
30 minutes 
9 
Mathematics 2 
4 hours 
5 
History and geography 
4 hours 
6 
20 minutes 
8 

Total 
30 
36 

458 
Ors et al. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="19,80.96,68.23,312.01,536.21"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>and Castellan ½1988, 38-44Þ. First, we test the null hypothesis ðH 1 0 Þ that the observed proportion of females is equal to 50%. a smaller number of credit hours ðhence fewer ECTS creditsÞ. As a result, we cannot make meaningful comparisons of first-year performance for 2005 and 2006 cohorts with that of 2007. Descriptive Statistics for Gender Compositions and Control Variables NOTE.-Under gender composition, five hypotheses are tested using two-tailed tests for which the z-statistics are provided. First, we test for the equality of the estimated proportions of females ðPrðFÞÞ to .5000 for the sample of candidates, admissibles, and admitted ði.e., H 1 where i denotes the sample of candidates, admissibles, or admittedÞ. Second, we test for the equality of the estimated proportions of females and males in a given sample ði.e., H 2candidates, admissibles, or admittedÞ. Third, we test for the equality of the estimated proportions of females for the candidates with that for the admissibles ði.e., H 3 0Þ. Fourth, we test for the equality of the estimated proportions of females for the admissibles with that for the admitted ði.e., H 4 0Þ. Fifth, we test for the equality of the estimated proportions of females for the admitted with that for the candidates ði.e., H 5</figDesc><table coords="19,80.96,68.23,100.45,9.19">Performance Gender Gap Table 2 
Candidates ðWritten 

Exam SampleÞ 

Admissibles ðOral 
Exam SampleÞ 

Admitted 

Male 

Female 

z-Statistic 

Male 

Female 

z-Statistic 

Male 

Female 

z-Statistic 

Gender composition: PrðXÞ 

.5084 

.4916 

.5368 

.4632 

.5408 

.4592 

ð2,920Þ 

ð2,823Þ 

ð 
737Þ 

ð 
636Þ 

ð 
398Þ 

ð 
338Þ 

H 1 
0 : PrðF 

i Þ 

2 
.5000 5 

0 

21.2800 

22.7258*** 

22.2116** 

½.2006 

½ 
.0064 

½ 
.0270 

H 2 
0 : PrðF 

i Þ 

2 

PrðM 
i Þ 

5 

0 

21.8102* 

23.8548*** 

23.1277*** 

½.0703 

½ 
.0001 

½ 
.0018 

H 3 
0 : PrðF 

candidates Þ 

2 

PrðF 
admissibles Þ 

5 

0 

1.8872* 
½.0591 

H 4 
0 : PrðF 

admissibles Þ 

2 

PrðF 
admitted Þ 

5 

0 

.1748 
½.8613 

H 5 
0 : PrðF 

admitted Þ 

2 

PrðF 
candidates Þ 

5 

0 

21.6513* 
½.0987 

Baccalaure´at honors ð/4Þ: 
Science majors 

2.69 

2.98 

f212.72g*** 

3.13 

3.43 

f27.88g*** 

3.29 

3.58 

f26.15g*** 

ð2,911Þ 

ð2,819Þ 

½ 

.0000 

ð 
735Þ 

ð 
635Þ 

½ 
.0000 

ð 
396Þ 

ð 
338Þ 

½ 
.000 

Mathematics submajors 

2.72 

2.99 

f210.62g*** 

3.14 

3.41 

f26.49g*** 

3.28 

3.58 

f25.57g*** 

ð2,070Þ 

ð1,958Þ 

½ 

.0000 

ð 
575Þ 

ð 
497Þ 

½ 
.0000 

ð 
321Þ 

ð 
266Þ 

½ 
.0000 

Physics and chemistry submajors 

2.62 

2.92 

f25.21g*** 

3.09 

3.49 

f23.32g*** 

3.39 

3.51 

f2.71g 

ð427Þ 

ð 

447Þ 

½ 

.0000 

ð 
77Þ 

ð 
59Þ 

½ 
.0012 

ð 

28Þ 

ð 
35Þ 

½ 
.4799 

Life sciences submajors 

2.67 

2.96 

f24.60g*** 

3.11 

3.44 

f22.69g*** 

3.28 

3.65 

f22.40g** 

ð351Þ 

ð 

368Þ 

½ 

.0000 

ð 
72Þ 

ð 
68Þ 

½ 
.0081 

ð 

40Þ 

ð 
31Þ 

½ 
.0193 

Science prep school rank 

27.62 

24.75 

f4.99g*** 

14.21 

12.93 

f1.80g* 

11.53 

10.36 

f1.41g 

ð2,746Þ 

ð2,656Þ 

½ 

.0000 

ð 
718Þ 

ð 
616Þ 

½ 
.0722 

ð 
391Þ 

ð 
327Þ 

½ 
.1584 

Non-French nationals ð%Þ 

5.92 

9.03 

f24.48g*** 

4.75 

8.81 

f22.96g*** 

5.53 

9.47 

f22.01g** 

ð2,920Þ 

ð2,823Þ 

½ 

.0000 

ð 
737Þ 

ð 
636Þ 

½ 
.0032 

ð 
398Þ 

ð 
338Þ 

½ 
.0453 

0 : 

PrðF 
i Þ 

5 
.5000, 0 : PrðF 

i Þ 

2 

PrðM 
i Þ 

5 
0, where i denotes the sample of 

0 : PrðF 

candidates Þ 

2 

PrðF 
admissibles Þ 

5 
0 : PrðF 

admissibles Þ 

2 

PrðF 
admitted Þ 

5 
0 : PrðF 

admitted Þ 

2 

PrðF 
candidates Þ 

5 

0Þ. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="21,81.07,516.99,312.00,99.63"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>27 The proportion of science track female candidates in our sample is higher than that observed in the comparable population of students in the final year of high school: in the 2003 ð2004, 2005Þ cohorts of high school science majors that correspond to the cohorts of candidates in our sample, of the 159,673 ð156,814, 161,396Þ students who sat for the science track baccalaure´at exam, 44.6% ð44.7%, 45.2%Þ were female. Of the 135,374 ð130,225, 136,877Þ students who succeeded and obtained a science major baccalaure´at diploma in 2003 ð2004, 2005Þ, 46.2% ð46.3%, 46.6%Þ were female ðhttp://www.education.gouv.fr/statevalÞ. 28 Unfortunately, we do not have the candidates' average baccalaure´at grades, which would have permitted more precise tests.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="24,80.96,68.23,312.11,556.14"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Gender Composition of Candidates with a Science Baccalaure´at by Submajor in High SchoolNOTE.-This table provides information on the gender composition for the 5,730 candidates with a science background that form the main sample by submajors that they have chosen in high school. In cols. 1, 2, and 4, numbers in parentheses are percentages with respect to the total at the bottom of each column, whereas the numbers in brackets are percentages with respect to the submajor total on the left of each row; in col. 3, numbers in parentheses and brackets are the corresponding two-tailed binomial test statistics for the null hypothesis that col. 1 minus col. 2 difference equals zero.</figDesc><table coords="24,80.96,329.54,312.08,294.82">High School Science Major 
by Submajor 

Number 
of Males 
ð1Þ 

Number of 
Females 
ð2Þ 

H 0 : 
PrðMaleÞ 2 
PrðFemaleÞ 5 0 
ð3Þ 

Submajor 
Total 
ð4Þ 

Mathematics 
2,070 
1,958 
4,028 
ð71.11Þ 
ð69.46Þ 
ð 1.3684Þ 
ð 70.30Þ 
½51.39 
½ 48.61 
½ 2.4957** 
Physics and chemistry 
427 
447 
874 
ð14.67Þ 
ð15.86Þ 
ð21.2507Þ 
ð 15.25Þ 
½48.86 
½ 51.14 
½ 2.9567 
Life sciences ðbiology and geologyÞ 
351 
368 
719 
ð12.06Þ 
ð13.05Þ 
ð21.1385Þ 
ð 12.55Þ 
½48.82 
½ 51.12 
½ 2.8966 
Engineering and agronomy 
47 
16 
63 
ð1.61Þ 
ð .57Þ 
ð 3.7996Þ*** 
ð1.12Þ 
½74.60 
½ 25.40 
½ 5.5234*** 
Other majors in science track in 
admission exam 
16 
30 
46 
ð.55Þ 
ð 1.06Þ 
ð22.1821Þ** 
ð.78Þ 
½34.78 
½ 65.22 
½ 22.9192*** 

Total 
2,911 
2,819 
5,730 
ð100.00Þ 
ð100.00Þ 
ð 100.00Þ 

* p &lt; .10. 
** p &lt; .05. 
*** p &lt; .01. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="27,86.78,83.29,299.08,531.20"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Descriptive Statistics on HEC Entrance Exam Performance NOTE.-All tests are two-tailed. The null hypothesis for the nonparametric median test is the equality of the medians across genders. The null hypothesis for the t-test is the equality of the means across genders allowing for unequal variances. The Wilcoxon-Mann-Whitney ðWMWÞ rank-sum test is the nonparametric equivalent of the t-test. The null hypothesis for the variance test is that the ratio of variances is equal to one. The null hypothesis for the nonparametric Kolmogorov-Smirnov ðKSÞ test is the equality of distributions.</figDesc><table coords="27,110.99,83.29,274.87,531.20">C. Written Exam 

D. Oral Exam 

A. Written Exam: 
Overall Grade 

B. Oral Exam: 
Overall Grade 

Math Exam 

Nonmath Exams 

Math Exam 

Nonmath Exams 

Male 

Female 

Male 

Female 

Male 

Female 

Male 

Female 

Male 

Female 

Male 

Female 

Observations 

2,889 

2,810 

735 

636 

2,889 

2,810 

2,889 

2,810 

735 

636 

735 

636 

Median 

10.69 

10.52 

10.69 

10.54 

10.79 

10.30 

10.49 

10.54 

10.00 

10.00 

11.48 

11.52 

Median test 

3.79** 

1.50 

9.53*** 

.36 

1.79 

.01 

Mean 

10.66 

10.58 

10.70 

10.56 

10.92 

10.58 

10.52 

10.58 

10.47 

9.93 

11.64 

11.64 

t-test 

1.28 

1.31 

3.01*** 

21.26 

2.62*** 

.05 

WMW rank-sum test 

1.64* 

1.19 

3.04*** 

2.66 

2.27** 

.02 

KS test ðD-statisticÞ 

.04* 

.06 

.05*** 

.03* 

.05 

.04 

1st percentile 

4.76 

5.66 

6.47 

6.33 

1.83 

2.27 

5.56 

6.07 

3.00 

1.00 

6.84 

6.92 

5th percentile 

6.62 

6.98 

7.36 

7.47 

3.69 

4.02 

6.94 

7.40 

4.00 

4.00 

7.92 

8.16 

10th percentile 

7.38 

7.61 

8.14 

8.15 

5.00 

5.40 

7.69 

8.09 

6.00 

5.00 

8.48 

8.76 

25th percentile 

8.87 

8.90 

9.22 

9.22 

7.71 

7.55 

9.04 

9.18 

8.00 

7.00 

9.92 

10.08 

50th percentile 

10.69 

10.52 

10.69 

10.54 

10.79 

10.30 

10.49 

10.54 

10.00 

10.00 

11.48 

11.52 

75th percentile 

12.42 

12.20 

12.03 

11.86 

14.15 

13.55 

11.99 

12.00 

13.00 

13.00 

13.40 

13.32 

90th percentile 

13.88 

13.61 

13.36 

13.08 

17.06 

16.24 

13.33 

13.21 

16.00 

15.00 

14.88 

14.56 

95th percentile 

14.76 

14.33 

14.08 

13.86 

18.47 

17.75 

13.93 

14.00 

17.00 

16.00 

15.56 

15.32 

99th percentile 

16.03 

15.78 

15.42 

14.94 

20.00 

19.68 

15.12 

15.19 

19.00 

18.00 

17.04 

16.64 

Standard deviation 

2.49 

2.28 

2.03 

1.91 

4.41 

4.09 

2.13 

2.00 

3.90 

3.76 

2.37 

2.22 

Variance test 

1.19*** 

1.13 

1.16*** 

1.14*** 

1.08 

1.15* 

* p &lt; 

.10. 

** p &lt; 

.05. 

*** p &lt; 

.01. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" coords="30,80.96,91.83,311.99,518.81"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Tests of First-Order Stochastic Dominance</figDesc><table coords="30,257.22,114.80,127.99,25.96">H 0 : 
FðxÞ ≤ MðxÞ 
ð1Þ 

H 

0 

0 : 
MðxÞ ≤ FðxÞ 
ð2Þ 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" coords="31,80.96,89.20,312.01,275.11"><head>Table 5 (</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Continued ) NOTE.-This table presents the results of ðweakÞ first-order stochastic dominance ðFOSDÞ tests of Barrett and Donald ð2003Þ. H 0 : FðxÞ ≤ MðxÞ ðH 0 0 : MðxÞ ≤ FðxÞÞ corresponds to the null hypothesis that females' ðmales'Þ performance weakly first-order stochastically dominates that of males ðfemalesÞ. A rejection of H 0 combined with a failure to reject H 0 0 suggests that males' performance dominates that of females in an FOSD sense. p-values are provided below test statistics within parentheses; sample sizes are within brackets. GAUSS codes for the FOSD tests are obtained from http://www.economics.unsw.edu .au/GarryBarrett. * p &lt; .10. ** p &lt; .05. *** p &lt; .01.</figDesc><table coords="31,257.22,102.78,127.99,25.90">H 0 : 
FðxÞ ≤ MðxÞ 
ð1Þ 

H 

0 

0 : 
MðxÞ ≤ FðxÞ 
ð2Þ 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" coords="31,80.96,68.23,314.01,560.68"><head>Table 5 (</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Continued )    reversed for nonmathematics-related exams. Once the selection is made and</figDesc><table coords="31,80.96,68.23,311.99,9.19">Performance Gender Gap 
473 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8" coords="34,76.80,85.84,348.00,530.36"><head>Table 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Performance in the Written Exam ðFirst NOTE.-This table presents quantile regression models that are simultaneously estimated, where the dependent variable is the weighted average of written exam grades, with subject matter weights as detailed in table 1. Indicator variables are preceded by the prefix D _ . The regression model includes prep school fixed effects ðnot</figDesc><table coords="34,86.27,85.84,338.53,530.36">Stage of the Entrance ExamÞ 

Percentile 

10th 

25th 

50th 

75th 

90th 

Constant 

3.6483*** 

3.9600*** 

5.1538*** 

6.6423*** 

8.5749*** 

ð.4635Þ 

ð 
.3744Þ 

ð 

.4994Þ 

ð 
.4828Þ 

ð 

.7569Þ 

D _ 

2006 

.7593*** 

.8100*** 

.7954*** 

.8033*** 

.8004*** 

ð.1027Þ 

ð 
.0827Þ 

ð 

.0820Þ 

ð 
.0962Þ 

ð 

.1138Þ 

D _ 

2007 

.8300*** 

.9200*** 

.9799*** 

1.0180*** 

.9404*** 

ð.1084Þ 

ð 
.0876Þ 

ð 

.0794Þ 

ð 
.0927Þ 

ð 

.1176Þ 

D _ 

female 

2.1357 

2.2562*** 

2.3488*** 

2.5153*** 

2.6646*** 

ð.0873Þ 

ð 
.0728Þ 

ð 

.0634Þ 

ð 
.0767Þ 

ð 

.0940Þ 

D _ 

non-French 

2.4823*** 

2.4105** 

2.4711*** 

2.2937 

2.2448 

ð.1845Þ 

ð 
.1618Þ 

ð 

.1342Þ 

ð 
.1875Þ 

ð 

.2558Þ 

D _ 

mathematics _ 

submajor 

.6330* 

.4835 

.1546 

.1080 

.3444 

ð.3361Þ 

ð 
.2955Þ 

ð 

.2869Þ 

ð 
.2743Þ 

ð 

.2112Þ 

D _ 

physics _ 

and _ 

chemistry _ 

submajor 

.1960 

.0852 

2.3354 

2.4367 

2.1567 

ð.3533Þ 

ð 
.3044Þ 

ð 

.2957Þ 

ð 
.2819Þ 

ð 

.2388Þ 

D _ 

life _ 

sciences _ 

submajor 

.2297 

.0625 

2.1342 

2.0700 

.0678 

ð.3566Þ 

ð 
.3098Þ 

ð 

.2995Þ 

ð 
.2861Þ 

ð 

.2493Þ 

D _ 

cum _ 

laude 

.5747*** 

.8833*** 

.8994*** 

.8223*** 

.7611*** 

ð.1922Þ 

ð 
.1343Þ 

ð 

.1759Þ 

ð 
.1912Þ 

ð 

.2175Þ 

D _ 

magna _ 

cum _ 

laude 

1.2200*** 

1.5917*** 

1.5976*** 

1.4490*** 

1.5257*** 

ð.1880Þ 

ð 
.1374Þ 

ð 

.1822Þ 

ð 
.1950Þ 

ð 

.2239Þ 

D _ 

summa _ 

cum _ 

laude 

2.1303*** 

2.5487*** 

2.5888*** 

2.3780*** 

2.5923*** 

ð.2128Þ 

ð 
.1587Þ 

ð 

.1929Þ 

ð 
.2094Þ 

ð 

.2455Þ 

Prep school fixed effects 

Yes 

Observations 

5,635 

Pseudo-R 2 

.2594 

.2609 

.2652 

.2499 

.2420 

reportedÞ. Bootstrap 

standard errors ðpresented 
within parentheses below the coefficient estimatesÞ are obtained with 5,000 replications. 

* p &lt; 

.10. 

** p &lt; 

.05. 

*** p &lt; 

.01. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9" coords="37,75.78,85.56,325.55,528.42"><head>Table 7</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Performance in the Written Mathematics Exams</figDesc><table coords="37,99.99,85.56,301.34,528.42">Percentile 

10th 

25th 

50th 

75th 

90th 

Constant 

2.8088 

2.0401 

2.3261*** 

5.2027*** 

7.5724*** 

ð.5593Þ 

ð 
.6712Þ 

ð 
.8132Þ 

ð 
1.1866Þ 

ð 
1.1572Þ 

D _ 

2006 

1.0891*** 

1.1576*** 

1.2403*** 

.9194*** 

.8625*** 

ð.1795Þ 

ð 
.1479Þ 

ð 
.1587Þ 

ð 

.1854Þ 

ð 

.1957Þ 

D _ 

2007 

1.0900*** 

1.4165*** 

1.6309*** 

1.4416*** 

1.4384*** 

ð.2031Þ 

ð 
.1541Þ 

ð 
.1541Þ 

ð 

.1954Þ 

ð 

.2189Þ 

D _ 

female 

2.1267 

2.3877*** 

2.7830*** 

21.1051*** 

21.2504*** 

ð.1520Þ 

ð 
.1214Þ 

ð 
.1248Þ 

ð 

.1301Þ 

ð 

.1573Þ 

D _ 

non-French 

2.6639* 

2.5846** 

2.7109** 

2.3524 

2.1439 

ð.3487Þ 

ð 
.2981Þ 

ð 
.3208Þ 

ð 

.3735Þ 

ð 

.3191Þ 

D _ 

mathematics _ 

submajor 

.7358* 

.6159 

.2136 

2.2579 

.1739 

ð.3836Þ 

ð 
.4654Þ 

ð 
.5853Þ 

ð 

.5936Þ 

ð 

.5080Þ 

D _ 

physics _ 

and _ 

chemistry _ 

submajor 

2.1458 

2.5297 

2.8336 

21.7625*** 

21.3622** 

ð.4175Þ 

ð 
.4719Þ 

ð 
.6034Þ 

ð 

.6113Þ 

ð 

.5467Þ 

D _ 

life _ 

sciences _ 

submajor 

2.4824 

2.4699 

2.5485 

2.9803 

2.7027 

ð.4104Þ 

ð 
.4817Þ 

ð 
.6119Þ 

ð 

.6140Þ 

ð 

.5353Þ 

D _ 

cum _ 

laude 

.9830*** 

1.3456*** 

1.3230*** 

1.4089*** 

1.3260*** 

ð.3189Þ 

ð 
.2576Þ 

ð 
.2790Þ 

ð 

.3290Þ 

ð 

.4245Þ 

D _ 

magna _ 

cum _ 

laude 

2.0470*** 

2.5822*** 

2.4788*** 

2.5501*** 

2.5019*** 

ð.3290Þ 

ð 
.2583Þ 

ð 
.2961Þ 

ð 

.3418Þ 

ð 

.4422Þ 

D _ 

summa _ 

cum _ 

laude 

3.3097*** 

3.7271*** 

3.8791*** 

4.0954*** 

3.8859*** 

ð.3642Þ 

ð 
.2849Þ 

ð 
.3317Þ 

ð 

.3693Þ 

ð 

.4690Þ 

Prep school fixed effects 

Yes 

Observations 

5,635 

Pseudo-R 2 

.2107 

.2180 

.2248 

.2321 

.2227 

NOTE.-This table presents quantile regression models that are simultaneously estimated, where the dependent variable is the weighted average of written mathematics exam 

grades ðof 
which there are twoÞ, with subject matter weights as detailed in table 1. Indicator variables are preceded by the prefix D _ 

. The regression model includes prep school 

fixed effects ðnot 
reportedÞ. Bootstrap standard errors ðpresented 
within parentheses below the coefficient estimatesÞ are obtained with 5,000 replications. 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10" coords="38,77.77,84.51,348.06,529.48"><head>Table 8</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Performance in the Written Nonmathematics Exams</figDesc><table coords="38,101.98,84.51,323.85,529.48">Percentile 

10th 

25th 

50th 

75th 

90th 

Constant 

4.8968*** 

5.7095*** 

6.9189*** 

8.4358*** 

10.3874*** 

ð.4872Þ 

ð 
.3897Þ 

ð 
.4424Þ 

ð 
.5012Þ 

ð 
.7809Þ 

D _ 

2006 

.4211*** 

.5916*** 

.5916*** 

.5568*** 

.5137*** 

ð.0995Þ 

ð 
.0812Þ 

ð 
.0808Þ 

ð 
.0910Þ 

ð 
.1128Þ 

D _ 

2007 

.6800*** 

.6723*** 

.6916*** 

.5874*** 

.4653*** 

ð.1016Þ 

ð 
.0821Þ 

ð 
.0831Þ 

ð 
.0852Þ 

ð 
.1069Þ 

D _ 

female 

2.0632 

2.1453** 

2.2242*** 

2.2747*** 

2.2968*** 

ð.0855Þ 

ð 
.0693Þ 

ð 
.0694Þ 

ð 
.0696Þ 

ð 
.0911Þ 

D _ 

non-French 

2.3663** 

2.3874*** 

2.3337** 

2.2168 

2.1789 

ð.1866Þ 

ð 
.1341Þ 

ð 
.1529Þ 

ð 
.1633Þ 

ð 
.2097Þ 

D _ 

mathematics _ 

submajor 

.4947* 

.5067** 

.3716 

.0926 

2.3137 

ð.2988Þ 

ð 
.2480Þ 

ð 
.3219Þ 

ð 
.3357Þ 

ð 
.4270Þ 

D _ 

physics _ 

and _ 

chemistry _ 

submajor 

.4547 

.4407* 

.2853 

2.0232 

2.3895 

ð.3203Þ 

ð 
.2604Þ 

ð 
.3318Þ 

ð 
.3439Þ 

ð 
.4341Þ 

D _ 

life _ 

sciences _ 

submajor 

.4274 

.5782** 

.4789 

.1232 

2.2400 

ð.3269Þ 

ð 
.2636Þ 

ð 
.3304Þ 

ð 
.3467Þ 

ð 
.4390Þ 

D _ 

cum _ 

laude 

.4211** 

.5860*** 

.6642*** 

.5305*** 

.2737 

ð.1641Þ 

ð 
.1310Þ 

ð 
.1419Þ 

ð 
.2031Þ 

ð 
.2127Þ 

D _ 

magna _ 

cum _ 

laude 

.7347*** 

.9249*** 

1.0347*** 

.9453*** 

.7705*** 

ð.1736Þ 

ð 
.1339Þ 

ð 
.1430Þ 

ð 
.2040Þ 

ð 
.2122Þ 

D _ 

summa _ 

cum _ 

laude 

1.3663*** 

1.7312*** 

1.9011*** 

1.8411*** 

1.5368*** 

ð.2001Þ 

ð 
.1539Þ 

ð 
.1599Þ 

ð 
.2119Þ 

ð 
.2316Þ 

Prep school fixed effects 

Yes 

Observations 

5,635 

Pseudo-R 2 

.1886 

.1715 

.1653 

.1565 

.1438 

NOTE.-This table presents quantile regression models that are simultaneously estimated, where the dependent variable is the weighted average of written nonmathematics exam 

grades, with subject matter weights as detailed in table 1. Indicator variables are preceded by the prefix D _ 

. The regression model includes prep school fixed effects ðnot 

reportedÞ. 

Bootstrap standard errors ðpresented 
within parentheses below the coefficient estimatesÞ are obtained with 5,000 replications. 

* p &lt; 

.10. 

** p &lt; 

.05. 

*** p &lt; 

.01. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11" coords="42,85.82,85.71,305.81,527.14"><head>Table 9</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Performance in the Oral Exam Stage ðSecond</figDesc><table coords="42,95.29,85.71,296.34,527.14">Stage of the Entrance ExamÞ 

Oral Exams' Weighted Average 

Oral Math Exam Score 

Oral Nonmath Exams' 
Weighted Average 

25th 
ð1Þ 

50th 
ð2Þ 

75th 
ð3Þ 

25th 
ð4Þ 

50th 
ð5Þ 

75th 
ð6Þ 

25th 
ð7Þ 

50th 
ð8Þ 

75th 
ð9Þ 

Constant 

.1519 

3.2684 

.9274 

25.3016 

2.6698 

5.0089 

2.8097 

2.5187 

4.5078 

ð3.9768Þ 

ð3.4318Þ 

ð3.4665Þ 

ð6.8063Þ 

ð7.2069Þ 

ð 
2.10e115Þ ð4.8357Þ 

ð4.8375Þ ð4.6549Þ 

D _ 

2006 
2.5110*** 2.5887*** 2.5470*** 2.7120* 

2.8320** 

2.8269 
2.5297** 2.4374* 2.4897** 

ð.1884Þ 

ð 
.1837Þ 

ð 
.1993Þ 

ð 
.3637Þ 

ð 
.3480Þ 

ð36.4133Þ 

ð 
.2082Þ 

ð 
.2247Þ 

ð.2377Þ 

D _ 

2007 
2.9577*** 2.9107*** 2.8060*** 22.3084*** 22.0342*** 21.8457 

2.4977** 2.5996** 2.5484** 

ð.2020Þ 

ð 
.1837Þ 

ð 
.2074Þ 

ð 
.3657Þ 

ð 
.3982Þ 

ð 
4.7525Þ 

ð 
.2241Þ 

ð 
.2530Þ 

ð.2370Þ 

D _ 

female 

2.2052 

2.2036 

2.2780* 

2.7340** 

2.2992 

2.2679 

2.0383 

2.1632 

2.3574** 

ð.1430Þ 

ð 
.1417Þ 

ð 
.1641Þ 

ð 
.3021Þ 

ð 
.2798Þ 

ð34.1885Þ 

ð 
.1688Þ 

ð 
.1707Þ 

ð.1791Þ 

D _ 

non-French 

.4425 

2.0943 

.0316 

.3879 

.4438 

.4932 

.1384 

2.3831 

2.1497 

ð.3320Þ 

ð 
.3107Þ 

ð 
.3549Þ 

ð 
.6645Þ 

ð 
.7756Þ 

ð27.8762Þ 

ð 
.3331Þ 

ð 
.3987Þ 

ð.4210Þ 

D _ 

mathematics _ 

submajor 

.0932 

2.3686 

.2601 

.6507 

1.0308 

.0695 

.3399 

2.9109 

2.1752 

ð.9696Þ 

ð 
.5967Þ 

ð 
.6388Þ 

ð 
.9632Þ 

ð1.3325Þ 

ð 
2.10e115Þ ð1.0444Þ 

ð1.0622Þ 

ð.6540Þ 

D _ 

physics _ 

and _ 

chemistry _ 
submajor 2.0477 

2.5339 

.1168 

.6600 

.3537 

21.1585 

.3623 

2.5828 

.0683 

ð.9921Þ 

ð 
.6394Þ 

ð 
.6758Þ 

ð1.0164Þ 

ð1.3743Þ 

ð 
2.10e115Þ ð1.0751Þ 

ð1.0930Þ 

ð.7008Þ 

D _ 

life _ 

sciences _ 

submajor 

.2008 

2.2870 

.1338 

.2340 

.4914 

21.0325 

.7217 

2.7348 

.0016 

ð.9890Þ 

ð 
.6187Þ 

ð 
.6634Þ 

ð1.0604Þ 

ð1.3797Þ 

ð 
2.10e115Þ ð1.0686Þ 

ð1.0794Þ 

ð.6841Þ 

D _ 

cum _ 

laude 

2.0343 

2.7193 

2.6550 

1.1421 

2.6792 

23.0924 

.3431 

2.4871 

2.1984 

ð.8094Þ 

ð 
.5871Þ 

ð 
.7258Þ 

ð1.7636Þ 

ð2.1715Þ 

ð21.6885Þ 

ð 
.7052Þ 

ð 
.7095Þ 

ð.7588Þ 

D _ 

magna _ 

cum _ 

laude 

.0021 

2.2616 

.0342 

1.5505 

.4018 

22.2778 

.4463 

2.1914 

.4890 

ð.8088Þ 

ð 
.5845Þ 

ð 
.7253Þ 

ð1.7608Þ 

ð2.1593Þ 

ð 
8.7715Þ 

ð 
.6731Þ 

ð 
.7154Þ 

ð.7445Þ 

D _ 

summa _ 

cum _ 

laude 

.3631 

.0966 

.3020 

2.0534 

.6911 

21.6610 

.7539 

.1741 

.6758 

ð.8215Þ 

ð 
.5967Þ 

ð 
.7465Þ 

ð1.7920Þ 

ð2.1743Þ 

ð47.5180Þ 

ð 
.6915Þ 

ð 
.7341Þ 

ð.7463Þ 

1st _ 

foreign _ 

language 

.3710 

.2676 

.3643 

2.3129 

2.1552 

2.3660 

.7044*** 

.6671** 

.8288*** 

ð.2587Þ 

ð 
.2280Þ 

ð 
.2892Þ 

ð 
.4622Þ 

ð 
.4968Þ 

ð 
7.0348Þ 

ð 
.2595Þ 

ð 
.2735Þ 

ð.2901Þ 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12" coords="44,85.82,84.98,292.74,529.01"><head>Table 10</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Performance in the Baccalaure´at: Linear Probability Models NOTE.-This table presents linear probability model estimates for the probability of obtaining the baccalaure´at with at least a certain level of honors. In cols. 1 and 4 the dependent variable is equal to one if the student has obtained the baccalaure´at diploma with at least cum laude ði.e., with cum laude, magna cum laude, or summa cum laudeÞ or zero if the student obtained the high school diploma with a simple pass ðno honorsÞ. In cols. 2 and 5 the dependent variable is equal to one if the student has obtained the baccalaure´at diploma with at least magna cum laude ði.e.,</figDesc><table coords="44,110.21,85.02,268.35,528.97">At Least 
Cum Laude 
ð1Þ 

At Least 
Magna Cum 
Laude 
ð2Þ 

At Least 
Summa Cum 
Laude 
ð3Þ 

At Least 
Cum Laude 
ð4Þ 

At Least 
Magna Cum 
Laude 
ð5Þ 

At Least 
Summa Cum 
Laude 
ð6Þ 

Constant 

.9062*** 

.8593*** 

.6147*** 

.9338*** 

.9154*** 

.8550*** 

ð.0250Þ 

ð 

.0362Þ 

ð 

.0886Þ 

ð 
.0414Þ 

ð 

.0486Þ 

ð 

.1012Þ 

D _ 

2006 

.0184** 

.0274** 

.0947*** 

.0170** 

.0216** 

.0592*** 

ð.0081Þ 

ð 

.0109Þ 

ð 

.0253Þ 

ð 
.0075Þ 

ð 

.0090Þ 

ð 

.0175Þ 

D _ 

2007 

.0115 

.0191* 

.0636** 

.0158** 

.0219** 

.0454** 

ð.0082Þ 

ð 

.0111Þ 

ð 

.0259Þ 

ð 
.0076Þ 

ð 

.0093Þ 

ð 

.0190Þ 

D _ 

female 

.0503*** 

.0782*** 

.2129*** 

.0328*** 

.0496*** 

.1034*** 

ð.0064Þ 

ð 

.0088Þ 

ð 

.0203Þ 

ð 
.0060Þ 

ð 

.0074Þ 

ð 

.0150Þ 

D _ 

non-French 

2.0163 

2.0304 

2.1237*** 

.0134 

.0018 

2.0312 

ð.0132Þ 

ð 

.0186Þ 

ð 

.0467Þ 

ð 
.0145Þ 

ð 

.0164Þ 

ð 

.0298Þ 

D _ 

mathematics _ 

submajor 

2.0014 

.0033 

.0109 

2.0080 

2.0007 

2.0258 

ð.0244Þ 

ð 

.0356Þ 

ð 

.0869Þ 

ð 
.0232Þ 

ð 

.0299Þ 

ð 

.0715Þ 

D _ 

physics _ 

and _ 

chemistry _ 

submajor 

2.0102 

2.0126 

2.0412 

.0099 

.0229 

2.0111 

ð.0256Þ 

ð 

.0371Þ 

ð 

.0906Þ 

ð 
.0242Þ 

ð 

.0314Þ 

ð 

.0739Þ 

D _ 

life _ 

sciences _ 

submajor 

2.0056 

2.0045 

.0054 

.0048 

.0097 

.0456 

ð.0259Þ 

ð 

.0374Þ 

ð 

.0904Þ 

ð 
.0242Þ 

ð 

.0311Þ 

ð 

.0744Þ 

Prep school fixed effects 

No 

No 

No 

Yes 

Yes 

Yes 

Observations 

5,635 

4,140 

1,621 

5,635 

4,140 

1,621 

Adjusted R 2 

.0105 

.0199 

.0742 

.1647 

.3382 

.6037 

F-statistic 

9.56*** 

12.98*** 

19.56*** 

10.42*** 

19.39*** 

24.96*** 

with magna cum laude or summa cum laudeÞ or zero if the 

student obtained the high school diploma with a simple pass ðno 
honorsÞ; those who obtained cum laude are excluded. In cols. 3 and 6 the dependent variable ðat 

least summa cum laudeÞ is equal to one if the 

student has obtained the baccalaure´at diploma with at least summa cum laude or zero if the student obtained the high school diploma with a simple pass ðno 

honorsÞ; those who have obtained cum laude or magna 

cum laude are excluded. Linear probability models in cols. 4-6 include prep school fixed effects. Heteroskedasticity-consistent ði.e., 

robustÞ standard errors are reported within parentheses below the coefficient 

estimates. 

* p &lt; 

.10. 

** p &lt; 

.05. 

*** p &lt; 

.01. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_13" coords="48,66.77,84.18,342.88,528.67"><head>Table 11</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Performance in the First-Year HEC Core Courses NOTE.-This table presents ðiÞ pooled OLS regressions in which the dependent variable is HEC first-year GPA in core courses ðcols.</figDesc><table coords="48,90.98,84.18,318.68,528.67">Grade Point Average ðout 
of 4.00Þ in First-Year Core 
Courses at HEC 

Letter Grades ðout 
of 4.00Þ in First-Year Core 
Courses at HEC 

GPA 
ð1Þ 
GPA for Math-
Oriented Courses 
ð2Þ 
GPA for Nonmath-
Oriented Courses 
ð3Þ 

Letter 
Grades 
ð4Þ 

Letter Grades 
for Math-
Oriented Courses 
ð5Þ 

Letter Grades 
for Nonmath-
Oriented Courses 
ð6Þ 

Constant 

21.0150 

21.3955 

2.7819 

.2580 

2.7180 

.7132 

ð1.6890Þ 

ð 
2.1157Þ 

ð 
1.7479Þ 

ð 
1.4516Þ 

ð 
1.7071Þ 

ð 
1.5369Þ 

D _ 

2006 

2.1564** 

2.1557* 

2.1720*** 

2.8172*** 

2.3522 

2.5119** 

ð.0635Þ 

ð 

.0795Þ 

ð 
.0657Þ 

ð 
.2659Þ 

ð 
.2273Þ 

ð 
.2151Þ 

D _ 

female 

.0342 

2.1118 

.1521** 

.0420 

2.0942 

.1506*** 

ð.0601Þ 

ð 

.0752Þ 

ð 
.0621Þ 

ð 
.0498Þ 

ð 
.0608Þ 

ð 
.0538Þ 

D _ 

non-French 

2.0669 

.0749 

2.2102 

2.0441 

.0146 

2.1481 

ð.1315Þ 

ð 

.1647Þ 

ð 
.1360Þ 

ð 
.1168Þ 

ð 
.1381Þ 

ð 
.1265Þ 

D _ 

mathematics _ 

submajor 

2.1805 

2.1586 

2.2022 

2.2612 

2.2812 

2.2296 

ð.2261Þ 

ð 

.2832Þ 

ð 
.2340Þ 

ð 
.2185Þ 

ð 
.2187Þ 

ð 
.2397Þ 

D _ 

physics _ 

and _ 

chemistry _ 

submajor 

2.2424 

2.2897 

2.1973 

2.2976 

2.3759 

2.2522 

ð.2434Þ 

ð 

.3048Þ 

ð 
.2518Þ 

ð 
.2352Þ 

ð 
.2425Þ 

ð 
.2564Þ 

D _ 

life _ 

sciences _ 

submajor 

2.1602 

2.1258 

2.2002 

2.2506 

2.2381 

2.2393 

ð.2454Þ 

ð 

.3075Þ 

ð 
.2540Þ 

ð 
.2393Þ 

ð 
.2465Þ 

ð 
.2617Þ 

D _ 

cum _ 

laude 

.1111 

.0687 

.1283 

.0823 

.1205 

.0233 

ð.2481Þ 

ð 

.3107Þ 

ð 
.2567Þ 

ð 
.2002Þ 

ð 
.2892Þ 

ð 
.2010Þ 

D _ 

magna _ 

cum _ 

laude 

.2242 

.1917 

.2360 

.2259 

.2336 

.1937 

ð.2336Þ 

ð 

.2926Þ 

ð 
.2418Þ 

ð 
.1912Þ 

ð 
.2757Þ 

ð 
.1899Þ 

D _ 

summa _ 

cum _ 

laude 

.4645* 

.4238 

.4767* 

.4344** 

.4613 

.3944** 

ð.2403Þ 

ð 

.3010Þ 

ð 
.2487Þ 

ð 
.2010Þ 

ð 
.2872Þ 

ð 
.1997Þ 

1st _ 

foreign _ 
language ðwrittenÞ 

2.2635** 

2.2660* 

2.2694** 

2.2365** 

2.1892* 

2.2966*** 

ð.1176Þ 

ð 

.1473Þ 

ð 
.1217Þ 

ð 
.0994Þ 

ð 
.1147Þ 

ð 
.1079Þ 

1st _ 

foreign _ 

language 2 

ðwrittenÞ 

.0098** 

.0099* 

.0100** 

.0088** 

.0071* 

.0112*** 

ð.0043Þ 

ð 

.0054Þ 

ð 
.0045Þ 

ð 
.0037Þ 

ð 
.0043Þ 

ð 
.0041Þ 

2nd _ 

foreign _ 
language ðwrittenÞ 

.0292 

.0352 

.0205 

.0554 

.0323 

.0525 

ð.1103Þ 

ð 

.1382Þ 

ð 
.1142Þ 

ð 
.1052Þ 

ð 
.1243Þ 

ð 
.1052Þ 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_14" coords="53,136.79,96.70,61.86,515.75"><head>Table 12 Subject</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Weights in the Baccalaure´at Exam</figDesc><table coords="53,160.94,96.70,37.70,515.75">Mathematics Submajor 

ð70.30% 
of the SampleÞ 

Physics and Chemistry 
Submajor 

ð15.25% 
of the SampleÞ 

Life Sciences Submajor 
ð12.55% 
of the SampleÞ 

Science Majors 

Coefficient 

Weight ð%Þ 

Coefficient 

Weight ð%Þ 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_15" coords="54,80.96,295.81,312.00,187.37"><head>Table 14 Subject</head><label>14</label><figDesc>Weights in the HEC First-Year Courses</figDesc><table coords="54,80.96,320.02,312.00,163.17">ECTS Credits 
Weight ð%Þ 

Economics 
5 
11.36 
Finance 
5 
11.36 
Quantitative methods 
2.5 
5.68 
Statistics 
2.5 
5.68 
Supply chain 
5 
11.36 

Math-oriented courses' subtotal 
20 
45.45 
Accounting 
5 
11.36 
English as a 1st foreign language 
2 
4.55 
Business law 
5 
11.36 
Marketing 
5 
11.36 
Modeling with Excel 
2 
4.55 
Theory of organizations 
5 
11.36 
Nonmath-oriented courses' subtotal 
24 
54.55 

Total 
44 
100.00 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_16" coords="54,80.96,68.23,312.11,194.93"><head>Table 13 Subject</head><label>13</label><figDesc>Weights in the HEC Entrance Exam</figDesc><table coords="54,80.96,68.23,312.11,194.93">Writen Exam Stage 
Oral Exam Stage 

Coefficient 
Weight ð%Þ 
Coefficient 
Weight ð%Þ 

Mathematics 1 
6 
9 
Mathematics 2 
5 

Mathematics subtotal 
11 
36.67 
9 
25.00 
French 
3 
1st foreign language 
4 
4 
2nd foreign language 
2 
3 
General culture 
4 
6 
History and geography 
6 
8 
Debate 
6 
Other fields' subtotal 
19 
63.33 
27 
75.00 

Total 
30 
100.00 
36 
100.00 

496 
Ors et al. 

</table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Because of data restrictions, honors are the only performance metric available to us for the baccalaure´at exam.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">We also note that other unobservable differences across genders, such as risk aversion, may play a role in our findings. Unfortunately, we are limited by the data at our disposal in exploring the role, if any, of these additional factors.7  The HEC MSc in Management program was ranked first in Europe in2008,  second in 2009, third in 2010, and fourth in 2011.  8  See http://rankings.ft.com/businessschoolrankings/masters-in-management.448Ors et al.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="9">As we explain further below, this holds true even for those candidates who fail the HEC entrance exam. 10 ECTS is a pan-European grading standard under which a typical academic year of higher education corresponds to 60 ECTS credits. The corresponding grading</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="11">These include some of the best French engineering schools of the current day, e.g., Ecole des Ponts et Chaussées, Ecole des Mines, and Ecole des Arts et Métiers.452   Ors et al.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="25">Moreover, testing centers typically seat students from different high schools in alphabetical order.Performance Gender Gap 459</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="26">The 2007 cohort cannot be added to this analysis since the first-year curriculum was subject to a major reform that came into effect in September 2007: some of the first-year courses were moved to the second year, whereas others were given460   Ors et al.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="29">These tests are also less precise given the lower number of observations involved ð63 and 71, respectivelyÞ.30  Note that the actual baccalaure´at performance gap between the HEC candidates and the population of science track majors in high school is even larger, since the averages that we report here do not take into account the fact that 15% of high school seniors fail the high school graduation exam.464   Ors et al.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="31">Different prep school rankings are published in various French newspapers and magazines. We use the most comprehensive ranking list. Performance Gender Gap 465</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">Performance Gender Gap</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="474">  Ors et al.   </note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="41">We obtain similar results if the logarithm of prep school rank is used to control for quality of the preparation received. These estimates are presented in online app. tables A2 and A3 to conserve space.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="42">We do not consider the 10th or the 90th percentiles because of the lower number of observations for the admissibles.482   Ors et al.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="43">We do not provide a formal test of equality of coefficient estimates across equations as all the models in table 10 are estimated with overlapping data.Performance Gender Gap</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="44">Accounting, economics, finance, marketing, law, theory of organizations, and supply chain courses are worth 5 ECTS credits each; statistics and quantitative Performance Gender Gap 487</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="45">Science majors also have to sit for examinations in physics, chemistry, and life sciences ðbiology and geologyÞ during the baccalaure´at ðsee table 12 belowÞ. Performance Gender Gap 493</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="47">We do not, e.g., have experimental data on objective probability lotteries or field data on gambles for the individuals who are in our data set so as to be able to test whether measures of risk aversion vary across genders.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="56,81.07,185.91,311.98,10.21;56,90.71,197.93,231.85,10.21" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nonparametric tests of stochastic dominance in income distributions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gordon</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1183" to="93" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="56,81.07,209.95,311.92,10.21;56,90.71,221.91,217.06,10.21" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consistent tests for stochastic dominance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Garry</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Donald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="104" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="56,81.07,233.93,312.03,10.21;56,90.71,245.95,302.35,10.21;56,90.71,257.91,36.52,10.21" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of gender, dysphoria, and performance feedback on the accuracy of self-evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sylvia</forename><surname>Beyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sex Roles</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="453" to="564" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="56,81.07,269.93,311.90,10.21;56,90.71,281.95,302.33,10.21;56,90.71,293.91,302.36,10.21;56,90.71,305.93,21.35,10.21" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The temporal stability of gender differences in MIS students</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sylvia</forename><surname>Beyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michelle</forename><surname>Dekeuster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><surname>Rynes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Deheer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://aisel.aisnet.org/amcis2004/151" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">151</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>AMCIS</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="56,81.07,317.95,311.99,10.21;56,90.71,329.91,302.44,10.21;56,90.71,341.93,81.44,10.21" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deterrents to women taking computer science courses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sylvia</forename><surname>Beyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><surname>Rynes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Susan</forename><surname>Haller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Society and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="56,81.07,353.95,312.05,10.21;56,90.71,365.91,183.49,10.21" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gender differences in preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Croson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Uri</forename><surname>Gneezy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Literature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="448" to="74" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="56,81.07,377.93,312.04,10.21;56,90.71,389.95,302.39,10.21;56,90.71,401.91,152.93,10.21" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical inference for stochastic dominance and for the measurement of poverty and inequality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Russell</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean-Yves</forename><surname>Duclos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1435" to="64" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="56,81.07,413.93,312.03,10.21;56,90.71,425.95,302.35,10.21;56,90.71,437.91,291.54,10.21;56,81.07,449.93,312.03,10.21;56,90.71,461.95,302.34,10.21;56,90.71,473.91,302.39,10.21;56,90.71,485.93,63.11,10.21" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tournament incentives in the field: Gender differences in the workplace</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josse</forename><surname>Delfgaauw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Dur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joeri</forename><surname>Sol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Willem</forename><surname>Verbeke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">;</forename><surname>Eckel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Catherine</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Grossman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of experimental economics results</title>
		<editor>Charles Plott and Vernon Smith</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Bonn; New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1061" to="73" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Men, women and risk aversion: Experimental evidence</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="56,81.07,497.95,311.94,10.21;56,90.71,509.91,149.25,10.21" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lessons from the campus: In higher education, a freefor-all does not work</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economist</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006-10-26" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="56,81.07,521.93,312.08,10.21;56,90.71,533.95,208.25,10.21" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Women&apos;s college decisions: How much does marriage matter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suqin</forename><surname>Ge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Labor Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="773" to="818" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="56,81.07,545.91,311.96,10.21;56,90.71,557.93,302.33,10.21;56,90.71,569.95,173.40,10.21" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gender differences in competition: Evidence from a matrilineal and a patriarchal society</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Uri</forename><surname>Gneezy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kenneth</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Leonard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>List</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1637" to="64" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="56,81.07,581.91,312.04,10.21;56,90.71,593.93,302.41,10.21;56,90.71,605.95,127.45,10.21" xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Performance in competitive environments: Gender differences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Uri</forename><surname>Gneezy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Muriel</forename><surname>Niederle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aldo</forename><surname>Rustichini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">118</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1049" to="74" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="56,356.32,68.23,36.75,9.19" xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ors</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="57,80.96,90.49,311.99,10.21;57,90.60,102.46,302.41,10.21;57,90.60,114.47,130.80,10.21" xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Orchestrating impartiality: The impact of &quot;blind&quot; auditions on female musicians</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claudia</forename><surname>Goldin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cecilia</forename><surname>Rouse</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="715" to="756" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="57,80.96,126.49,311.92,10.21;57,90.60,138.46,278.79,10.21" xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Culture, gender, and math</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luigi</forename><surname>Guiso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ferdinando</forename><surname>Monte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paola</forename><surname>Sapienza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luigi</forename><surname>Zingales</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">320</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1164" to="65" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="57,80.96,150.47,312.05,10.21;57,90.60,162.49,302.43,10.21;57,90.60,174.46,167.95,10.21" xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gender gap in admission performance under competitive pressure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stepan</forename><surname>Jurajda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Munich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review Papers and Proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">101</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="514" to="532" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="57,80.96,186.47,311.98,10.21;57,90.60,198.49,302.41,10.21;57,90.60,210.46,105.87,10.21" xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do gender differences in preferences for competition matter for occupational expectations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristin</forename><surname>Kleinjans</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="701" to="711" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="57,80.96,222.48,311.98,10.21;57,90.60,234.49,110.06,10.21" xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Classement des prépas commerciaux voie scientifique</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">La</forename><surname>Lettre De L&amp;apos;etudiant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006-09-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="57,80.96,246.46,312.01,10.21;57,90.60,258.48,302.32,10.21;57,90.60,270.49,141.95,10.21;57,80.96,282.46,312.01,10.21;57,90.60,294.48,302.33,10.21;57,90.60,306.50,302.31,10.21;57,90.60,318.46,104.76,10.21" xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gender differences in market competitiveness in a real workplace: Evidence from performance-based pay tournaments among teachers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victor</forename><surname>Lavy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>nos. 10-11:2083-2105</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Public Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Do gender stereotypes reduce girls&apos; human capital outcomes? Evidence from a natural experiment. Working paper no. 14338, National Bureau of Economic Research</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="57,80.96,330.48,311.93,10.21;57,90.60,342.50,55.58,10.21;57,80.96,354.46,251.28,10.21" xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Les filles brillent en classe, les garçons aux concours</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Le</forename><surname>Monde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-09" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2012. Prépas, l&apos;excellence au prix fort</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="57,80.96,366.48,311.98,10.21;57,90.60,378.50,302.32,10.21;57,90.60,390.46,123.98,10.21" xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do women shy away from competition? Do men compete too much?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Muriel</forename><surname>Niederle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lise</forename><surname>Vesterlund</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quarterly Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">122</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1067" to="1101" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="57,80.96,402.48,311.99,10.21;57,90.60,414.50,273.01,10.21" xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Explaining the gender gap in math test scores: The role of competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">---</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Perspectives</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="173" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="57,80.96,426.46,312.07,10.21;57,90.60,438.48,302.34,10.21;57,90.60,450.50,126.89,10.21" xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Gender differences in performance in competitive environments? Evidence from professional tennis players. Working paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Paserman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Daniele</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<pubPlace>Boston University</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="57,80.96,462.46,311.96,10.21;57,90.60,474.48,302.35,10.21;57,90.60,486.50,302.32,10.21;57,90.60,498.46,55.82,10.21" xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Annual report. French Ministry of National Education and the Ministry of Higher Education and Research</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">RERS ðRepères et Références Statistiques sur les Enseignements, la Formation et la RechercheÞ</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Paris</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="57,80.96,510.48,311.98,10.21;57,90.60,522.50,250.57,10.21" xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Nonparametric statistics for the behavioral sciences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sidney</forename><surname>Siegel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>John Castellan</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<publisher>McGraw-Hill</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="57,80.96,68.23,100.45,9.19;57,379.44,68.23,13.50,9.19" xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Performance Gender Gap 499</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
